<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <id>https://p2pempire.com/en/newsfeed</id>
  <title>P2P Empire</title>
  <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.596226+00:00</updated>
  <link href="https://p2pempire.com/en/newsfeed" rel="alternate"/>
  <generator uri="https://lkiesow.github.io/python-feedgen" version="1.0.0">python-feedgen</generator>
  <entry>
    <id>UnaFinancial CFO: FX Losses, No Group Guarantee Raise Investor Risks - 2025-07-28T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>UnaFinancial CFO: FX Losses, No Group Guarantee Raise Investor Risks</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.635997+00:00</updated>
    <content>UnaFinancial’s CFO reported a spike in the debt-to-equity ratio, though some recovery was seen in early 2025. The group’s exit from Vietnam cut assets, while currency losses in Kazakhstan, Sri Lanka, and the Philippines reduced equity. Lending in the Philippines remains uncertain amid regulatory talks. The use of Singapore loan funds is unclear, and no group guarantee covers lending entities—raising risk for P2P investors in case of default.</content>
    <link href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=bmVeMNVQ9OM"/>
    <published>2025-07-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>EstateGuru Lietuva UAB Banned from Crowdfunding in Lithuania - 2025-07-24T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>EstateGuru Lietuva UAB Banned from Crowdfunding in Lithuania</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.635909+00:00</updated>
    <content>The Bank of Lithuania confirmed that EstateGuru Lietuva, UAB is not authorized to offer crowdfunding services. The company was delisted in July 2023 and did not apply for an EU license under Regulation (EU) 2020/1503. Its activities are unsupervised, and investors lack recourse through Lithuanian authorities. Only EstateGuru OÜ, licensed in Estonia, may legally operate—independently from EstateGuru Lietuva.</content>
    <link href="https://www.lb.lt/lt/naujienos/estateguru-lietuva-uab-neturi-teises-teikti-sutelktinio-finansavimo-paslaugu-lietuvoje"/>
    <published>2025-07-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Aventus Group Boosts Profits by 33% in H1 2025 - 2025-07-17T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Aventus Group Boosts Profits by 33% in H1 2025</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.635821+00:00</updated>
    <content>Aventus Group reported EUR 46.73M in net profits for H1 2025, up 33.3% year-over-year. Loan issuance rose nearly 20% to EUR 631.4M, while the group's total loan portfolio reached EUR 303.14M. Equity stood at EUR 188.09M. Interest income for the period was EUR 205.6M, reflecting strong lending activity and portfolio growth.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/peerberry"/>
    <published>2025-07-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Crowdpear Passes €28M in Funded Loans - 2025-07-17T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Crowdpear Passes €28M in Funded Loans</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.635731+00:00</updated>
    <content>In June, investors funded 17 real estate-backed loans on Crowdpear, totaling €1.42M. Nine loans were repaid, returning €1.09M (excluding interest). Interest payouts last month reached €188,690, bringing total interest paid since launch to over €1.62M. The platform’s cumulative funded loan volume now exceeds €28.07M, reflecting steady growth in property-backed lending.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/crowdpear"/>
    <published>2025-07-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Afranga Adds Swiss Funds as New Loan Originator - 2025-07-15T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Afranga Adds Swiss Funds as New Loan Originator</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.635643+00:00</updated>
    <content>Afranga introduces Swiss Funds, a licensed Czech lender backed by Orka Ventures. Investors can access business loans with returns up to 11% p.a. Swiss Funds uses a fully automated system, enabling sub-60-second approvals and greater repayment predictability. With over €3.3M in loans issued and 16,000+ users, this addition enhances portfolio diversification with a tech-driven, regulated partner.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/afranga"/>
    <published>2025-07-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Esketit Appoints Ieva Grigaļūne as CEO, Replacing Vitalijs Zalovs - 2025-07-14T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Esketit Appoints Ieva Grigaļūne as CEO, Replacing Vitalijs Zalovs</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.635553+00:00</updated>
    <content>Esketit has named Ieva Grigaļūne as its new CEO, effective July 30. With nine years of investment sector experience, she will lead operational structure and licensing strategy. Outgoing CEO Vitalijs Zalovs will transition to an advisory role, continuing to support the company.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/esketit"/>
    <published>2025-07-14T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Honest Karlin Reopens €300K Investment with 9% Annual Interest - 2025-07-09T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Honest Karlin Reopens €300K Investment with 9% Annual Interest</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.635464+00:00</updated>
    <content>Honest Karlin, a top-performing rental project on Fintown, is reopening €300,000 for reinvestment. Terms include 9% annual interest, a 12-month minimum term, and monthly interest payments. The opportunity will be available as a single lot starting July 10, offering investors a chance to join a trusted project with proven confidence from the community.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/fintown"/>
    <published>2025-07-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Platform Update: June Activity and New Communication on Late Loans - 2025-07-09T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Platform Update: June Activity and New Communication on Late Loans</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.635356+00:00</updated>
    <content>June saw a slower month with 107 loan applications totaling €14M, up from May’s 96 applications (€11.5M). The platform published 18 projects (€1.67M) and fully repaid 10 loans (€0.7M). Updates on loans late over 5 days will now be bi-weekly on Mondays. New investment opportunities include Capitalia bonds (6-7% yield) and Loanstream’s consumer loan fund (12% annual return).</content>
    <link href="/en/review/capitalia"/>
    <published>2025-07-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Platform Hits €5.7M Funded in June, Total €174.5M with 13.54% Average Return - 2025-07-08T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Platform Hits €5.7M Funded in June, Total €174.5M with 13.54% Average Return</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.635267+00:00</updated>
    <content>In June 2025, the platform funded €5.7 million in loans, reaching a total all-time funded amount of €174.5 million. The average return since inception remains strong at 13.54%. Loans originated in June carried an average interest rate of 12.13%.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/income"/>
    <published>2025-07-08T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Letsinvest Reaches €80M Funded Loans Since Inception With No Delays - 2025-07-08T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Letsinvest Reaches €80M Funded Loans Since Inception With No Delays</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.635177+00:00</updated>
    <content>European real estate crowdfunding platform Letsinvest has funded €80 million in loans since inception, with a current loan portfolio of €39 million in the first half of 2025. New investments of €19 million mark a 65% increase from H1 2024. The platform maintains a 10.15% average annual return and zero defaults, focusing on international projects across Spain, Portugal, Norway, Latvia, and Lithuania.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/letsinvest"/>
    <published>2025-07-08T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Loan Top-Ups Temporarily Unavailable on Lonvest - 2025-07-01T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Loan Top-Ups Temporarily Unavailable on Lonvest</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.635088+00:00</updated>
    <content>Lonvest has completed its loan originator’s financial plan, causing a temporary suspension of top-up options on the website. Customers will be unable to add new funds to the platform until further notice. Withdrawals are not affected.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/lonvest"/>
    <published>2025-07-01T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Money For Specialized Finance Sees 30% Revenue Growth in 2024 - 2025-06-26T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Money For Specialized Finance Sees 30% Revenue Growth in 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.634999+00:00</updated>
    <content>Money For Specialized Finance reported audited revenue of €34.6 million in 2024, up 30% from €26.7 million in 2023. Net profit climbed to €6.3 million from €3.9 million. The figures, verified by independent auditors, reflect strong profitability and consistent business expansion.</content>
    <link href="https://esketit.cdn.prismic.io/esketit/aFu3ynfc4bHWitBw_MoneyForSpecializedFinanceSignedFinancialStatements2024Standalone.pdf"/>
    <published>2025-06-26T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Fintown Spring Update: Key Milestones Achieved - 2025-06-26T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Fintown Spring Update: Key Milestones Achieved</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.634909+00:00</updated>
    <content>Fintown reached €1.28M in interest payouts and launched a more transparent quarterly report with Vihorev Group. The Park Vista project in Prague completed its demolition phase, while €7.5M in principal has been returned to investors. Total investments now exceed €21.5M, with an active portfolio of €14M. Login access is also faster thanks to a recent 2FA fix.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/fintown"/>
    <published>2025-06-26T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>LANDE Hits Record €1.42M in Loans Issued in May 2025 - 2025-06-24T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>LANDE Hits Record €1.42M in Loans Issued in May 2025</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.634814+00:00</updated>
    <content>LANDE reported an all-time high of €1.42 million in loans issued across 43 projects in May 2025. Investor earnings hit €90,085 for the month, pushing total interest paid past €3 million. Most loans were backed by land or machinery. Debt recovery saw strong progress, especially in Latvia and Romania. LANDE also launched its first non-agricultural project, signaling cautious diversification.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/lande"/>
    <published>2025-06-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>P2P Lending Platforms Performance Update - June 2025 - 2025-06-21T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>P2P Lending Platforms Performance Update - June 2025</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.634723+00:00</updated>
    <content>Curious how your favorite P2P platforms performed this month? Our latest video breaks down recovery progress, new products like EG Grow, licensing issues at Robocash, and big lender exits on Esketit. Get a snapshot of transparency trends, standout returns, and what investors should watch next. Don’t miss this month’s must-see review — now live on our comparison page!</content>
    <link href="https://p2pempire.com/en/comparison"/>
    <published>2025-06-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Midsummer Holidays May Delay P2P Platform Support - 2025-06-20T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Midsummer Holidays May Delay P2P Platform Support</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.634623+00:00</updated>
    <content>Latvia celebrates Midsummer’s Eve and Jāņi on June 23–24, a major national holiday. Expect limited customer support and potential delays in processing on some Baltic-based P2P lending platforms during this period. Plan accordingly to avoid disruptions.</content>
    <link href="https://p2pempire.com/en/newsfeed"/>
    <published>2025-06-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>LANDE Expands Beyond Agriculture with New Non-Agri Loans - 2025-06-20T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>LANDE Expands Beyond Agriculture with New Non-Agri Loans</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.634534+00:00</updated>
    <content>LANDE is now offering non-agricultural loans, starting with a €22,000 freight transport project in Romania. The loan features an 11% interest rate, 44% LTV, and strong real estate collateral. While agriculture remains the core focus, LANDE will occasionally list carefully vetted non-agri projects that meet its strict risk and quality standards, offering investors new diversification opportunities without compromising on security.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/lande"/>
    <published>2025-06-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Latvia’s Midsummer Holidays May Delay P2P Platform Support - 2025-06-20T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Latvia’s Midsummer Holidays May Delay P2P Platform Support</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.634444+00:00</updated>
    <content>Latvia celebrates Midsummer’s Eve and Jāņi on June 23–24, a major national holiday. Expect limited customer support and potential delays in processing on some Latvia-based P2P lending platforms during this period. Plan accordingly to avoid disruptions.</content>
    <link href="https://p2pempire.com/en/newsfeed"/>
    <published>2025-06-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Ricany Apartments Stage 2 Completed, Now Closed to New Investors - 2025-06-18T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Ricany Apartments Stage 2 Completed, Now Closed to New Investors</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.634336+00:00</updated>
    <content>Vihorev Group has completed Stage 2 of the Ricany Apartments. This project is now closed to new investments, but current investors will continue receiving monthly interest payments. Fintown now offers two active Prague opportunities—Kolovraty and Park Vista—each providing 13% p.a. over a 24-month term.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/fintown"/>
    <published>2025-06-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>ConnectPay Now Live on InSoil Finance Platform - 2025-06-17T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>ConnectPay Now Live on InSoil Finance Platform</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.634219+00:00</updated>
    <content>InSoil Finance has integrated ConnectPay as its new payment partner. All transactions—including deposits, withdrawals, and investments—now run directly via ConnectPay's e-wallet, ensuring faster and more secure operations. Key features include instant and recurring payments, access to all investment options within the platform, and enhanced security for investments over €500.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/insoil-finance"/>
    <published>2025-06-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>P2P Portfolio Update | May 2025 - 2025-06-14T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>P2P Portfolio Update | May 2025</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.634130+00:00</updated>
    <content>Learn more about the recent changes in our P2P lending portfolio.</content>
    <link href="https://p2pempire.com/en/portfolio"/>
    <published>2025-06-14T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>InSoil Secures €100M from Key Carbon to Fund Regenerative Farming Across Europe - 2025-06-10T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>InSoil Secures €100M from Key Carbon to Fund Regenerative Farming Across Europe</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.634040+00:00</updated>
    <content>InSoil, formerly HeavyFinance, has partnered with Key Carbon in a €100 million deal to fund interest-free Green Loans for European farmers adopting regenerative agriculture. A €3.7M royalty-based investment will help InSoil scale to 1M hectares by 2026, targeting over 35M tonnes of CO₂ removal. The deal marks InSoil’s largest raise and is among Europe's biggest climate-resilient farming finance initiatives to date.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/insoil-finance"/>
    <published>2025-06-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Aventus Group Scales Back PeerBerry Loan Supply Amid Strong Profits, Eyes Expansion - 2025-06-13T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Aventus Group Scales Back PeerBerry Loan Supply Amid Strong Profits, Eyes Expansion</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.633953+00:00</updated>
    <content>Aventus Group now funds only 15% of its €305M loan book via PeerBerry, down from 45% share on the platform. CEO Andrejus Trofimovas attributes reduced borrowing to €87M+ in 2024 profits and mature market positions. While short-term loan supply drops, Aventus is expanding into five new markets and growing business lending in Poland. Real estate loans in Spain and investments via Crowdpear also present new investor options.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/peerberry"/>
    <published>2025-06-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Indemo Repays €191K to Investors from Girona Property Debt - 2025-06-11T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Indemo Repays €191K to Investors from Girona Property Debt</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.633865+00:00</updated>
    <content>Indemo has completed its third repayment of 2025, returning €191,061 to 1,677 investors from the RO79: House in Les Preses, Girona debt. The average annual ROI was 17.78%, with some investors earning up to 34%. The repayment, facilitated via institutional secondary market sale, covered 9.3% of active Notes and underscores the performance of Indemo’s real estate-backed Discounted Debt model.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/indemo"/>
    <published>2025-06-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Triple Dragon Repays All Delayed Loans with Penalties on Debitum - 2025-05-29T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Triple Dragon Repays All Delayed Loans with Penalties on Debitum</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.633777+00:00</updated>
    <content>Debitum reports that all delayed loans from loan originator Triple Dragon have been fully repaid. Investors received not only the principal but also additional penalty interest, compensating for the delay.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/debitum-network"/>
    <published>2025-05-29T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>TWINO Phases Out Rentals Product Amid Strategic Refocus - 2025-05-31T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>TWINO Phases Out Rentals Product Amid Strategic Refocus</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.633689+00:00</updated>
    <content>TWINO is discontinuing its Rentals product after underwhelming performance. The platform will gradually exit existing rental projects, returning investors’ capital and profits from property sales. This move aims to optimize investor returns by reallocating resources toward higher-potential loan and investment offerings. Full project and financial performance details are available on the platform for logged-in users.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/twino"/>
    <published>2025-05-31T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>P2P Lending Platforms Performance Update - May 2025 - 2025-05-18T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>P2P Lending Platforms Performance Update - May 2025</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.633600+00:00</updated>
    <content>In this month’s update, we cover the latest data on recoveries, defaults, and loan volumes across major players like Mintos, PeerBerry, EstateGuru, and more. Watch the full video to see where your money might be working—or at risk.</content>
    <link href="https://p2pempire.com/en/comparison"/>
    <published>2025-05-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Last Chance To Vote For The Worst Platform Of 2025 - 2025-05-17T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Last Chance To Vote For The Worst Platform Of 2025</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.633511+00:00</updated>
    <content>Use the source link to express your opinion about the worst P2P lending platform of 2025. The result will be published on our YouTube channel. Vote now!</content>
    <link href="https://forms.gle/TESBKzusEqh9YTuPA"/>
    <published>2025-05-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>YouHodler Starts Re-Verification of Older Accounts - 2025-05-14T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>YouHodler Starts Re-Verification of Older Accounts</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.633419+00:00</updated>
    <content>YouHodler is re-verifying older user accounts as part of stricter KYC enforcement. Affected users must complete enhanced verification, including a video call, ID, proof of funds, and residency. Without full compliance, fund withdrawals will be blocked, though deposits and trading remain available.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/youhodler"/>
    <published>2025-05-14T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Cashback Linked to Portfolio Growth from May 12–31 - 2025-05-12T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Cashback Linked to Portfolio Growth from May 12–31</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.633313+00:00</updated>
    <content>Nectaro will offer up to 5% Cashback based on portfolio growth during May 12–31. Portfolio balances on May 11 will be used to calculate growth. Minimum €1,000 growth is required to qualify. Cashback is capped at €2,000 and will be credited by June 15. Only users registered by May 11 are eligible.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/nectaro"/>
    <published>2025-05-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Vote For The Worst P2P Lending Platform Of 2025 - 2025-04-27T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Vote For The Worst P2P Lending Platform Of 2025</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.633226+00:00</updated>
    <content>Vote for the P2P platform you believe is underperforming or most likely to shut down this year. Submit your vote by 16 May 2025 via the "Source" link. Results will be publicly presented on our YouTube channel — stay tuned to see the community’s verdict.</content>
    <link href="https://forms.gle/YdB9ZoA1zf8wK7zt7"/>
    <published>2025-04-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Mintos Launches Secondary Market for Bonds, Boosting Trading Flexibility - 2025-04-25T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Mintos Launches Secondary Market for Bonds, Boosting Trading Flexibility</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.633139+00:00</updated>
    <content>Mintos has rolled out a Secondary Market for its bond products, allowing investors to trade bonds by ISIN, issuer, yield, and more. This upgrade enhances liquidity and access to fixed-income options</content>
    <link href="/en/review/mintos"/>
    <published>2025-04-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>HeavyFinance Rebrands as InSoil - 2025-04-24T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>HeavyFinance Rebrands as InSoil</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.633051+00:00</updated>
    <content>HeavyFinance has rebranded to InSoil, reflecting its deeper focus on regenerative agriculture and soil health. The company also introduced InSoil Finance, a new identity tailored to its 14,000+ investors, aiming to enhance the retail investment experience while continuing to support sustainable farming practices.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/insoil-finance"/>
    <published>2025-04-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Mintos Adjusts Smart Cash Rate to 2.25% After ECB Cut - 2025-04-24T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Mintos Adjusts Smart Cash Rate to 2.25% After ECB Cut</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.632963+00:00</updated>
    <content>Mintos has lowered the interest rate for its Smart Cash product to 2.25%, effective immediately. The change follows the recent rate reduction by the European Central Bank.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/mintos"/>
    <published>2025-04-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Indemo Launches Up to 4% Cashback Campaign Until May 23 - 2025-04-23T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Indemo Launches Up to 4% Cashback Campaign Until May 23</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.632875+00:00</updated>
    <content>From April 22 to May 23, Indemo is offering tiered cashback rewards of up to 4% on total investments starting from €500. Cashback levels unlock instantly as investors reach €1,500 (3%) and €5,000 (4%), whether in a single deposit or multiple. Both new and existing funds qualify. Cashback is non-withdrawable and subject to Indemo’s terms and conditions.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/indemo"/>
    <published>2025-04-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>P2P Portfolio Update | March 2025 - 2025-04-20T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>P2P Portfolio Update | March 2025</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.632787+00:00</updated>
    <content>Learn more about the recent changes in our P2P lending portfolio.</content>
    <link href="https://p2pempire.com/en/portfolio"/>
    <published>2025-04-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Capitalia: No systemic issues behind recent rise in late loans - 2025-04-09T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Capitalia: No systemic issues behind recent rise in late loans</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.632698+00:00</updated>
    <content>Capitalia reports a recent increase in loans over 90 days late, linked to two clients with seven loans now in recovery. Most are secured by real estate with reasonable LTVs, though resolution may take time. The firm stresses these are isolated cases, not a systemic trend, due to its decision not to extend large exposures where refinancing efforts failed.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/capitalia"/>
    <published>2025-04-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Income reports €6.3M in new funding for March 2025 - 2025-04-08T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Income reports €6.3M in new funding for March 2025</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.632608+00:00</updated>
    <content>Income Marketplace funded €6.3M in March 2025, bringing total all-time funding to €156.5M. The average interest rate for March-originated loans was 11.9%, while the platform’s all-time average return stands at 13.68%. Income now has 9,374 investors, with 158 new joiners in March. The average investor portfolio is €4,081, and total investor earnings have reached €4.35M.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/income"/>
    <published>2025-04-08T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Baltic borrower activity rises sharply in March - 2025-04-08T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Baltic borrower activity rises sharply in March</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.632508+00:00</updated>
    <content>Baltic companies submitted 118 loan applications worth €12.9M in March, up from 75 in February. Income published 29 projects on its platform totaling €3.13M, nearly doubling February’s €1.65M. Project sizes ranged between €10K and €426K. While the project pipeline remains strong, the ongoing global trade war may affect business sentiment in the Baltic region.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/capitalia"/>
    <published>2025-04-08T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>PeerBerry reaches record €117.45M portfolio in March - 2025-04-02T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>PeerBerry reaches record €117.45M portfolio in March</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.632417+00:00</updated>
    <content>In March 2025, PeerBerry investors funded €33.62M in loans—up nearly 10% from February—and earned €944,538 in interest. Total interest paid since launch reached €41.97M. The platform’s portfolio hit an all-time high of €117.45M. PeerBerry welcomed 1,522 new investors, bringing its verified user base to over 99,500. Since inception, nearly €2.99B in loans have been funded.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/peerberry"/>
    <published>2025-04-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>PeerBerry warns investors of email scam - 2025-03-27T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>PeerBerry warns investors of email scam</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.632309+00:00</updated>
    <content>PeerBerry has alerted users about scam emails falsely sent from support@peerberry.com. These emails may request personal data or urge users to click suspicious links or download files. Investors are urged not to engage and to contact Client Support if uncertain about any communication. PeerBerry emphasizes vigilance to protect personal and financial information.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/peerberry"/>
    <published>2025-03-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>HeavyFinance sees strong investment growth in February - 2025-03-20T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>HeavyFinance sees strong investment growth in February</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.632221+00:00</updated>
    <content>HeavyFinance secured €2.66M in investments last month, fully financing 63 farmer loans worth €2.65M. Since inception, total loan issuance has reached €73.5M. Investors have received €36.85M in repaid principal, €7.45M in interest, and €1.55M in delayed interest. In February, repayments totaled €2.06M, with €0.82M scheduled for March 2025. Meanwhile, funds in recovery have risen to €9.99M.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/heavy-finance"/>
    <published>2025-03-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Fintown: 2% bonus for new investors via P2P Empire - 2025-03-20T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Fintown: 2% bonus for new investors via P2P Empire</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.632132+00:00</updated>
    <content>New investors who sign up through P2P Empire’s link can enjoy an exclusive 2% investment bonus from Fintown. There’s no time limit, no cap, and the bonus is automatically credited after your first investment.</content>
    <link href="https://p2pempire.com/en/cashback-bonus/fintown-referral-code"/>
    <published>2025-03-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Indemo launches a 2% cashback campaign - 2025-03-18T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Indemo launches a 2% cashback campaign</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.632043+00:00</updated>
    <content>Earn up to 2% cashback on investments from March 17 to April 16. Investors who contribute €800 or more receive 2% cashback, while those investing between €200 and €799.99 get 1.5%. Cashback is applied automatically, with both new deposits and uninvested funds qualifying.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/indemo"/>
    <published>2025-03-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Recovery progress &amp; outlook - 2025-03-07T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Recovery progress &amp; outlook</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.631951+00:00</updated>
    <content>As of March 7, 2025, CROWDESTOR has categorized all outstanding projects based on their recovery status: Concluded, Pre-litigation, Court/Insolvency/Bailiff, and Solution in Progress. Projects are actively moving through these phases, with debt collection expected to conclude by early 2026. No new investments, investor registrations, or Secondary Market activity will resume. Investors can track project updates on the platform.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/crowdestor"/>
    <published>2025-03-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Recovery Progress &amp; Outlook - 2025-03-07T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Recovery Progress &amp; Outlook</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.631855+00:00</updated>
    <content>As of March 7, 2025, CROWDESTOR has categorized all outstanding projects based on their recovery status: Concluded, Pre-litigation, Court/Insolvency/Bailiff, and Solution in Progress. Projects are actively moving through these phases, with debt collection expected to conclude by early 2026. No new investments, investor registrations, or Secondary Market activity will resume. Investors can track project updates on the platform.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/crowdestor"/>
    <published>2025-03-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>P2P Portfolio Update | February 2025 - 2025-03-09T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>P2P Portfolio Update | February 2025</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.631765+00:00</updated>
    <content>Learn more about the recent changes in our P2P lending portfolio.</content>
    <link href="https://p2pempire.com/en/portfolio"/>
    <published>2025-03-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Capitalia sees strong growth in February - 2025-03-07T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Capitalia sees strong growth in February</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.631677+00:00</updated>
    <content>Baltic business financing surged in February, with Capitalia processing 75 borrower applications worth EUR 13.1 million—up from 61 applications totaling EUR 6.6 million in January. The average application size grew to EUR 174,000. On Capitalia’s platform, 18 projects were published, amounting to EUR 1.65 million, slightly exceeding January’s EUR 1.63 million. Project sizes ranged from EUR 10,000 to EUR 329,000.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/capitalia"/>
    <published>2025-03-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Crowdpear reports record €3.43M in real estate loan investments - 2025-03-06T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Crowdpear reports record €3.43M in real estate loan investments</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.631588+00:00</updated>
    <content>In February, Crowdpear investors funded 14 real estate-backed loans worth over €3.43M—the highest monthly investment on the platform. Total loan funding exceeded €22M. Investors earned €64,743 in interest, pushing total payouts past €1.18M. Additionally, 11 loans totaling €869,100 were repaid. Since inception, investors have funded 250 loans worth €22.15M, with 151 loans (€21.01M) already repaid.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/crowdpear"/>
    <published>2025-03-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Key updates for investors - 2025-03-06T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Key updates for investors</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.631499+00:00</updated>
    <content>Bondster is enhancing security with mandatory two-factor authentication (2FA)—users will be prompted to enable or disable it at login. From March 10, 2025, secondary market limits will change, allowing sales with up to a 15% discount or 5% premium for fairer trading. Additionally, Bondster welcomes SWISS FUNDS, offering 10.1% annual returns on short-term loans.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/bondster"/>
    <published>2025-03-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Green loans secure backing from ILTE - 2025-03-06T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Green loans secure backing from ILTE</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.631407+00:00</updated>
    <content>Lithuania’s national development bank, ILTE, has joined Green Loans as an investor, committing up to 40% of each loan (max €30,000). With support from the Avietė fund, HeavyFinance plans to lend over €8 million by year-end.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/heavy-finance"/>
    <published>2025-03-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Successful repayment: A82 apartment in Palma - 2025-03-06T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Successful repayment: A82 apartment in Palma</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.631301+00:00</updated>
    <content>Indemo has completed its 7th consecutive repayment, distributing €190,866 (principal + interest) to 472 investors, covering 25% of all active Notes. Investors saw annual returns between 16.63% and 36%, with an average weighted ROI of 21.92%.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/indemo"/>
    <published>2025-03-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Income Marketplace reports €5.23M funded loans in February - 2025-03-05T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Income Marketplace reports €5.23M funded loans in February</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.631212+00:00</updated>
    <content>**Income Marketplace Reports €5.23M Funded in February**  

Income Marketplace saw €5,232,935 in funding in February 2025, bringing its all-time total to €150.2M. The platform’s average return since inception stands at 13.74%, while loans issued in February had an average interest rate of 12.26%. In February, 154 new investors joined, raising the total investor count to 9,216.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/income"/>
    <published>2025-03-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Indemo launched a 1.3% instant cashback - 2025-03-04T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Indemo launched a 1.3% instant cashback</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.631122+00:00</updated>
    <content>From March 3rd (11:00 CET) to March 16th (23:59 CET), every euro you invest earns an automatic 1.3% cashback—no tiers, no promo codes, no hassle.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/indemo"/>
    <published>2025-03-04T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Indemo's second debt repayment of 2025 - Up to 36% ROI - 2025-02-18T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Indemo's second debt repayment of 2025 - Up to 36% ROI</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.631033+00:00</updated>
    <content>Indemo has announced its second Discounted Debt repayment of 2025, distributing €190,866 in principal and interest. This marks the platform’s 7th consecutive repayment, benefiting 472 investors and covering 25% of active Notes. Investors saw returns ranging from 16.63% to 36% per annum, with an average weighted ROI of 21.92%.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/indemo"/>
    <published>2025-02-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Indemo launches a limited 1.4% instant cashback bonus - 2025-02-11T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Indemo launches a limited 1.4% instant cashback bonus</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.630944+00:00</updated>
    <content>The platform announced an instant cashback bonus of 1.4% on all investments until the 24. February 2025.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/indemo"/>
    <published>2025-02-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Robocash lowers interest rates from February 10 - 2025-02-06T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Robocash lowers interest rates from February 10</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.630856+00:00</updated>
    <content>Starting February 10, interest rates for some loan terms will range between 8% and 10.5%, with a maximum 11.3% for Loyalty program participants. This adjustment addresses growing demand exceeding supply. Existing loans remain unchanged.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/robocash"/>
    <published>2025-02-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Nectaro launches exclusive cashback campaign - 2025-02-02T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Nectaro launches exclusive cashback campaign</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.630769+00:00</updated>
    <content>Nectaro introduces a new Cashback campaign, rewarding investors for portfolio growth in February 2025. By increasing investments from February 1 to February 28, participants can earn up to 4% Cashback. Investors with portfolios over €20,000 unlock higher bonus rates. Cashback tiers range from 1.5% to 4%, depending on portfolio growth.</content>
    <link href="https://c.trackmytarget.com/?a=i5pjek&amp;i=6ckbe7&amp;r=https%3A%2F%2Fnectaro.eu%2Fblog%2Fdont-read-this-if-you-dont-want-extra-cashback"/>
    <published>2025-02-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Money for Finance reports strong 2024 growth and expansion - 2025-01-30T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Money for Finance reports strong 2024 growth and expansion</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.630680+00:00</updated>
    <content>Money for Finance achieved record business growth in 2024, expanding to 54 branches across Jordan. Their new loyalty program boosted client retention, while advanced analytics enhanced operational efficiency. Debt recovery processes improved significantly, and they received top industry awards. The company is progressing toward Central Bank of Jordan licensing. Effective Feb. 3, 2025, EUR loans will offer a 10% APY and USD loans 11% APY.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/esketit"/>
    <published>2025-01-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Fintown opens investment for businesses - 2025-01-30T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Fintown opens investment for businesses</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.630592+00:00</updated>
    <content>Fintown now allows investments through legal entities, enabling entrepreneurs to invest via their companies. The streamlined registration and verification process takes just 24 hours. Investors can easily switch between personal and business accounts, offering greater flexibility and control over their portfolios.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/fintown"/>
    <published>2025-01-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Mintos’ AirBaltic bond offer sells out in 24 hours - 2025-01-30T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Mintos’ AirBaltic bond offer sells out in 24 hours</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.630503+00:00</updated>
    <content>Mintos’ investment offer in AirBaltic bonds, featuring an 11.3% yield-to-maturity, quarterly payouts, and a five-year term, was fully subscribed within 24 hours. The strong demand highlights investor confidence in the airline and the appeal of high-yield fixed-income opportunities.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/mintos"/>
    <published>2025-01-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>CashX joins PeerBerry with 9% returns - 2025-01-27T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>CashX joins PeerBerry with 9% returns</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.630400+00:00</updated>
    <content>Starting January 27, 2025, Nigerian lender CashX NG is offering 30-day business loans on PeerBerry. Backed by buyback and group guarantees, these loans yield a 9% annual return. CashX, known for its quick mobile loan services, began operations in March 2024. Loans will be available periodically based on demand and can be added to Auto Invest for eligible strategies.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/peerberry"/>
    <published>2025-01-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Monthly fee for loan portfolios begins February 7 - 2025-01-28T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Monthly fee for loan portfolios begins February 7</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.630295+00:00</updated>
    <content>Starting February 7, 2025, a monthly fee of 0.39% p.a. will be charged on outstanding amounts in Core Loans, High-Yield, and Conservative portfolios. This fee applies across these investment options to support streamlined portfolio management.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/mintos"/>
    <published>2025-01-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Indemo completes first discounted debt repayment of 2025 - 2025-01-28T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Indemo completes first discounted debt repayment of 2025</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.630206+00:00</updated>
    <content>Indemo has repaid €271,485 (principal and interest) to investors in Debt A83—Apartment in Virgen del Cortijo, Madrid, impacting 471 investors and 39% of active Notes. Investor returns ranged from 15.1% to 40.2% p.a., with an average of 21.52%. This milestone marks the platform’s first discounted debt repayment of 2025, showcasing strong performance for both Indemo and its investor community.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/indemo"/>
    <published>2025-01-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>TWINO's lender in Vietnam is insolvent, the recovery of €1.3 million is unlikely - 2025-01-28T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>TWINO's lender in Vietnam is insolvent, the recovery of €1.3 million is unlikely</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.630117+00:00</updated>
    <content>TWINO has confirmed that VAMO Vietnam (Hoang Kim Nhat Company Ltd.) is insolvent, with €1.3 million in outstanding liabilities deemed unlikely to be recovered. Settlement negotiations have failed, and the company has stated its inability to repay investors. TWINO is now pursuing legal measures, although the chances of successful recovery remain low.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/twino"/>
    <published>2025-01-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Kirsan Group Scandal: €9 Million Debt and ReInvest24 Missteps - 2025-01-28T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Kirsan Group Scandal: €9 Million Debt and ReInvest24 Missteps</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.630029+00:00</updated>
    <content>The Kirsan group faces allegations of embezzlement, insolvency fraud, and €9 million in unpaid debts. Estonian platform ReInvest24 is criticized for failing to perform proper due diligence and securing legal protection for funds, contributing to the losses. Additionally, ReInvest24 has reportedly stopped processing investor withdrawals, raising concerns about its operational stability. With key insolvency administrators detained in Bălți, the case exposes systemic corruption and risks European investor trust.</content>
    <link href="https://www.jurnal.md/ro/news/b573ec5c31bd5a78/dosarele-kirsan-administratoarele-de-insolventa-retinute-la-balti-implicate-intr-un-jaf-de-peste-9-milioane-de-euro.html"/>
    <published>2025-01-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>YouHodler introduces $YHDL tokens - 2025-01-28T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>YouHodler introduces $YHDL tokens</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.629940+00:00</updated>
    <content>YouHodler has launched $YHDL tokens as a reward for achieving high Loyalty Levels. Users can now earn up to 40% annual yield on $YHDL via the Yield account. Once listed publicly, $YHDL holders can access high payouts, trading opportunities, and exclusive features tailored for loyal users.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/youhodler"/>
    <published>2025-01-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Authorities detain administrators in Kirsan debt cases; Reinvest24 silent on withdrawals - 2025-01-18T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Authorities detain administrators in Kirsan debt cases; Reinvest24 silent on withdrawals</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.629851+00:00</updated>
    <content>Moldovan authorities detained three administrators tied to Kirsan companies’ alleged fraudulent bankruptcies and asset seizures. This follows investigations by the National Anticorruption Agency. While Reinvest24 urges investors to fund legal costs for these cases, it remains silent on processing withdrawal requests.</content>
    <link href="https://telegraph.md/update-selevestru-onichevici-si-girleanu-retinute-de-cna-si-procurori-fiind-banuite-de-falimentarea-fictiva-a-unor-companii-si-preluarea-acestora-prin-actiuni-de-tip-raider/"/>
    <published>2025-01-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>InRento launches Stage II of 46 lofts, Kaunas investment - 2025-01-18T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>InRento launches Stage II of 46 lofts, Kaunas investment</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.629761+00:00</updated>
    <content>InRento presents a buy-to-let opportunity in Kaunas: 46 Lofts, Kaunas II. Located near Kaunas Žalgiris Arena, this 1,449 m² project features 46 modern loft-style apartments, blending sales and rental options. Investors can expect annual returns of 11.5%–12% (including 10%–10.5% interest and 1.5% capital gains). With rental income projected at €9,000–€24,000 monthly and a 70% LTV cap, the property offers steady cash flow and market potential.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/inrento"/>
    <published>2025-01-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Fintown raises €498K for The Seed: Lot 1 in just 9 days - 2025-01-18T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Fintown raises €498K for The Seed: Lot 1 in just 9 days</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.629673+00:00</updated>
    <content>Fintown celebrates raising €498,000 for The Seed: Lot 1 in just nine days. This 24-month investment offers a 15% annual yield, with a total stage target of €1.5M across three lots. Lot 2/3 is now live, presenting an exclusive opportunity for investors to join.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/fintown"/>
    <published>2025-01-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Lendermarket gains EU crowdfunding authorisation - 2025-01-07T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Lendermarket gains EU crowdfunding authorisation</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.629585+00:00</updated>
    <content>Lendermarket has secured authorisation from the Central Bank of Ireland to operate as a Crowdfunding Service Provider under EU Regulation 2020/1503.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/lendermarket"/>
    <published>2025-01-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Interviewing Fintown CEO Maxim Vihorev: Your questions wanted - 2025-01-07T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Interviewing Fintown CEO Maxim Vihorev: Your questions wanted</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.629497+00:00</updated>
    <content>This week, we’ll speak with Maxim Vihorev, CEO of Fintown, about the company’s 2025 plans. What innovations, strategies, or goals would you like to know about? Share your specific questions in our community thread on our YouTube channel.</content>
    <link href="https://www.youtube.com/post/Ugkx3sREZGFydvMbtxQkFqXDTX3iMtFCRw_8"/>
    <published>2025-01-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Inrento's Grand Sale investment in Vilnius - 2025-01-07T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Inrento's Grand Sale investment in Vilnius</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.629404+00:00</updated>
    <content>Earn annual returns of 11.5%–12% with fixed interest of 10%–10.5% plus 1.5% capital gains. This Vilnius Old Town project transforms a historic property into a 31-room boutique hotel, projecting €270,000 rental income in 2025. Backed by a 70% LTV ratio and expert management, interest payments begin in February.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/inrento"/>
    <published>2025-01-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Fintown unveils construction schedule for Honest Michle development - 2024-12-19T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Fintown unveils construction schedule for Honest Michle development</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.629298+00:00</updated>
    <content>Fintown has officially released the construction timeline for Honest Michle, an exciting property development funded by Fintown investors. The construction is projected to conclude by June 2026, with the grand opening anticipated in the latter half of 2026. This milestone underscores Fintown's commitment to transparency and progress in delivering value-driven investment opportunities.</content>
    <link href="https://s3.eu-central-1.amazonaws.com/fintown.eu/reports-investors/michle/honest-michle---construction-work-schedule_c.pdf"/>
    <published>2024-12-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>December 2024 Performance Update Is Now Available! - 2024-12-15T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>December 2024 Performance Update Is Now Available!</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.629208+00:00</updated>
    <content>We've released a new video showcasing the top-performing P2P lending platforms for December 2024. This video includes the latest news and insights that could affect your investments on these platforms.</content>
    <link href="https://p2pempire.com/en/p2p-lending-platform-winners-and-losers"/>
    <published>2024-12-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Indemo expands loan offerings and ends Fast Track program - 2024-12-13T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Indemo expands loan offerings and ends Fast Track program</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.629116+00:00</updated>
    <content>Indemo has announced an increase in loan availability, enhancing investor opportunities. The platform will also discontinue its fast-track program in its current form by the end of December 2024.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/indemo"/>
    <published>2024-12-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Danarupiah adjusts interest rates - 2024-12-13T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Danarupiah adjusts interest rates</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.629026+00:00</updated>
    <content>From December 16th, new Danarupiah loans will offer a 13% annual interest rate, while existing loans remain unchanged. This update aligns with OJK regulations in Indonesia, ensuring competitive returns. Investors should update their Auto Invest settings to include the new rate.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/income"/>
    <published>2024-12-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Multitude Bank partners with HeavyFinance to invest EUR 14 million - 2024-12-12T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Multitude Bank partners with HeavyFinance to invest EUR 14 million</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.628939+00:00</updated>
    <content>Multitude Bank will invest EUR 14 million through HeavyFinance to support small and medium-sized farms in adopting sustainable practices. Investments start in December 2024, with full deployment by the end of 2025.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/heavy-finance"/>
    <published>2024-12-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>LANDE reports strong November performance - 2024-12-12T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>LANDE reports strong November performance</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.628851+00:00</updated>
    <content>LANDE issued €1.18 million in loans across 37 projects in November, with most backed by land or machinery. Investors earned €119,987 in interest, while total repaid principal reached €11.96 million. Debt recovery saw notable progress, including successful recoveries in Latvia and Lithuania. New partnerships in Romania and improved repayment habits across markets highlight LANDE’s ongoing commitment to financial stability and sustainability.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/lande"/>
    <published>2024-12-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Signet Bank partners with Capitalia - 2024-12-12T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Signet Bank partners with Capitalia</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.628762+00:00</updated>
    <content>Signet Bank, the platform's first institutional investor, has committed up to €5 million over two years, boosting funding for small and medium-sized enterprises.

In November, the platform published 12 projects worth €1.65 million, including a €408,000 project funded in just two days, highlighting its efficiency and growth potential.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/capitalia"/>
    <published>2024-12-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>PeerBerry achieves new milestones in November - 2024-12-02T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>PeerBerry achieves new milestones in November</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.628675+00:00</updated>
    <content>In November, PeerBerry investors funded EUR 32.33 million in loans and earned EUR 910,282 in interest. The platform’s total portfolio exceeded EUR 117.31 million, with 1,316 new investors joining, raising the total user base to over 93,000. Since launch, PeerBerry has facilitated EUR 2.86 billion in loans, delivering EUR 37.99 million in interest to investors.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/peerberry"/>
    <published>2024-12-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Fintown hits €500,000 in interest paid &amp; earns prestigious nomination - 2024-11-28T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Fintown hits €500,000 in interest paid &amp; earns prestigious nomination</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.628588+00:00</updated>
    <content>Fintown celebrates paying over €500,000 in interest to investors and earning a Project of the Year 2024 nomination for Honest Ricany. Public voting could boost the project's visibility and bookings. Support Honest Ricany in the competition and help it shine!</content>
    <link href="https://www.projektroku.cz/projekt-honest-ricany-132/"/>
    <published>2024-11-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Indemo’s latest debt repayment delivers 24.14% in ROI - 2024-11-27T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Indemo’s latest debt repayment delivers 24.14% in ROI</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.628498+00:00</updated>
    <content>Indemo has completed its second debt repayment for November, distributing €218,254.50 across 655 investor portfolios. Annualized ROI ranged from 15.1% to 65.7%, averaging an impressive 24.14%, highlighting the strong potential of discounted debt investments.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/indemo"/>
    <published>2024-11-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Fintown launches new investment opportunity: Park Vista - 2024-11-27T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Fintown launches new investment opportunity: Park Vista</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.628405+00:00</updated>
    <content>Park Vista offers a 13% p.a. return over a 24-month term with a 69% LTV. The project, valued at €7,570,000, is supported by a Fintown loan of €2,064,000 and €900,000 in developer equity. Payments are structured as a bullet payout at the end of the term.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/fintown"/>
    <published>2024-11-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Indemo raises €556,000 - 2024-11-22T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Indemo raises €556,000</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.628299+00:00</updated>
    <content>Indemo has secured €556,000 in its 2024 equity funding round, supporting expansion across 29 EU/EEA states. Key initiatives include a secondary market for trading mortgage debts and new income-focused investment options in Spanish real estate.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/indemo"/>
    <published>2024-11-22T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Fintown launches new statistics page to boost transparency for investors - 2024-11-21T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Fintown launches new statistics page to boost transparency for investors</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.628211+00:00</updated>
    <content>Fintown has unveiled a new statistics page, offering investors a clear and concise overview of its loan book performance, track record, and yields. This initiative significantly enhances transparency, empowering investors with the data they need to make informed, data-driven decisions.</content>
    <link href="https://c.trackmytarget.com/?a=z77799&amp;i=6ckbe7&amp;r=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.fintown.eu%2Fstatistics"/>
    <published>2024-11-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Reinvest24 faces investor backlash amid legal challenges, project delays, and communication silence - 2024-11-20T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Reinvest24 faces investor backlash amid legal challenges, project delays, and communication silence</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.628123+00:00</updated>
    <content>Reinvest24, under CEO Tanel Orro, has recently addressed legal developments in Moldova and Spain, indicating efforts to secure external financing to complete certain development projects. Additionally, some rental properties have been listed for sale. While a detailed recovery plan has not been disclosed, the company anticipates exiting multiple properties and repaying investors by 2025. Communication with affected investors has reportedly been conducted via email; however, public updates have been absent since July. This lack of transparency, coupled with unprocessed withdrawal requests and unanswered investor inquiries, has led to skepticism within the investor community regarding the authenticity of the provided information.</content>
    <link href="https://youtu.be/urpgOQmUYcQ?si=kXHFf6dLtIqgbi-i"/>
    <published>2024-11-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>New real estate opportunities in Riga - 2024-11-20T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>New real estate opportunities in Riga</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.628031+00:00</updated>
    <content>Entrum Latvia has launched four new investment opportunities in Riga’s Old Town, offering yields of up to 7% with monthly payments and a 30-year maturity. The total available investment is €554,548, catering to high investor demand for stable rental income.

Founded in 2024, Entrum Latvia specializes in managing rental properties, leveraging platforms like Airbnb for steady revenue.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/mintos"/>
    <published>2024-11-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Nectaro's Auto-Invest is now available! - 2024-11-14T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Nectaro's Auto-Invest is now available!</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.627744+00:00</updated>
    <content>Nectaro has launched its new Auto-Invest feature, allowing investors to automate their portfolios by setting parameters like country, loan term, and interest rate preferences. With support for up to three strategies executed daily, Auto-Invest offers a streamlined way to manage idle funds without manual input.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/nectaro"/>
    <published>2024-11-14T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>P2P Portfolio Update | October 2024 - 2024-11-13T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>P2P Portfolio Update | October 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.627656+00:00</updated>
    <content>Learn more about the recent changes in our P2P lending portfolio.</content>
    <link href="https://p2pempire.com/en/portfolio"/>
    <published>2024-11-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Exclusive interview with Nectaro CEO Sigita Kotlere: Moldova and Romania investment insights - 2024-11-13T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Exclusive interview with Nectaro CEO Sigita Kotlere: Moldova and Romania investment insights</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.627567+00:00</updated>
    <content>In an exclusive interview, Nectaro CEO Sigita Kotlere shared insights on the platform’s investment opportunities in Moldova and Romania. She highlighted loan types, regulatory challenges, liquidity, and funding sources, offering a transparent view of the risks and returns for investors. Kotlere also discussed the potential introduction of group guarantees, and the platform’s commitment to transparency in performance reporting. Watch the full interview in our Nectaro review.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/nectaro"/>
    <published>2024-11-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Indemo delivers up to 33% ROI with €211,024 in repayments on A27 Townhouse on Penote - 2024-11-07T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Indemo delivers up to 33% ROI with €211,024 in repayments on A27 Townhouse on Penote</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.627478+00:00</updated>
    <content>Indemo has completed total repayments of €211,024, impacting around 41% of investor portfolios that included Notes tied to the discounted debt in the A27 Townhouse on Penote. The achieved ROI ranged from 15% to 33% per annum, depending on the investment entry date. Initially listed on Indemo in November 2023, the debt began at the "Auction Initiated" Flow stage with a Price to Value of 65%. Over time, it progressed through various Recovery Flow stages, ultimately reaching the "Access to Estate" stage. The debt was later sold on the secondary market to a debt buyer specializing in post-auction assets.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/indemo"/>
    <published>2024-11-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>ClickCash pauses repayments - 2024-10-22T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>ClickCash pauses repayments</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.627374+00:00</updated>
    <content>Income Marketplace is pausing repayments for ClickCash, a Brazilian lender, until the end of November 2024. ClickCash has been suspended from the platform since November 2022, with 40.9% of its outstanding debt recovered so far. The temporary halt in repayments is due to ClickCash's efforts to raise additional funds for its revitalization plan.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/income"/>
    <published>2024-10-22T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Swaper will be witholding income tax for Estonian residents - 2024-10-16T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Swaper will be witholding income tax for Estonian residents</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.627269+00:00</updated>
    <content>Starting from 28.10.2024, Swaper will be withholding income tax for Estonian residents. If you are an individual residing in the Republic of Estonia, Swaper is required to withhold and pay income tax on your earned income in accordance with the laws and regulations of the Republic of Estonia.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/swaper"/>
    <published>2024-10-16T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>HeavyFinance reaches 60.57M EUR in loan issuance, with 28% of portfolio facing challenges - 2024-10-09T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>HeavyFinance reaches 60.57M EUR in loan issuance, with 28% of portfolio facing challenges</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.627181+00:00</updated>
    <content>In September, HeavyFinance facilitated investments totaling 1.33 million EUR, including 713K EUR across 24 agricultural projects. The platform now has a total loan issuance of 60.57 million EUR. For October, 2.29 million EUR in repayments are scheduled, with 28% of the outstanding portfolio currently not performing as expected, highlighting some challenges while still driving impact in European agriculture.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/heavy-finance"/>
    <published>2024-10-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Income introduces loan announcement bot on Telegram - 2024-10-01T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Income introduces loan announcement bot on Telegram</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.627092+00:00</updated>
    <content>Income has introduced a Telegram bot to provide real-time updates on the latest loan investment opportunities. Investors can now receive instant notifications of new loans and enjoy convenient access to updates directly through Telegram.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/income"/>
    <published>2024-10-01T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>EstateGuru clarifies the terms for the inactivity fee - 2024-10-01T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>EstateGuru clarifies the terms for the inactivity fee</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.627004+00:00</updated>
    <content>If a User's account is inactive for over a year and has funds, an inactive account fee will be charged, as per the Price List. The Portal Operator will notify the User 7 days before the first and each monthly fee deduction. During this time, Users can withdraw funds without a service fee.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/estateguru"/>
    <published>2024-10-01T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Aventus Group expands offerings with new Romanian loans - 2024-09-24T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Aventus Group expands offerings with new Romanian loans</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.626916+00:00</updated>
    <content>Aventus Group lender Acredit from Romania now offers up to 90-day business loans on the PeerBerry platform, providing investors with a 9% annual return. These loans are backed by a buyback and group guarantee. Acredit is the second Romanian lender from Aventus to join PeerBerry, following Credit7 RO, which has shifted its loan offerings from short-term to 90-day business loans with a similar 9% interest rate. Investors are encouraged to adjust their Auto Invest settings accordingly.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/peerberry"/>
    <published>2024-09-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>LANDE reports strong loan performance for August 2024 - 2024-09-24T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>LANDE reports strong loan performance for August 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.626827+00:00</updated>
    <content>In August 2024, LANDE saw a total of €639,750 issued across 45 projects, with 88% of the loans backed by collateral. The average loan-to-value ratio (LTV) across Latvia, Lithuania, and Romania was 49%. Repayments in August reached €681,597, while total repaid principal stands at €8.72 million. Loan repayment delays were primarily due to seasonal factors in agriculture, particularly affecting Latvian farmers. Despite challenges, the overall default rate remains low, and debt recovery processes continue smoothly across key markets.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/lande"/>
    <published>2024-09-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>UltraDinero from Mexico joins PeerBerry with 9% annual return on short-term loans - 2024-09-10T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>UltraDinero from Mexico joins PeerBerry with 9% annual return on short-term loans</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.626738+00:00</updated>
    <content>Aventus Group’s Mexican lender, UltraDinero, has expanded its offerings to the PeerBerry platform, now providing short-term loans with an annual return of 9% to investors. These loans come with both a buyback guarantee and a group guarantee, ensuring an added layer of security for investors. UltraDinero loans will be available on PeerBerry every business day.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/peerberry"/>
    <published>2024-09-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>August 2024 Performance Update Is Now Available! - 2024-08-17T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>August 2024 Performance Update Is Now Available!</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.626649+00:00</updated>
    <content>We've released a new video showcasing the top-performing P2P lending platforms for August 2024. This video includes the latest news and insights that could affect your investments on these platforms.</content>
    <link href="https://p2pempire.com/en/comparison"/>
    <published>2024-08-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Hoovi reports doubling of net income in 2023 and significant growth in loan portfolio - 2024-08-07T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Hoovi reports doubling of net income in 2023 and significant growth in loan portfolio</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.626561+00:00</updated>
    <content>Hoovi has announced its 2023 financial results, showcasing impressive growth. The company’s net income doubled to EUR 960,349, with a net profit of EUR 307,467. Their net loan portfolio also expanded significantly, from EUR 2,229,749 in 2022 to EUR 4,648,794 in 2023. Since joining the Income platform in February 2022, Hoovi has attracted over EUR 7.2M in investments, generating EUR 330k for investors. Offering yields up to 14% per annum, Hoovi-originated loans continue to be an attractive investment option.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/income"/>
    <published>2024-08-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Vihorev Group opened its rental project "Honest Ricany" - 2024-08-01T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Vihorev Group opened its rental project "Honest Ricany"</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.626472+00:00</updated>
    <content>The crowdlending platform announced that "Honest Ricany" is now operational. Fintown is offering investments in "Honest Ricany" with annual interest rates of 10% or 12%, depending on the loan period.</content>
    <link href="/newsfeed"/>
    <published>2024-08-01T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Crowdpear reports another default - 2024-07-27T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Crowdpear reports another default</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.626379+00:00</updated>
    <content>Crowdpear has terminated its contract with UAB "Sondvitus," which had borrowed money for the development of the "Azalijų 1" project. Due to a dispute between the borrower and its business partner, the court has initiated insolvency proceedings.

While investors receive an additional 5% annual interest for each day of delay, under the Law on Insolvency of Legal Entities of the Republic of Lithuania, interest on investments in the "Azalijų 1" project loans will no longer accumulate from the date of the court's decision regarding UAB "Sondvitus"'s insolvency case, effective from July 25th of this year.

Crowdpear is confident that the project's low Loan-to-Value (LTV) ratio of 53% will enable the company to recover all of the investors' funds.</content>
    <link href="https://crowdpear.com/en/client/account/news/a28b3ac9-b66a-4c12-9277-70c20066aac9"/>
    <published>2024-07-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>TWINO's lender in Vietnam defaulted with a €1.3M loss - 2024-07-15T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>TWINO's lender in Vietnam defaulted with a €1.3M loss</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.626278+00:00</updated>
    <content>TWINO's high-risk venture in collaboration with the VIA SMS Group in Vietnam is over. The company informed selected investors via email that the lender, Hoang Kim Nhat Company Ltd in Vietnam, is preparing for liquidation. TWINO announced that the currently outstanding debt to investors is at €2.7 M, out of which €600,000 should be returned to investors by the end of August 2024. Another €800,000 should be returned by the end of January 2026. Whether TWINO will recover the remaining €1.3 M of investors' funds is unclear.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/twino"/>
    <published>2024-07-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>P2P Portfolio Update | June 2024 - 2024-07-06T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>P2P Portfolio Update | June 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.626189+00:00</updated>
    <content>Learn more about the recent changes in our P2P lending portfolio.</content>
    <link href="https://p2pempire.com/en/portfolio"/>
    <published>2024-07-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>New lender &amp; fractional bonds - 2024-07-05T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>New lender &amp; fractional bonds</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.626101+00:00</updated>
    <content>Mintos has introduced two new investment opportunities: Nera Capital, a UK-based lender offering corporate loans to law firms with expected returns of 14% and loan amounts ranging from £800 to £2,200, and new fractional bonds from Sun Finance, an online consumer financing platform, with an 11% coupon rate, monthly payments, and a 3-year maturity.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/mintos"/>
    <published>2024-07-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Review Update - 2024-07-04T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Review Update</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.626013+00:00</updated>
    <content>We have added new information about Fintown's owners, risks, and currently available projects.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/fintown"/>
    <published>2024-07-04T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Aktualisierung des Erfahrungsberichts - 2024-07-04T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Aktualisierung des Erfahrungsberichts</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.625924+00:00</updated>
    <content>Wir haben neue Informationen über die Eigentümer von Fintown, die Risiken und die aktuell verfügbaren Projekte hinzugefügt.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/fintown"/>
    <published>2024-07-04T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Update to the automated portfolio management strategies - 2024-07-03T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Update to the automated portfolio management strategies</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.625837+00:00</updated>
    <content>VIAINVEST announced amendments to the maximum investment amounts per investment into one security for the Diversified (from €100) and Active (from €500) strategies. These changes will take effect on 5 August 2024.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/viainvest"/>
    <published>2024-07-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Kredis is now listing loans on IUVO - 2024-07-03T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Kredis is now listing loans on IUVO</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.625748+00:00</updated>
    <content>IUVO onboarded a new lending company from Croatia. Kredis is part of the MFG and it offers investments in loans with a duration of 4 months with an interest of 9.5% p.a.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/iuvo-group"/>
    <published>2024-07-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Mintos launches Smart Cash - 2024-06-27T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Mintos launches Smart Cash</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.625660+00:00</updated>
    <content>Mintos launched Smart Cash, which pays up to 3.75% interest p.a. on cash deposits. Mintos Smart Cash invests in a low-volatility and highly liquid money market fund managed by BlackRock. Users can withdraw their money on the same day.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/mintos"/>
    <published>2024-06-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Esketit starts offering business loans from MojoCapital - 2024-06-07T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Esketit starts offering business loans from MojoCapital</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.625571+00:00</updated>
    <content>Esketit starts listing business loans with a 12% interest rate and a loan term of 24 months. The loan originator, MojoCapital, is owned by the same owners as Esketit. From 12.06.2024, those loans will be added to Esketit's automated Diversified strategy.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/esketit"/>
    <published>2024-06-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>EstateGuru raises withdrawal fees and introduces a monthly €10 fee for inactive accounts - 2024-06-04T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>EstateGuru raises withdrawal fees and introduces a monthly €10 fee for inactive accounts</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.625482+00:00</updated>
    <content>EstateGuru users who have not invested funds for the past 12 months will be charged a €10 inactivity fee per month. Additionally, EstateGuru increased the withdrawal fee from €1 to €3. The new fee structure further decreases the return for users with defaulted loans who do not wish to continue investing but have locked funds on the platform due to EstateGuru's poor risk management.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/estateguru"/>
    <published>2024-06-04T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Decrease of net return for 2023, change of the CEO - 2024-06-01T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Decrease of net return for 2023, change of the CEO</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.625389+00:00</updated>
    <content>UnaFinancial released its financials from 2023, reporting a significant decrease in net return due to the sale of the lending business in Vietnam and investments in new services in Asia. Natalya Ischenko also announced its departure from UnaFinancial. The founder, Sergey Sedov, is returning as the CEO.</content>
    <link href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=fdke7vEltrw"/>
    <published>2024-06-01T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Crowdestor informs investors about its outstanding portfolio - 2024-04-22T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Crowdestor informs investors about its outstanding portfolio</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.625284+00:00</updated>
    <content>Crowdestor released information about the status of outstanding projects. The platform identifies €27.94 M of its portfolio as problematic.</content>
    <link href="https://crowdestor.com/uploads/Project_statuses_list.pdf?utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=outstanding-portfolio-update&amp;utm_source=platform"/>
    <published>2024-04-22T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>CrowdedHero offers investments in SIMPLEROS for a 14.25% annual return - 2024-04-19T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>CrowdedHero offers investments in SIMPLEROS for a 14.25% annual return</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.625195+00:00</updated>
    <content>CrowdedHero offers the option to invest in SIMPLEROS, a Spanish lending company founded and operated by Santa Lemsa, former Chief Risk Officer at the Robocash Group. The project offers a fixed loan term of 2 years and semi-annual interest payouts.</content>
    <link href="https://crowdedhero.com/uploads/documents/yMPYEtLZMWvs0C0YwbVgfI5a56OtV0tl.pdf"/>
    <published>2024-04-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Mintos announces the next crowdfunding round - 2024-03-29T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Mintos announces the next crowdfunding round</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.625107+00:00</updated>
    <content>Mintos announced it will start the next crowdfunding campaign on Crowdcube in early April. A return on investment is made via a liquidity event such as an IPO or Mintos being acquired by another company.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/mintos"/>
    <published>2024-03-29T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>LendPlus from South Africa started listing loans on PeerBerry - 2024-03-19T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>LendPlus from South Africa started listing loans on PeerBerry</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.625020+00:00</updated>
    <content>Aventus Group lender LendPlus from South Africa has started offering short-term loans on PeerBerry. The South African loans are backed with a buyback and a group guarantee and will generate an 11% annual return to PeerBerry investors. LendPlus ZA loans will be available on the platform every business day. If these loans meet your investment strategy, include LendPlus ZA in your Auto Invest portfolio.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/peerberry"/>
    <published>2024-03-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Crowdpear is adjusting limits on discounts and premiums on the secondary market - 2024-03-07T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Crowdpear is adjusting limits on discounts and premiums on the secondary market</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.624933+00:00</updated>
    <content>In response to feedback and requests from investors, the platform adjusted pricing limits on the secondary market. The maximum premium price limit is set at +20%, and a maximum discount limit of -50% for trades on the secondary market.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/crowdpear"/>
    <published>2024-03-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>CreditStar is decreasing the amount in pending payments - 2024-03-07T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>CreditStar is decreasing the amount in pending payments</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.624843+00:00</updated>
    <content>Some investors reported that the amount in pending payments from CreditStar has decreased in recent days.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/lendermarket"/>
    <published>2024-03-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Investors are experiencing withdrawal delays - 2024-02-28T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Investors are experiencing withdrawal delays</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.624754+00:00</updated>
    <content>Bondora reported a technical issue, causing withdrawals to be "stuck" in "reserved funds."</content>
    <link href="/en/review/bondora"/>
    <published>2024-02-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Debitum will be migrating to a new domain - 2024-02-27T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Debitum will be migrating to a new domain</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.624659+00:00</updated>
    <content>From February 28, 2024, the business loan platform Debitum will transition to a new domain: debitum.investments</content>
    <link href="/en/review/debitum-network"/>
    <published>2024-02-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>The Office of Competition and Consumer Protection in Poland fines CreamFinance amid their illegal refinancing practices - 2024-02-23T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>The Office of Competition and Consumer Protection in Poland fines CreamFinance amid their illegal refinancing practices</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.624569+00:00</updated>
    <content>For violating the collective interests of consumers, the Office of Competition and Consumer Protection imposed a financial penalty on Creamfinance Poland of PLN 2,949,471. Three related entities were also fined: MDP Finance – PLN 1,885,941, KIM Finance – PLN 2,545,098 and JJK Credit – PLN 88,833. There is no imminent risk for investors as the lenders from Poland have no exposure on Esketit.</content>
    <link href="https://bank.pl/uokik-karze-za-rolowanie-pozyczek/"/>
    <published>2024-02-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>VIVUS repaid all delayed loans - 2024-02-09T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>VIVUS repaid all delayed loans</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.624480+00:00</updated>
    <content>The loan originator, VIVUS from Mexico, repaid the outstanding amount, including accrued interest, back to investors.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/income"/>
    <published>2024-02-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Exclusive Interview: EstateGuru's Recovery Plan For 2024 - 2024-02-09T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Exclusive Interview: EstateGuru's Recovery Plan For 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.624388+00:00</updated>
    <content>Dive into exclusive insights with the CEO at EstateGuru. Learn about the expected recoveries in 2024, forecasted loss rates for Germany, Finland, and the Baltics, pivotal credit policy changes, and EstateGuru's financial health.</content>
    <link href="https://www.buymeacoffee.com/p2pempire/estateguru-recovery-plan-for-2024"/>
    <published>2024-02-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Reinvest24 has suspended primary and secondary market transaction - 2024-02-06T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Reinvest24 has suspended primary and secondary market transaction</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.624285+00:00</updated>
    <content>The platform informed investors that it is temporarily pausing transactions on the secondary market. Reinvest24 also removed the primary market offers. Last month, the Estonian Financial Supervisory issued a warning as Reinvest24 is operating without the necessary authorization.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/reinvest24"/>
    <published>2024-02-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>New criteria for defaulted loans - 2024-01-29T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>New criteria for defaulted loans</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.624198+00:00</updated>
    <content>The essential criteria for a loan to be classified as default on LANDE include a payment delay exceeding 90 days (with variations based on market or schedule type), absence of refinancing options, and/or a complete lack of communication between the borrower and debt collection officers.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/lande"/>
    <published>2024-01-29T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>LANDE expects to receive the ECSP license by the end of the month - 2024-01-18T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>LANDE expects to receive the ECSP license by the end of the month</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.624110+00:00</updated>
    <content>LANDE currently continues its operations in Latvia, as the company is in the final stages of obtaining the required license. The Latvian regulator has not mandated a halt in operations. Operations in Romania are currently paused, pending the acquisition of the necessary license.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/lande"/>
    <published>2024-01-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>LANDE is in the process of updating its debt collection policy - 2024-01-18T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>LANDE is in the process of updating its debt collection policy</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.624012+00:00</updated>
    <content>The exact criteria for a loan moving into default status will be communicated to investors in the upcoming newsletter, expected to be released in the next few days.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/lande"/>
    <published>2024-01-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>The platform is raising funds to cover legal fees against its shareholder and borrower KIRSAN - 2024-01-09T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>The platform is raising funds to cover legal fees against its shareholder and borrower KIRSAN</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.623923+00:00</updated>
    <content>Reinvest24 is raising funds from "a limited group of verified investors, who have a serious interest in Reinvest24 succeeding with the legal recovery". Many concerned investors are questioning Reinvest24's intentions, given the platform is not replying to emails and is delaying withdrawals for up to 40 days. Since Reinvest24 is not regulated in Estonia, it's questionable whether the company can raise further funds from retail investors. Reinvest24 has not given enough information about the legal action or the portfolio performance in Spain. Any further investments on this platform are connected with extreme risk.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/reinvest24"/>
    <published>2024-01-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>The investigation into Nexo has been closed - 2023-12-27T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>The investigation into Nexo has been closed</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.623834+00:00</updated>
    <content>The investigation into Nexo was ended on the grounds that Bulgaria found no evidence of crime.</content>
    <link href="https://blockworks.co/news/bulgaria-concludes-nexo-investigation"/>
    <published>2023-12-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Afranga has moved to sticredit.eu - 2023-12-29T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Afranga has moved to sticredit.eu</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.623746+00:00</updated>
    <content>The platform moved to a new domain, sticredit.eu, until the company updated its website afranga.com to fit the regulatory requirements.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/afranga"/>
    <published>2023-12-29T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Instant Exit Program is currently disabled - 2023-12-29T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Instant Exit Program is currently disabled</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.623657+00:00</updated>
    <content>Instant Exit has been temporarily disabled while EstateGuru updates the program to align with the new European Crowdfunding Regulations.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/estateguru"/>
    <published>2023-12-29T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>A portion of funds from VIVUS MX has been repaid - 2023-12-28T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>A portion of funds from VIVUS MX has been repaid</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.623568+00:00</updated>
    <content>The loan originator, Vivus from Mexico, repaid about 65% of the outstanding debt to investors.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/income"/>
    <published>2023-12-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Vote for the worst P2P lending platform - 2023-12-23T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Vote for the worst P2P lending platform</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.623478+00:00</updated>
    <content>Have you felt cheated by P2P lending platforms? Get ready to voice your concerns and shed light on issues within the P2P lending industry! Click the link below to cast your vote and expose the shortcomings of the worst platform.</content>
    <link href="https://forms.gle/RsrjZS6N9MwxuGjW8"/>
    <published>2023-12-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Esketit offers investments in music royalties - 2023-12-20T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Esketit offers investments in music royalties</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.623386+00:00</updated>
    <content>Investors can now earn 9% interest by investing in advances for artists through Utopia. Those investments come with a 90-day buyback obligation. The advances will be added to Esketit's automated Diversified strategy from 02.01.2024.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/esketit"/>
    <published>2023-12-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>PeerBerry exited the Polish loan listings - 2023-12-20T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>PeerBerry exited the Polish loan listings</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.623282+00:00</updated>
    <content>PeerBerry completed the repayments of the last Polish loans. Over EUR 20 million of Polish loans and the accrued interest were repaid to investors in November and December. The platform plans to onboard ten new lenders in H1 2024.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/peerberry"/>
    <published>2023-12-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>LANDE is pausing all transactions on the secondary market - 2023-12-19T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>LANDE is pausing all transactions on the secondary market</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.623192+00:00</updated>
    <content>LANDE announced that it is temporarily pausing transactions on the secondary market until the platform migrates to the new IT system.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/lande"/>
    <published>2023-12-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>The platform is temporarily pausing new loan listings - 2023-11-28T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>The platform is temporarily pausing new loan listings</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.623102+00:00</updated>
    <content>Due to the ongoing crowdfunding application, Lendermarket has temporarily paused new loan listings on the platform.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/lendermarket"/>
    <published>2023-11-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Credito365 from Mexico starts offering loans on PeerBerry - 2023-12-01T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Credito365 from Mexico starts offering loans on PeerBerry</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.623012+00:00</updated>
    <content>Aventus Group lender Credito365 from Mexico has started offering short-term loans on the PeerBerry platform. Mexican loans are backed with a buyback and a group guarantee and will generate a 10% annual return to PeerBerry investors.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/peerberry"/>
    <published>2023-12-01T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Reinvest24 fails to update investors on latest developments - 2023-12-01T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Reinvest24 fails to update investors on latest developments</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.622924+00:00</updated>
    <content>The Estonian crowdlending platform Reinvest24 fails to communicate the progress on the loan recoveries in Moldova and the non-performing Spanish portfolio.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/reinvest24"/>
    <published>2023-12-01T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Vivus from Mexico isn't honoring the buyback guarantee - 2023-12-01T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Vivus from Mexico isn't honoring the buyback guarantee</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.622836+00:00</updated>
    <content>The payday lender, Vivus from Mexico, has still not covered all the obligations towards investors. The platform fails to communicate updates regarding the non-fulfillment of the buyback obligation from Vivus.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/income"/>
    <published>2023-12-01T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Technical maintenance works - 2023-12-01T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Technical maintenance works</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.622747+00:00</updated>
    <content>InRento announced that some of the platform's features may not be accessible from the 1. December 4 PM (EET) until the 4. December 12 PM due to scheduled maintenance work.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/inrento"/>
    <published>2023-12-01T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>First recovery from the German portfolio is expected in Q2/2024 - 2023-11-28T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>First recovery from the German portfolio is expected in Q2/2024</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.622659+00:00</updated>
    <content>5% of the German portfolio is performing well, with borrowers seeking refinancing or project exit. About 50% of defaulted borrowers are cooperating with partner Steinberg for resolution, while 10% undergo asset search or legal actions. The most challenging 35% face a 2-year recovery timeline with ongoing legal efforts. Seven insolvency proceedings are underway, taking at least a year, and forced auctions are avoided due to market conditions.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/estateguru"/>
    <published>2023-11-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Twino is broadening its footprint in the riskiest market - 2023-11-28T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Twino is broadening its footprint in the riskiest market</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.622570+00:00</updated>
    <content>TWINO has just revealed its plans to expand its lending portfolio in Vietnam, a market widely viewed as one of the riskiest for lending globally. Regulatory challenges have led many established lending groups to exit Vietnam.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/twino"/>
    <published>2023-11-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Update on the merger with KoM - 2023-11-11T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Update on the merger with KoM</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.622479+00:00</updated>
    <content>Kapitaal op Maat (KoM) and Max Crowdfund (MCF) have teamed up to strengthen their presence in the European crowdfunding market. KoM, leveraging its European Crowdfunding Service Provider Regulation (ECSPR) license, is expanding its crowdfunding activities across Europe following the acquisition of Capital Circle's platform. Simultaneously, MCF seeks a partnership for continuity without an ECSPR permit but with an AFM exemption. Discussions are underway for a potential merger to enhance European expansion, with both parties actively engaging potential partners. MCF is launching a Series-B equity round to fund growth, inviting existing shareholders and users of MCF, KoM, and Capital Circle. The raised funds will also go towards acquiring additional platforms, creating a unified European marketplace.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/max-crowdfund"/>
    <published>2023-11-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Lendermarket will start listing loans from Rapicredit - 2023-11-07T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Lendermarket will start listing loans from Rapicredit</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.622385+00:00</updated>
    <content>Rapicredit will use Lendermarket to list its Colombian loans with an 18% interest. Rapicredit has just repaid its debt to investors on Bondster after not honoring the buyback guarantee for 12 months.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/lendermarket"/>
    <published>2023-11-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Afranga increases loan availability - 2023-11-05T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Afranga increases loan availability</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.622283+00:00</updated>
    <content>Afranga has increased loan availability from its in-house loan originator, Stikcredit.  The platform offers 10% APY for investments in loans from Bulgaria.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/afranga"/>
    <published>2023-11-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Latest statistical data has been updated - 2023-11-05T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Latest statistical data has been updated</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.622196+00:00</updated>
    <content>P2P Empire updated the publicly available statistical data from all platforms.</content>
    <link href="https://p2pempire.com/en/newsfeed"/>
    <published>2023-11-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Exclusive interview with the CEO about the delisting of loans from Poland - 2023-11-04T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Exclusive interview with the CEO about the delisting of loans from Poland</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.622107+00:00</updated>
    <content>PeerBerry will be delisting all loans from Poland, representing 17% of PeerBerry's outstanding portfolio. Watch our exclusive interview with the CEO, Arunas Lekavicius, where we discuss the changes and upcoming plans for PeerBerry.</content>
    <link href="https://www.buymeacoffee.com/p2pempire/the-end-of-polish-loans-on-peerberry"/>
    <published>2023-11-04T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Banking holidays in Lithuania from 1. to 2. November 2023 - 2023-10-31T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Banking holidays in Lithuania from 1. to 2. November 2023</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.622019+00:00</updated>
    <content>Due to the upcoming banking holidays in Lithuania, withdrawals from Lithuanian platforms or P2P lending sites that use Lithuanian payment solutions will be delayed.</content>
    <link href="https://p2pempire.com/en/newsfeed"/>
    <published>2023-10-31T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>PeerBerry is updating its Auto Invest - 2023-10-31T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>PeerBerry is updating its Auto Invest</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.621931+00:00</updated>
    <content>The platform improving its Auto Invest by removing old/outdated parameters. Investors are requested to review their Auto Invest settings. The platform supports up to five Auto Invest strategies.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/peerberry"/>
    <published>2023-10-31T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Deadline to receive the ECSP license in Lithuania - 2023-10-31T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Deadline to receive the ECSP license in Lithuania</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.621837+00:00</updated>
    <content>Lithuanian crowdlending platforms that don't receive the ESCP license until the 10. November 2023 won't be able to offer new investment opportunities.</content>
    <link href="https://p2pempire.com/en/newsfeed"/>
    <published>2023-10-31T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Selling and buying full bullet loans is temporarily unavailable - 2023-10-27T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Selling and buying full bullet loans is temporarily unavailable</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.621748+00:00</updated>
    <content>LANDE informed its users that the buying and selling full bullet loans is temporarily unavailable. The platform is working on fixing this issue.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/lande"/>
    <published>2023-10-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>PeerBerry repays €45.86M or 91.3% of war-affected loans - 2023-10-16T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>PeerBerry repays €45.86M or 91.3% of war-affected loans</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.621659+00:00</updated>
    <content>In 20 months of the war (since February 24, 2022), PeerBerry business partners Aventus Group and Gofingo Group have, in total, repaid PeerBerry investors EUR 45.86 million or 91.3% of the total outstanding war-affected obligations. A large portion of the portfolio from the Gofingo Group is yet to be recovered.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/peerberry"/>
    <published>2023-10-16T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>EstateGuru introduces a 0.05% AUM monthly fee - 2023-10-16T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>EstateGuru introduces a 0.05% AUM monthly fee</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.621570+00:00</updated>
    <content>EstateGuru announced that it will be deducting 0.05% "Asset Under Management" fee on newly funded investments from 01.11.2023. The monthly fee will be 0.05% (e.g., €0.5 for every €1000) of the principal balance on performing loans and is only applicable to investors who receive returns within the given month on their outstanding performing principal.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/estateguru"/>
    <published>2023-10-16T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>UnaFinancial is leaving Vietnam - 2023-10-11T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>UnaFinancial is leaving Vietnam</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.621480+00:00</updated>
    <content>UnaFinancial (previously Robocash Group) has decided to suspend its operations in Vietnam for the time being to prioritize development in strategic markets. The decision to suspend the business in this country resulted from careful consideration and weighing complex factors, including economic risks and the current market climate. With the Vietnamese project suspended, investors' money in RC Riga Singapore will be reallocated to fund other businesses of UnaFinancial.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/robocash"/>
    <published>2023-10-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Esketit reassures investors investing in Jordan - 2023-10-10T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Esketit reassures investors investing in Jordan</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.621341+00:00</updated>
    <content>Despite the Israeli-Palestinian conflict, the lending business in Jordan continues running smoothly without disruption. The local lender continues to increase its lending volumes while maintaining a calculated risk profile.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/esketit"/>
    <published>2023-10-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Best &amp; worst performing platforms for September - 2023-09-17T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Best &amp; worst performing platforms for September</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.621253+00:00</updated>
    <content>The best-performing platforms in September are Robocash, Esketit, InRento, Crowdpear, and Fintown. Click on the link below to analyze the latest statistical data.</content>
    <link href="https://p2pempire.com/en/comparison"/>
    <published>2023-09-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Robocash continues to lower the offered interest rates - 2023-09-15T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Robocash continues to lower the offered interest rates</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.621162+00:00</updated>
    <content>Investors on Robocash continue experiencing cash drag, which is why the platform will lower the interest rates for its loans with loan periods between 31 days to 3 years. The new interest rates will be ranging from 8% to 11%.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/robocash"/>
    <published>2023-09-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Max Crowdfund's application for the ECSPR has been rejected - 2023-09-15T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Max Crowdfund's application for the ECSPR has been rejected</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.621074+00:00</updated>
    <content>Yesterday, the Max Crowdfund team received the official letter from the Authority Financial Markets (AFM) in the Netherlands which rejected Max Crowdfund's ECSPR license application.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/max-crowdfund"/>
    <published>2023-09-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Capitalia will be under maintenance on the 16th and 17th of September - 2023-09-15T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Capitalia will be under maintenance on the 16th and 17th of September</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.620984+00:00</updated>
    <content>Capitalia is updating its platform which is why it may be unavailable during the scheduled maintenance period.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/capitalia"/>
    <published>2023-09-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Fintown lowers the minimum investment amount - 2023-09-12T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Fintown lowers the minimum investment amount</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.620894+00:00</updated>
    <content>The Czech crowdlending platform Fintown lowered the minimum investment threshold to €1 to enable investors to reinvest the earned interest quickly.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/fintown"/>
    <published>2023-09-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Lendermarket is not honoring the buyback guarantee - 2023-09-12T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Lendermarket is not honoring the buyback guarantee</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.620807+00:00</updated>
    <content>Lendermarket continues not to honor the advertised buyback guarantee. The platform continues to extend loans up to six times before they appear in "pending payments" for an unknown period of time.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/lendermarket"/>
    <published>2023-09-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Heavy Finance Website Maintenance - 2023-09-04T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Heavy Finance Website Maintenance</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.620717+00:00</updated>
    <content>The Heavy Finance platform will be undergoing scheduled maintenance on the 5. September 2023 from 4:00 CET to 12:00 CET. The website might not be accessible during this period.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/heavy-finance"/>
    <published>2023-09-04T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Reinvest24 will be liquidating assets in Spain to repay investors - 2023-08-25T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Reinvest24 will be liquidating assets in Spain to repay investors</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.620629+00:00</updated>
    <content>The Estonian crowdfunding platform reported that the new management in Spain would sell assets to repay investors who invested in projects such as La Canada, L' Eliana, Montesano, Xirivella, Gandia Playa, and the Casablanca projects. Reinvest24 expects the repayment of the first project within the next three to four months.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/reinvest24"/>
    <published>2023-08-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Fintown launches a loyalty program - 2023-08-22T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Fintown launches a loyalty program</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.620539+00:00</updated>
    <content>The P2P platform Fintown launches a VIP Club. Investors with an investment amount between €10,000 and €29,999 will receive an additional 0.5% bonus on top of their investments. Investments of more than €30,000 will grant investors a 1% bonus. Any VIP bonuses can be reinvested or withdrawn after 12 months.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/fintown"/>
    <published>2023-08-22T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>PeerBerry repays € 1.8 M in war-affected loans - 2023-08-16T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>PeerBerry repays € 1.8 M in war-affected loans</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.620447+00:00</updated>
    <content>PeerBerry's business partners repaid another €1.8 M in war-affected loans from Ukraine and Russia. PeerBerry business partners have already repaid EUR 44,58 million, or 89% of the total war-affected obligations towards PeerBerry investors. Aventus Group is yet to repay €2,908,989, whereas the remaining obligation by Gofingo Group is higher at €4,380,834..</content>
    <link href="/en/review/peerberry"/>
    <published>2023-08-16T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Investors report issues with buyback guarantee from FastFinance - 2023-08-16T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Investors report issues with buyback guarantee from FastFinance</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.620336+00:00</updated>
    <content>Investors report delays with the lender FastFinance. The buyback guarantee hasn't been triggered. The support claims it's a technical issue.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/iuvo-group"/>
    <published>2023-08-16T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>P2P Empire recorded an exclusive interview with the CEO of Fintown - 2023-08-16T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>P2P Empire recorded an exclusive interview with the CEO of Fintown</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.620244+00:00</updated>
    <content>Members of P2P Empire can enjoy our exclusive interview with the founder and CEO of Fintown. We have covered the business model, liquidity management, risks, and plans for the platform.</content>
    <link href="https://www.buymeacoffee.com/p2pempire/interview-ceo-fintown"/>
    <published>2023-08-16T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Debitum changes owners and removes DEB token features - 2023-07-28T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Debitum changes owners and removes DEB token features</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.620153+00:00</updated>
    <content>The legal entity behind Debitum platform, DN Operator changes ownership from Mārtiņš Liberts to Henrijs Jansons, Ingus Salmiņš and Ēriks Reņģītis. The former management of Debitum Network raised over € 6 Million worth of DEB tokens to fund the platform's development. The new leadership distances itself from the DEB token and removes it from the platform, claiming the legal entity behind Debitum platform doesn't have any connection to the Token Generation Event conducted by the previous management.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/debitum-network"/>
    <published>2023-07-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Cash Drag on Income - 2023-07-31T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Cash Drag on Income</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.620061+00:00</updated>
    <content>Income Marketplace reports low loan availability due to the season and changes in investment structures from larger lending companies. Investors should explore other top-rated platforms to get their funds invested.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/income"/>
    <published>2023-07-31T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Reinvest24 replaced management in Spain due to poor portfolio performance - 2023-07-28T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Reinvest24 replaced management in Spain due to poor portfolio performance</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.619971+00:00</updated>
    <content>Reinvest24 is undergoing several changes in its Spanish branch. The management and its business partners, such as the construction company and real estate agency, are about to be replaced. As a result of the ongoing challenges, Reinvest24 has stopped listing investment opportunities from Spain until the portfolio quality is improved.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/reinvest24"/>
    <published>2023-07-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Crowdpear received the ESCP license - 2023-07-27T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Crowdpear received the ESCP license</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.619881+00:00</updated>
    <content>Crowdpear became an EU-level regulated crowdfunding platform that enables the platform to provide services throughout the EU.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/crowdpear"/>
    <published>2023-07-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Heavy Finance received the ECSP license - 2023-07-26T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Heavy Finance received the ECSP license</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.619792+00:00</updated>
    <content>Heavy Finance received the European Service Providers licenses issued by the European Securities and Markets Authority (ESMA). This license provides enhanced investor protection.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/heavy-finance"/>
    <published>2023-07-26T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Capitalia will withold 20% income tax - 2023-07-21T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Capitalia will withold 20% income tax</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.619703+00:00</updated>
    <content>Starting from the 1st of September of this year, Capitalia will deduct a 20% personal income tax from the income received by investors - interest and late payment fees. Going forward, investors will receive the full principal amount of their loans and 80% of the total interest and late payment fees.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/capitalia"/>
    <published>2023-07-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Lendermarket introduced "pending payments" - 2023-07-19T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Lendermarket introduced "pending payments"</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.619613+00:00</updated>
    <content>When a Loan Originator notifies Lendermarket of a borrower's repayment, a "Pending Payment" status is assigned. At this point, Lendermarket has only received notice of the upcoming transfer. Lendermarket is still waiting for the Loan Originator to complete the transfer to Lendermarket.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/lendermarket"/>
    <published>2023-07-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>rethink-p2p reports about the questionable practices of the failed p2p platform Credon and the connection to Hive5 - 2023-07-19T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>rethink-p2p reports about the questionable practices of the failed p2p platform Credon and the connection to Hive5</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.619523+00:00</updated>
    <content>The German rethink-p2p.de page reports on the harmful practices of Credon and the connection of the shareholder to Hive5's business partner. The Croatian Hive5 platform is threatening to take legal action against the author of rethink-p2p.de for the revelations of questionable practices by the shareholder of Credon and business partner of Hive5, Juozas Rupšys.</content>
    <link href="https://rethink-p2p.de/en/credon-review/"/>
    <published>2023-07-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Vivus Mexico is moving to a new direct listing structure - 2023-07-17T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Vivus Mexico is moving to a new direct listing structure</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.619432+00:00</updated>
    <content>The Mexican lending company Vivus will be listing short-term loans from Mexico under a new direct listing structure.  This process has taken more time than anticipated, mainly due to IT bottlenecks on Vivus' side, and it looks like it will not be resolved in the very near future. Vivus won't be listing any new loans until the new structure is in place. The lender informed the Income Marketplace that it will clear all late loans by the 21. July 2023.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/income"/>
    <published>2023-07-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>PeerBerry repaid €42.65 M in war-affected loans - 2023-07-17T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>PeerBerry repaid €42.65 M in war-affected loans</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.619317+00:00</updated>
    <content>PeerBerry's business partners repaid another €1,8 M in war-affected loans from Ukraine and Russia. PeerBerry business partners have already repaid EUR 42,65 million, or 85% of the total war-affected obligations towards PeerBerry investors.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/peerberry"/>
    <published>2023-07-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Celsius founder Alex Mashinsky arrested and charged with fraud - 2023-07-15T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Celsius founder Alex Mashinsky arrested and charged with fraud</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.619227+00:00</updated>
    <content>Alex Mashinsky, the founder of bankrupt cryptocurrency lender Celsius Network, has been arrested by US authorities and charged with fraud and market manipulation.</content>
    <link href="https://www.ft.com/content/f58b1a33-3610-4cd5-b1ce-95c2ee1a1f7a"/>
    <published>2023-07-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Lendermarket allows the investment of "pending payments" - 2023-08-05T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Lendermarket allows the investment of "pending payments"</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.619135+00:00</updated>
    <content>The P2P marketplace enables investors to invest pending payments in the currently available loans. Pending payments are funds that are not available for withdrawal as the platform doesn't dispose of the funds.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/lendermarket"/>
    <published>2023-08-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Esketit shares information about how to handle potential investment risk - 2023-08-08T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Esketit shares information about how to handle potential investment risk</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.619044+00:00</updated>
    <content>Esketit released a statement about how the platform aims to deal with potential investment risk. In a follow-up message, the CEO confirmed that, currently, there is nothing that investors should be worried about. The platform is proactive to ensure that if certain risks materialize, they are being handled according to investors' expectations.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/esketit"/>
    <published>2023-08-08T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Crowdpear launched a news section - 2023-08-08T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Crowdpear launched a news section</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.618953+00:00</updated>
    <content>The crowdlending platform launched a notification feature for its desktop version.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/crowdpear"/>
    <published>2023-08-08T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>PeerBerry has launched a news section - 2023-08-08T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>PeerBerry has launched a news section</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.618862+00:00</updated>
    <content>The p2p lending marketplace launched a notification feature for its desktop version.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/peerberry"/>
    <published>2023-08-08T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>InRento's mailing system is being mantained - 2023-08-08T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>InRento's mailing system is being mantained</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.618771+00:00</updated>
    <content>Due to the scheduled mailing service maintenance, investors might be experiencing issues with email notifications. The system should by updated by the end of next business week.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/inrento"/>
    <published>2023-08-08T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Issues with the allocation of funds from Vivus, Mexico - 2023-08-08T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Issues with the allocation of funds from Vivus, Mexico</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.618682+00:00</updated>
    <content>Income Marketplace reported that the allocated funds from Vivus have been carried out prematurely due to data discrepancies. The team has been rolling back the transfers, which may have resulted in negative balances on customer accounts. The platform is working on resolving the issues.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/income"/>
    <published>2023-08-08T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Former CEO filed a privacy complaint against P2P Empire - 2023-08-15T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Former CEO filed a privacy complaint against P2P Empire</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.618594+00:00</updated>
    <content>Former CEO of Twino, Anastasija Oleinika filed a privacy complaint against an interview we recorded in May 2021. She wished to be no longer associated with the content as she left the company.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/twino"/>
    <published>2023-08-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Max Crowdfund is under maintenance - 2023-08-25T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Max Crowdfund is under maintenance</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.618504+00:00</updated>
    <content>The crowdfunding platform is updating its platform, which is why the website won't be accessible until the 4th of September 2023.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/max-crowdfund"/>
    <published>2023-08-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Aventus Group will finish the repayment of war-affected loans on 5th September 2023 - 2023-08-30T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Aventus Group will finish the repayment of war-affected loans on 5th September 2023</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.618411+00:00</updated>
    <content>The final repayment of €1.28 million will be processed on September 5. The Gofingo Group will continue the repayments in monthly installments of €200,000 or more until the remaining obligations of €4.18 million are repaid.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/peerberry"/>
    <published>2023-08-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Low loan availability on Esketit, Robocash, PeerBerry, Income, Afranga - 2023-08-31T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Low loan availability on Esketit, Robocash, PeerBerry, Income, Afranga</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.618304+00:00</updated>
    <content>The loan availability on many top-rated P2P lending platforms is low. New investors should consider suitable alternatives to earn interest from P2P lending.</content>
    <link href="https://p2pempire.com/en/newsfeed"/>
    <published>2023-08-31T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Robocash decreases the reward for loyal investors - 2023-08-31T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Robocash decreases the reward for loyal investors</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.618215+00:00</updated>
    <content>The P2P lending platform lowered the rewards for loyal investors. The minimum threshold to receive an increased interest was adjusted from €5,000 to €20,000. Investors who invest less than €20,000 won't be treated as loyal investors anymore.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/robocash"/>
    <published>2023-08-31T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Aventus Group will finish the repayment of war-affected short-term loans on 5th September 2023 - 2023-08-30T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Aventus Group will finish the repayment of war-affected short-term loans on 5th September 2023</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.618126+00:00</updated>
    <content>The final repayment of war-affected short-term loans of €1.28 million will be processed on September 5. The Gofingo Group will continue the repayments in monthly installments of €200,000 or more until the remaining obligations of €4.18 million are repaid.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/peerberry"/>
    <published>2023-08-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>The Robocash Group rebranded to UnaFinancial - 2023-09-07T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>The Robocash Group rebranded to UnaFinancial</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.618036+00:00</updated>
    <content>One of the leading financial groups - Robocash Group, rebranded to UnaFinancial to better reflect on the group's goal to build a more diversified portfolio of financial services.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/robocash"/>
    <published>2023-09-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Lendermarket replaces its CEO again - 2023-09-17T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Lendermarket replaces its CEO again</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.617944+00:00</updated>
    <content>The recently hired CEO Conor Gibney is no longer part of Lendermarket. The platform hired Carles Frederico Arnabat as the new CEO. The platform has not publicly communicated the change in management.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/lendermarket"/>
    <published>2023-09-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Esketit starts offering USD loans - 2023-09-18T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Esketit starts offering USD loans</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.617854+00:00</updated>
    <content>Esketit started offering USD loans with a 13% interest rate from its lending partner "Money for Finance" in Jordan. All USD loans come with a buyback guarantee.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/esketit"/>
    <published>2023-09-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Lande experienced a SSH-based attack - 2023-09-28T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Lande experienced a SSH-based attack</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.617764+00:00</updated>
    <content>The Latvian crowdlending platform informed its users about an SSH-based attack on its servers. The platform has strengthened the IT infrastructure which should prevent future incidents.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/lande"/>
    <published>2023-09-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>InRento generated between 23.54% and 35.34% ROI for investors - 2023-09-28T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>InRento generated between 23.54% and 35.34% ROI for investors</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.617675+00:00</updated>
    <content>The Lithuanian crowdlending platform InRento has sold two properties with variable capital gains. The return on investment for this project ranged from 23.54% to 35.34%, depending on the phases that investors invested in.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/inrento"/>
    <published>2023-09-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Smartcredito from Spain joins PeerBerry - 2023-09-30T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Smartcredito from Spain joins PeerBerry</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.617584+00:00</updated>
    <content>Smartcredito, launched by Aventus Group, will offer PeerBerry investors investments in short-term loans with a 10% annual return. Loans provided by Smartcredito to PeerBerry investors include a buyback and a group guarantee.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/peerberry"/>
    <published>2023-09-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>P2P Empire interviews the CEO at Lonvest - 2023-10-20T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>P2P Empire interviews the CEO at Lonvest</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.617493+00:00</updated>
    <content>The CEO Roman Katerynchyk joins P2P Empire to discuss the the lending business in Vietnam and Poland. The full interview is available for members only.</content>
    <link href="https://www.buymeacoffee.com/p2pempire/what-you-need-to-know-about-lonvest"/>
    <published>2023-10-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>New CEO at Income Marketplace - 2023-10-23T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>New CEO at Income Marketplace</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.617394+00:00</updated>
    <content>Lavrenti Tsudakov has been promoted from COO to CEO. Kimmo Rytkönen, the founder and former CEO, will be focusing on business development.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/income"/>
    <published>2023-10-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>MaxCrowdfund is considering a possible merger with Kapitaal op Maat (KoM) - 2023-10-25T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>MaxCrowdfund is considering a possible merger with Kapitaal op Maat (KoM)</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.617284+00:00</updated>
    <content>The dutch crowdlending platform is considering to merge with KoM, which holds the ECSPR license.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/max-crowdfund"/>
    <published>2023-10-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>LoanPlus from Sri Lanka starts listing loans on PeerBerry - 2023-10-25T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>LoanPlus from Sri Lanka starts listing loans on PeerBerry</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.617195+00:00</updated>
    <content>LoanPlus will offer PeerBerry investors investments in short-term loans with an 11.5% annual return. Loans provided by LoanPlus are backed by a buyback and a group guarantee.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/peerberry"/>
    <published>2023-10-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Schedule of technical maintenance works - 2023-10-26T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Schedule of technical maintenance works</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.617106+00:00</updated>
    <content>Please be informed that in order to improve users' experience of InRento, from this Thursday (26 October) 4 p.m. (CEST) until next Monday (30 October)  10:00 a.m., the platform will be undergoing technical maintenance works, which may lead to disruptions. The platform will also be updating its secondary market in November which can cause temporary restrictions.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/inrento"/>
    <published>2023-10-26T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Rapicredit repays all delayed loans - 2023-11-02T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Rapicredit repays all delayed loans</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.617014+00:00</updated>
    <content>Rapicredit from Colombia has repaid all outstanding loans to investors.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/bondster"/>
    <published>2023-11-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Loan availability in Jordan has increased - 2023-11-02T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Loan availability in Jordan has increased</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.616890+00:00</updated>
    <content>Esketit reports that the loan availability from the loan originator Money for Finance in Jordan has increased.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/esketit"/>
    <published>2023-11-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>PeerBerry will stop offering loans from Poland - 2023-11-04T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>PeerBerry will stop offering loans from Poland</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.616743+00:00</updated>
    <content>The platform announced that it will stop the listing of loans from Poland from January 1, 2024, due to the regulatory change that probits lenders to fund their portfolios via P2P investors. To ensure sufficient loan supply, PeerBerry will offer investments in new lenders via a business loan. As the Polish loans represent 17% of the AUM, it might take up to Q2 2024 to replace the current loan supply.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/peerberry"/>
    <published>2023-11-04T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Vivus is facing bank issues - €500,000 is delayed - 2023-11-10T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Vivus is facing bank issues - €500,000 is delayed</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.616646+00:00</updated>
    <content>The founder of Income has confirmed that the outstanding portfolio of €500,000 from Vivus in Mexico is delayed due to bank transfer issues. The platform is expecting the repayment of the final amount soon.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/income"/>
    <published>2023-11-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>PeerBerry is offering investments in emerging markets - 2023-11-10T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>PeerBerry is offering investments in emerging markets</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.616557+00:00</updated>
    <content>PeerBerry has started offering new business loans, which will be used to fund the portfolios in Mexico, South Africa, Nigeria, Tanzania, and Colombia. The loan term begins at 30 days, and the offered interest rate starts at 9%. All loans are backed by the buyback and group guarantee.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/peerberry"/>
    <published>2023-11-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Updates on the merger with KoM - 2023-11-11T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Updates on the merger with KoM</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.616468+00:00</updated>
    <content>Kapitaal op Maat (KoM) and Max Crowdfund (MCF) have teamed up to strengthen their presence in the European crowdfunding market. KoM, leveraging its European Crowdfunding Service Provider Regulation (ECSPR) license, is expanding its crowdfunding activities across Europe following the acquisition of Capital Circle's platform. Simultaneously, MCF seeks a partnership for continuity without an ECSPR permit but with an AFM exemption. Discussions are underway for a potential merger to enhance European expansion, with both parties actively engaging potential partners. MCF is launching a Series-B equity round to fund growth, inviting existing shareholders and users of MCF, KoM, and Capital Circle. The raised funds will also go towards acquiring additional platforms, creating a unified European marketplace.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/max-crowdfund"/>
    <published>2023-11-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>TWINO will continue funding Polish loans via its platform from 2024 - 2023-11-10T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>TWINO will continue funding Polish loans via its platform from 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.616373+00:00</updated>
    <content>The platform announced that the upcoming regulation doesn't impact TWINO as their lender in Poland is issuing loans via credit cards. According to TWINO's interpretation of the law, the prohibition of funding loans via P2P investors applies only for companies with a lending license that issue cash loans.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/twino"/>
    <published>2023-11-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Profitus receives the ECSP license - 2023-11-10T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Profitus receives the ECSP license</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.616270+00:00</updated>
    <content>The Bank of Lithuania grants Profitus the European Crowdfunding Service Provider license.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/profitus"/>
    <published>2023-11-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>InRento receives the ECSP license - 2023-11-10T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>InRento receives the ECSP license</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.616183+00:00</updated>
    <content>The Bank of Lithuania has issued InRento a European Crowdfunding (ECSP) license. Accordingly, the new license changes the procedures for calculating credit assessment scores, the suitability of a transaction for an investor, and the pricing and rates of interest. Another key change is the possibility for investors to cancel an investment within four days from the date of the transaction, however, this functionality has already been in place on the InRento platform for some time.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/inrento"/>
    <published>2023-11-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>ClickCash is "commited" to repay €5,000 per month - 2023-11-16T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>ClickCash is "commited" to repay €5,000 per month</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.616095+00:00</updated>
    <content>The problematic lender from Brazil, ClickCash is committed to repaying a fixed amount of €5,000 per month. This commitment aims to ensure a steady and predictable flow of repayments to investors. Currently, the principal amount that remains in recovery is €147,991. Should ClickCash not fulfill the repayment schedule, Income Marketplace will step in and cover the difference from its own pocket with the goal of returning the invested principal.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/income"/>
    <published>2023-11-16T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>PeerBerry repays €46.2M or 92% of war-affected loans - 2023-11-15T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>PeerBerry repays €46.2M or 92% of war-affected loans</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.616006+00:00</updated>
    <content>In 21 months of the war (since February 24, 2022), PeerBerry business partners Aventus Group and Gofingo Group have, in total, repaid PeerBerry investors EUR 46.2 million or 92% of the total outstanding war-affected obligations.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/peerberry"/>
    <published>2023-11-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Norstreet received the ESPC license - 2023-11-15T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Norstreet received the ESPC license</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.615916+00:00</updated>
    <content>Nordstreet has been granted a license by the Regulation on European Crowdfunding Service Providers.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/nordstreet"/>
    <published>2023-11-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Chance to win a Kite Safari with Fintown - 2023-11-23T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Chance to win a Kite Safari with Fintown</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.615828+00:00</updated>
    <content>Active investors on Fintown, who submit the registration form by the 21. December 2023, can win a Kite Safari hosted by Fintown. The event will take place from 23 to 30 March 2024 in Egypt.</content>
    <link href="https://985sz39ppoh.typeform.com/to/O8EBA8b8?typeform-source=www.fintown.eu"/>
    <published>2023-11-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Bondster lowers the rating of Right Choice from A- to D - 2023-11-23T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Bondster lowers the rating of Right Choice from A- to D</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.615738+00:00</updated>
    <content>Due to a mistake, Right Choice Finance has issued loans with a 10-day buyback guarantee. The loan originator cannot meet the 10-day buyback guarantee due to the deteriorated short-term liquidity of the entire financial group. Bondster has suspended the possibility of issuing new loans for Right Choice Finance and lowered its rating to D (defaulted).</content>
    <link href="/en/review/bondster"/>
    <published>2023-11-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Norstreet received the ESCP license - 2023-11-15T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Norstreet received the ESCP license</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.615651+00:00</updated>
    <content>Nordstreet has been granted a license by the Regulation on European Crowdfunding Service Providers.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/nordstreet"/>
    <published>2023-11-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Swaper is about to introduce business loans to finance the loan book from Poland - 2023-12-07T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Swaper is about to introduce business loans to finance the loan book from Poland</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.615563+00:00</updated>
    <content>Swaper Platform's subsidiary, SW Finance, now licensed in Estonia, will soon start offering business loans. The new investment opportunities will be used to continue funding Wandoo Finance Group's lending operations.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/swaper"/>
    <published>2023-12-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Statement from DFI, the parent company of Vivus Mexico - 2023-12-07T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Statement from DFI, the parent company of Vivus Mexico</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.615473+00:00</updated>
    <content>Due to internal policy changes, DFI, the parent company of Vivus MX, is transferring financial assets from DFI Cyprus to another institution as their compliance department now denies transfers to organizations without a domicile banking license. The migration process is underway and expected to finish in 3-5 days, after which repayment will resume, with DFI expressing regret for any inconvenience caused. Vivus MX is yet to repay €553,143 to investors.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/income"/>
    <published>2023-12-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Update on the legal recovery in Moldova - 2023-12-08T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Update on the legal recovery in Moldova</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.615379+00:00</updated>
    <content>Attached please find the decision of the Bălți Court in regard to the accelerated restructuring procedure of SRL "Metropolis City". The court has decided in favor of the borrower, meaning all the legal actions are on hold, including the calculation of accrued interest and penalties.</content>
    <link href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1SU7dX2LnO_XkRhqfWEHdChxYwsWT2YBG/view?usp=sharing"/>
    <published>2023-12-08T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>GoFingo repays another €200,000 - 2023-12-16T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>GoFingo repays another €200,000</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.615276+00:00</updated>
    <content>Gofingo Group repaid investors €200,000 in war-affected loans. In 22 months of the war in Ukraine, PeerBerry business partners Aventus Group and Gofingo Group have, in total, repaid investors €46.5 M or 92.6% of the total outstanding war-affected obligations.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/peerberry"/>
    <published>2023-12-16T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Fintown publishes another FLEXI project - 2023-12-16T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Fintown publishes another FLEXI project</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.615186+00:00</updated>
    <content>The Czech-based platform Fintown published another FLEXI project with 8% APY and 30-day lock-up period.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/fintown"/>
    <published>2023-12-16T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Afranga received the ECSP license - 2023-12-16T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Afranga received the ECSP license</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.615097+00:00</updated>
    <content>During the transition period from investments in claim rights to business loans, Afranga.com will temporarily pause new registrations.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/afranga"/>
    <published>2023-12-16T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>KIRSAN took money from apartment buyers and started the insolvency process - 2023-12-16T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>KIRSAN took money from apartment buyers and started the insolvency process</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.615006+00:00</updated>
    <content>Several construction companies under the umbrella of the "Kirsan" concern in Moldova have reached insolvency. The risk of potential bankruptcy upset those who invested their last money just to get an apartment in the capital. People, who have been waiting for years to receive the keys to their new homes, are outraged and worried.</content>
    <link href="https://www.zdg.md/video/video-anchete/mai-multe-companii-din-concernul-kirsan-in-proces-de-insolvabilitate-in-timp-ce-investitorii-care-asteapta-apartamentele-de-mai-multi-ani-acuza-administratori/"/>
    <published>2023-12-16T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Scheduled maintenance on EstateGuru - 2023-12-26T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Scheduled maintenance on EstateGuru</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.614880+00:00</updated>
    <content>EstateGuru is conducting scheduled website maintenance between 26/12/2023 at 7:00 (EET) and 27/12/2023 at 10:00 (EET). During this period, login to the portal, and new registrations will be unavailable.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/estateguru"/>
    <published>2023-12-26T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Esketit starts offering investments in non-performing loans from Spain - 2024-01-11T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Esketit starts offering investments in non-performing loans from Spain</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.614791+00:00</updated>
    <content>Esketit introduces a new investment opportunity in collaboration with Spanda Capital, specializing in acquiring discounted non-performing consumer loan portfolios in Spain. The product offers a 12% interest rate with a 24-month repayment schedule, featuring interest payments for the first six months and partial principal repayments starting from the 7th month. Listed under its Latvian holding company, the investment will be integrated into Esketit's Automated Diversified strategy from January 18th.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/esketit"/>
    <published>2024-01-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>The platform is raising funds to cover legal fees for its projects in Moldova - 2024-01-09T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>The platform is raising funds to cover legal fees for its projects in Moldova</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.614702+00:00</updated>
    <content>Reinvest24 is raising funds from "a limited group of verified investors, who have a serious interest in Reinvest24 succeeding with the legal recovery". Many concerned investors are questioning Reinvest24's intentions, given the platform is not replying to emails and is delaying withdrawals for up to 40 days. Since Reinvest24 is not regulated in Estonia, it's questionable whether the company can raise further funds from retail investors. Reinvest24 has not given enough information about the legal action or the portfolio performance in Spain. Any further investments on this platform are connected with extreme risk.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/reinvest24"/>
    <published>2024-01-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>The issuance of crowdlending offers in EU member states without a respective license is prohibited - 2024-01-15T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>The issuance of crowdlending offers in EU member states without a respective license is prohibited</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.614612+00:00</updated>
    <content>Crowdfunding service providers who are registered in EU member states and have failed to obtain authorization by 10 November 2023, in accordance with the regulation 2020/1503 recital 77 are service providers are prohibited from raising funds via crowdfunding offers. Investors who believe that a crowdfunding platform doesn't have the required authorization and continues issuing crowdfunding offers can contact the local police.</content>
    <link href="https://eur-lex.europa.eu/legal-content/EN/TXT/?uri=CELEX%3A32020R1503"/>
    <published>2024-01-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Gofingo Group repays another €200.000 in war-affected loans - 2024-01-15T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Gofingo Group repays another €200.000 in war-affected loans</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.614522+00:00</updated>
    <content>Throughout the 23-month war period, commencing on February 24, 2022, PeerBerry's business partners have successfully fulfilled their commitments by repaying a total of EUR 46.8 million to PeerBerry investors. This amounts to an impressive 93.2% of the overall outstanding obligations impacted by the conflict.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/peerberry"/>
    <published>2024-01-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>UnaPay temporarily halts new loans and announces closure of existing loans - 2024-01-18T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>UnaPay temporarily halts new loans and announces closure of existing loans</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.614430+00:00</updated>
    <content>UnaPay announces a temporary halt on new loan placements and the closure of all existing loans by the end of February. Repayment of principal and accrued interest on current loans will be conducted promptly.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/robocash"/>
    <published>2024-01-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Submit your questions for EstateGuru's CEO - 2024-01-24T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Submit your questions for EstateGuru's CEO</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.614322+00:00</updated>
    <content>P2P Empire will be interviewing the CEO of EstateGuru, Mihkel Stamm. Submit your questions to discuss the platform's current state and plans for recovering defaulted loans. Your participation is crucial for an informative dialogue.</content>
    <link href="https://app.sli.do/event/jpMRadUj3u3rV9qj7j36fY"/>
    <published>2024-01-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Exclusive: Esketit Investment Update! - 2024-01-27T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Exclusive: Esketit Investment Update!</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.614233+00:00</updated>
    <content>Explore Esketit's revamped loan offerings in a candid interview with CEO Vitalijs Zalovs. Get insights into investment structures, risks, and guarantees without any fluff.
Topics covered include the impact of Gaza on Jordan's portfolio, potential conflict scenarios, AvaFin's 2024 plans, investments in music royalties and defaulted Spanish loans.</content>
    <link href="https://www.buymeacoffee.com/p2pempire/big-changes-on-esketit"/>
    <published>2024-01-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>The Estonian Financial Supervisory has issued a warning in regards to the activities of Reinvest24 - 2024-01-30T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>The Estonian Financial Supervisory has issued a warning in regards to the activities of Reinvest24</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.614145+00:00</updated>
    <content>The Estonian Financial Supervisor is warning investors about the suspicion that Reinvest24 continues to offer crowdfunding services without authorization.</content>
    <link href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1ajcLaomhiWN8qnXY_bFF73jxY0n5MQmk/view?usp=sharing"/>
    <published>2024-01-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Top-up option is unavailable - 2024-02-01T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Top-up option is unavailable</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.614057+00:00</updated>
    <content>Lonvest has disabled the top-up option on the platform.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/lonvest"/>
    <published>2024-02-01T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Reinvest24 has suspended secondary market transaction - 2024-02-06T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Reinvest24 has suspended secondary market transaction</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.613968+00:00</updated>
    <content>The platform informed investors that it is temporarily pausing transactions on the secondary market. Last month, the Estonian Financial Supervisory issued a warning as Reinvest24 is operating without the necessary authorization.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/reinvest24"/>
    <published>2024-02-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>New lender and legal actions against Right Choice Finance - 2024-02-07T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>New lender and legal actions against Right Choice Finance</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.613881+00:00</updated>
    <content>Bondster announced that it is now listing loans from Advanto, a Czech fintech providing employee benefit of early earned wage access. The platform also revealed that it started legal actions against Right Choice Finance as the company failed to fulfill the buyback guarantee.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/bondster"/>
    <published>2024-02-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>LANDE received the ECSP license - 2024-02-12T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>LANDE received the ECSP license</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.613793+00:00</updated>
    <content>The Supervision Committee of Latvijas Banka has issued the Crowdfunding Services Authorization to the LANDE Platform.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/lande"/>
    <published>2024-02-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Gofingo Group repays €200.000 in war-affected loans - 2024-02-16T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Gofingo Group repays €200.000 in war-affected loans</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.613705+00:00</updated>
    <content>Gofingo Group has repaid €7.19 M in war-affected loans so far. Gofingo's remaining obligations are €2.9 M.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/peerberry"/>
    <published>2024-02-16T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Gofingo Group repaid another €200,000 - 2024-03-16T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Gofingo Group repaid another €200,000</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.613614+00:00</updated>
    <content>In 25 months of the war, PeerBerry business partners have repaid € 47.36 M, or 94.3% of the total outstanding war-affected obligations to investors.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/peerberry"/>
    <published>2024-03-16T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Capitec acquires controlling shares in Avafin for €26.3 million - 2024-04-02T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Capitec acquires controlling shares in Avafin for €26.3 million</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.613524+00:00</updated>
    <content>The South African bank Capitec is increasing its shares in Avafin Holding Limited from 40.66% to 97.69% for a purchase price of €26.3 million.</content>
    <link href="https://www.capitecbank.co.za/blog/news/2024/capitec-to-acquire-controlling-interest-in-avafin-holding-limited/"/>
    <published>2024-04-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Aventus Group made €53.8 M in net profit in 2023 - 2024-04-03T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Aventus Group made €53.8 M in net profit in 2023</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.613434+00:00</updated>
    <content>Lending companies operating under the Aventus Group name made €53.8 M in net profits in 2023, an annual increase of 260%.</content>
    <link href="https://c.trackmytarget.com/?a=wc58g4&amp;i=6ckbe7&amp;r=https%3A%2F%2Fpeerberry.com%2Fin-2023-aventus-group-lending-companies-made-eur-53-8-million-in-net-profit%2F"/>
    <published>2024-04-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Capitalia is adding a knowledge assessment test and the loss simulator - 2024-04-10T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Capitalia is adding a knowledge assessment test and the loss simulator</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.613326+00:00</updated>
    <content>Capitalia has added more risk-related features that help investors better understand the risks connected to the funding of business loans.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/capitalia"/>
    <published>2024-04-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>TWINO is exiting the lending business in Vietnam and in the Philippines - 2024-04-11T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>TWINO is exiting the lending business in Vietnam and in the Philippines</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.613237+00:00</updated>
    <content>TWINO announced that it will exit the joint venture lending business with VIA SMS Group in Vietnam due to the "increasingly challenging local business environment." Additionally, the TWINO Group has made a strategic decision to exit the Philippines venture, therefore suspending its operations in the Asia-Pacific region.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/twino"/>
    <published>2024-04-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>AvaFin published audited financial report for 2023 - 2024-04-12T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>AvaFin published audited financial report for 2023</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.613149+00:00</updated>
    <content>The AvaFin group ended FY 2023 with €32 M in equity, €80 M in liabilities, and €7.8 M in net profit. Auditors did not report any misstatements.</content>
    <link href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1jFNCn3TkK1XgIIZqTSFzihjgSMr8xLMK/view?usp=sharing"/>
    <published>2024-04-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>LANDE is strengthening its debt collection procedures - 2024-04-16T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>LANDE is strengthening its debt collection procedures</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.613058+00:00</updated>
    <content>LANDE announce new collaborations with debt collection lawyers in Latvia and Lithuania to speed up the recovery of defaulted loans.</content>
    <link href="https://c.trackmytarget.com/?a=lfw4z1&amp;i=6ckbe7&amp;r=https%3A%2F%2Flande.finance%2Fblog%2Flande-platform-performance-report-march-2024"/>
    <published>2024-04-16T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Audited financials from Money for Finance and the decrease of interest rates for Jordanian loans - 2024-04-23T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Audited financials from Money for Finance and the decrease of interest rates for Jordanian loans</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.612970+00:00</updated>
    <content>Money for Finance released its financials for 2023. The company reports €28.57 M in revenue, €4.16 M in net profit, and €5.49 M in equity. From April 29th, the platform will list Jordanian EUR loans at 11% and USD loans at 12%.</content>
    <link href="https://esketit.cdn.prismic.io/esketit/ZidoRfPdc1huKsWH_MFFSignedFinancialStatements2023EnglishFinalforEsketitinvestors.pdf"/>
    <published>2024-04-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>InRento publishes the audited annual report for 2023 - 2024-04-25T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>InRento publishes the audited annual report for 2023</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.612881+00:00</updated>
    <content>The company reports the following financials for 2023: €170,000 in net profit, €758,456 in revenue, and €350,596 in equity. According to the auditor, the financial statements give a true and fair view of the financial position.</content>
    <link href="https://inrento.com/assets/documents/Auditor%20report%20Inrento%202023.pdf"/>
    <published>2024-04-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>PeerBerry continues to grow amidst regulatory challenges - 2024-05-01T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>PeerBerry continues to grow amidst regulatory challenges</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.612793+00:00</updated>
    <content>In April, PeerBerry's portfolio hit EUR 110.59 million, despite a dip in loan funding to EUR 45.52 million due to fewer offerings, influenced by regulatory changes in Kazakhstan. Investors still earned EUR 901,552 in interest, with expectations for increased short-term loan availability in May.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/peerberry"/>
    <published>2024-05-01T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>VIAINVEST repaid 60% of the outstanding credit lines - 2024-05-09T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>VIAINVEST repaid 60% of the outstanding credit lines</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.612704+00:00</updated>
    <content>VIAINVEST has repaid around 60% of the outstanding credit lines from 2021 to 2022. The platform plans to repay all credit lines by the end of June 2024. VIAINVEST refused to share the amount of outstanding credit lines or the outstanding portfolio amount with P2P Empire.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/viainvest"/>
    <published>2024-05-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Debitum reports a loss for 2023 - 2024-05-10T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Debitum reports a loss for 2023</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.612616+00:00</updated>
    <content>Debitum published the audited financial report for 2023. The platform reports a loss of €358,634 in 2023. While the financial statements give a true and fair view of the financial position of the company, the auditor Grand Thorton reports a material misstatement of certain information in the report.</content>
    <link href="https://docs.debitum.investments/Audited_Annual_Financial_Report_2023_ENG.pdf"/>
    <published>2024-05-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Esketit expands its mortgage loan offerings - 2024-05-23T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Esketit expands its mortgage loan offerings</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.612526+00:00</updated>
    <content>Esketit announced the expansion of its mortgage-backed loan offerings issued by Credus Capital, which operates under the same management as A24 Group. The loans come with a loan period of three years.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/esketit"/>
    <published>2024-05-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Mintos launches passive real estate investments - 2024-05-24T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Mintos launches passive real estate investments</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.612437+00:00</updated>
    <content>Mintos enables investors to invest in financial instruments connected to rental residential real estate. Investors receive regular rental income with the option to liquidate the investment on the secondary market.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/mintos"/>
    <published>2024-05-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Danabijak released its financials for 2023 - 2024-05-24T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Danabijak released its financials for 2023</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.612329+00:00</updated>
    <content>Based on the financial statement provided for 2023, the Company's total revenue in 2023 was 994,000 EUR, a 15% decrease compared to 2022. Danabijak generated an operating profit of 13,000 EUR last year. In 2023, the balance sheet increased by 38% to 713,000 EUR. As of 31.12.2023, the total value of the Company’s share capital was 818,000 EUR.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/income"/>
    <published>2024-05-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Income Marketplace increases the loan offerings - 2024-05-28T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Income Marketplace increases the loan offerings</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.612240+00:00</updated>
    <content>Lending partners such as DanaRupiah, the ITF Group, Hoovi, or the Current Auto increased their loan supply, which reduces cash drag for investors on the platform.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/income"/>
    <published>2024-05-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>PeerBerry publishes its annual report for 2023 - 2024-06-02T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>PeerBerry publishes its annual report for 2023</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.612150+00:00</updated>
    <content>PeerBerry reports a net profit of €437,745 for 2023.</content>
    <link href="https://peerberry.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/05/PeerBerry-Annual-Report-2023.pdf"/>
    <published>2024-06-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>LANDE improves the advanced auto invest and announces a cashback bonus of up to 2% - 2024-06-02T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>LANDE improves the advanced auto invest and announces a cashback bonus of up to 2%</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.612064+00:00</updated>
    <content>LANDE has improved the auto invest by lowering the minimum investment amounts while adding new filters that enable you to define the country and schedule type. The platform also launched a "Summer Boost" cashback campaign where investors can earn up to 2% cashback by investing at least €5000 into a single project in June.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/lande"/>
    <published>2024-06-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>TWINO won't be distributing any yield from its rental business - 2024-06-06T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>TWINO won't be distributing any yield from its rental business</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.611975+00:00</updated>
    <content>Due to the acquisition costs connected to the three rental properties, the management has decided not to distribute any dividends for the reporting period.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/twino"/>
    <published>2024-06-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>EstateGuru has fired one fifth of its employees to reduce costs - 2024-06-08T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>EstateGuru has fired one fifth of its employees to reduce costs</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.611881+00:00</updated>
    <content>The CEO announced that the company is reducing its costs and increasing revenue to achieve profitability by the end of the year.</content>
    <link href="https://estateguru.co/blog/39270/"/>
    <published>2024-06-08T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Ecommoney from Kazakhstan joins PeerBerry - 2024-06-12T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Ecommoney from Kazakhstan joins PeerBerry</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.611792+00:00</updated>
    <content>PeerBerry starts listing consumer loans from Ecommoney in Kazakhstan with a 12-month loan term and an annual interest rate of 9.5%.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/peerberry"/>
    <published>2024-06-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>PeerBerry is adjusting its interest rates - 2024-06-14T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>PeerBerry is adjusting its interest rates</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.611704+00:00</updated>
    <content>The P2P lending marketplace announced that it is changing the interest rates of newly offered loans. The interest will range from 9% to 10.5% per year. Investors should adjust their Auto Invest if they wish to invest in the newly listed loans.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/peerberry"/>
    <published>2024-06-14T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>LANDE reactivated its secondary market - 2024-06-21T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>LANDE reactivated its secondary market</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.611615+00:00</updated>
    <content>The platform reactivated the secondary market with new requirements. The resale of loans will be available only for current loans. Investors will no longer be able to buy loans for less than €50. Furthermore, full bullet loans have been excluded from the secondary market.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/lande"/>
    <published>2024-06-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Important Update on Inactive Account Fees - 2024-06-21T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Important Update on Inactive Account Fees</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.611527+00:00</updated>
    <content>The inactive account fee is applied if the investor has not made any new investments within a 12-month period. €10 is applied once the account has been inactive for 12 months and €50 is applied when the period is respectively 24 months. Prior to any fees being deducted, investors will be informed via email that a fee will be applied, and prior to the fees being deducted, investors will have the ability to withdraw their available balance free of charge to avoid the fee from being deducted. The fee will not be deducted from accounts that have either made a small investment or withdrawn their available funds; nobody’s account will be drawn into minus, and nobody will receive an invoice. Therefore, if investors are keen on being idle and withdrawing their funds, then this fee encourages them to do it free of charge.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/estateguru"/>
    <published>2024-06-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Esketit adds instant deposits - 2024-07-03T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Esketit adds instant deposits</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.611435+00:00</updated>
    <content>If you have a bank account with one of the bigger banks in Europe, you can instantly top up your Esketit account through the service provided by Ecommpay.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/esketit"/>
    <published>2024-07-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Eriks Rengitis is the new CEO at Debitum - 2024-06-20T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Eriks Rengitis is the new CEO at Debitum</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.611328+00:00</updated>
    <content>Debitum has announced yet another CEO. From now on Eriks Rengitis will be leading the company.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/debitum-network"/>
    <published>2024-06-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>IUVO launched a mobile app - 2024-07-04T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>IUVO launched a mobile app</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.611240+00:00</updated>
    <content>IUVO launched a mobile app for its product iuvoSAFE.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/iuvo-group"/>
    <published>2024-07-04T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>The company closed its office in Rotterdam - 2024-07-10T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>The company closed its office in Rotterdam</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.611153+00:00</updated>
    <content>The platform announced that the office at Brielselaan 85 in Rotterdam is closed as of June 21. Customer support revealed that the company is facing financial difficulties. Investors can view updates only by registering on a dedicated website, the link for which is provided below.</content>
    <link href="https://projectmanagement199.wixstudio.io/site"/>
    <published>2024-07-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Esketit increases loan availability - 2024-07-11T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Esketit increases loan availability</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.611065+00:00</updated>
    <content>Esketit has listed a new loan from Spanda Capital on the primary market with a 12% interest rate. Spanda Capital specializes in the Spanish non-performing lending industry. Additionally, the platform has increased the availability of EUR loans from Jordan and Liechtenstein. Investors can invest in these opportunities through the diversified automated strategy, which enhances their liquidity.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/esketit"/>
    <published>2024-07-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>July 2024 Performance Update Is Now Available! - 2024-07-13T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>July 2024 Performance Update Is Now Available!</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.610976+00:00</updated>
    <content>We've released a new video showcasing the top-performing P2P lending platforms for July 2024. This video includes the latest news and insights that could affect your investments on these platforms.</content>
    <link href="https://p2pempire.com/en/comparison"/>
    <published>2024-07-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Exclusive benefits for premium investors: early access to new investments and reduced secondary market fee - 2024-07-15T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Exclusive benefits for premium investors: early access to new investments and reduced secondary market fee</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.610887+00:00</updated>
    <content>Premium investors who invest more than €50,000 will gain early access to new investment opportunities before they are available to the public. Additionally, these investors will receive a 0.5% discount on Secondary Market trades, reducing the fee from 2% to 1.5%.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/inrento"/>
    <published>2024-07-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Reinvest24 seeks investor input on SPV liquidation strategies - 2024-07-21T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Reinvest24 seeks investor input on SPV liquidation strategies</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.610798+00:00</updated>
    <content>Reinvest24 is seeking investors' opinions on the best approach for liquidating SPVs. The platform is interested in understanding investors' views on an acceptable time frame, expectations for recovering 3rd party projects, and raising funds to cover legal fees.</content>
    <link href="https://jpsbrngd.r.eu-central-1.awstrack.me/L0/https:%2F%2Fwww.isend.info%2Fl%2FWFUK1scD42CEnQJq0mEk5Q%2FfwMzRFjA0MjK4v4MZKItLA%2FDbXVLPG7634OBCrf2yPp9QKw/2/01070190cbc48c88-fc338727-4986-4875-a7d2-c080b55e3615-000000/ae9wC6J_mMdCUMNby0NkGN3HijE=164"/>
    <published>2024-07-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Wandoo Finance is raising funds on CrowdedHero - 2024-07-30T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Wandoo Finance is raising funds on CrowdedHero</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.610710+00:00</updated>
    <content>Wandoo Finance is raising a minimum of €200,000 for two years at a 15% interest rate per annum with quarterly payouts. The funds will be used to grow the lending portfolio in Poland and Spain. The company aims to use part of the funds to invest into machine learning, marketing and customer acquisition.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/crowdedhero"/>
    <published>2024-07-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Crowdpear increased its welcome bonus - 2024-07-30T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Crowdpear increased its welcome bonus</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.610621+00:00</updated>
    <content>The real estate crowdlending platform increased its welcome bonus. New investors will receive a 1% bonus on invested capital during the first 90 days from registration.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/crowdpear"/>
    <published>2024-07-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>UnaFinancial shares financials for H1 2024 - 2024-07-30T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>UnaFinancial shares financials for H1 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.610533+00:00</updated>
    <content>UnaFinancial’s net profit in H1 2024 reached USD 4.7 M, indicating an 18% increase compared to H1 2023. The Group’s revenue and commission income grew by 10%, from USD 93.1 M in H1 2023 to USD 102.1 M in H1 2024.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/robocash"/>
    <published>2024-07-30T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Mintos expands offerings with new listings and interest rate increases - 2024-08-02T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Mintos expands offerings with new listings and interest rate increases</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.610442+00:00</updated>
    <content>AvaFin has begun listing short-term loans from Mexico on Mintos, offering a 10% interest rate. Additionally, Mintos has announced the new listing of a fractional bond from ESTO, featuring a 10.5% coupon rate and a 3-year maturity. The platform also revealed increased interest rates for loans from IDF Eurasia, Iute Group, and Nera Capital.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/mintos"/>
    <published>2024-08-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Exclusive inside look: unveiling Fintown's real estate business in Prague - 2024-08-03T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Exclusive inside look: unveiling Fintown's real estate business in Prague</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.610335+00:00</updated>
    <content>Join us for an exclusive look inside Fintown's headquarters in Prague, where we delve into critical risk questions with the founder and explore their flagship projects. Get transparent insights and behind-the-scenes access in our latest video.</content>
    <link href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=89HtRoQ040M"/>
    <published>2024-08-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Credito365 from Colombia starts offering loans on PeerBerry - 2024-08-08T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Credito365 from Colombia starts offering loans on PeerBerry</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.610245+00:00</updated>
    <content>Aventus Group lender Credito365 from Colombia starts offering short-term loans on the PeerBerry platform. Colombian loans are backed with a buyback and a group guarantee and will generate a 9.5% annual return to PeerBerry investors.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/peerberry"/>
    <published>2024-08-08T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>P2P Portfolio Update | July 2024 - 2024-08-11T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>P2P Portfolio Update | July 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.610157+00:00</updated>
    <content>Learn more about the recent changes in our P2P lending portfolio.</content>
    <link href="https://p2pempire.com/en/portfolio"/>
    <published>2024-08-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Stikcredit releases the audited financial report for 2023 - 2024-08-09T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Stikcredit releases the audited financial report for 2023</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.610068+00:00</updated>
    <content>Stikcredit maintained a strong financial performance in 2023, with revenue holding steady at €12.6 million. The company's management successfully implemented cost-cutting measures, reducing expenses by 13% compared to the previous year. This efficiency contributed to a 17% increase in net income, which rose to €2.9 million. By the end of the year, Stikcredit's total assets amounted to €21.8 million.</content>
    <link href="https://stikcredit.eu/docs/pdf/stikcredit_annual_report_FY2023_ENG.pdf"/>
    <published>2024-08-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Esketit continues to increase loan availability - 2024-08-28T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Esketit continues to increase loan availability</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.609980+00:00</updated>
    <content>The Latvian-based P2P marketplace has seen a significant increase in loan availability across all loan originators. Notably, the volume of AvanFin loans has experienced substantial growth.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/esketit"/>
    <published>2024-08-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Security alert: Investor on TWINO targeted in fraud incident - 2024-09-04T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Security alert: Investor on TWINO targeted in fraud incident</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.609892+00:00</updated>
    <content>A TWINO investor recently fell victim to a fraud scheme in which a scammer gained access to the investor's account. The fraudster changed the email address, sold investments on the secondary market, and then used the stolen identity to open a bank account and clear the investment account. This incident is a reminder that such attacks are not uncommon in the P2P lending industry. We strongly urge all investors to activate two-factor authentication (2FA) and remain vigilant in monitoring their online activities.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/twino"/>
    <published>2024-09-04T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Petr Polenda appoined as new CEO of Bondster - 2024-09-04T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Petr Polenda appoined as new CEO of Bondster</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.609805+00:00</updated>
    <content>Bondster, the Czech P2P investment platform, has appointed Petr Polenda as its new CEO. With over 15 years of experience in banking and financial services, including expertise in lending and risk management, Polenda aims to broaden the platform's investment offerings.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/bondster"/>
    <published>2024-09-04T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>LANDE reports a loss of €73,129 for 2023 - 2024-09-07T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>LANDE reports a loss of €73,129 for 2023</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.609716+00:00</updated>
    <content>The financial statements for SIA "Lande Platform" from January 1, 2023, to December 31, 2023, show a net turnover of €1,610,293, a significant increase from the previous year's €344,014. The gross profit or loss for the period was €782,805, up from €227,011 in 2022. The largest costs were the cost of sales at €482,890 and administration costs of €345,773. After accounting for other income and expenses, the company reported a net loss of €73,129 for 2023, an increase from the €12,981 loss reported in 2022. According to the auditor, the financial report provides a true and clear picture of the company.</content>
    <link href="https://lande.finance/docs/auditor-statement-2023.pdf"/>
    <published>2024-09-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Income reports a loss of €590,252 for 2023 - 2024-09-07T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Income reports a loss of €590,252 for 2023</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.609627+00:00</updated>
    <content>Income doubled its revenues in the reporting year, with partners paying €433,000 in fees. Losses decreased by 40.7%, from €995,000 to €590,000. As of July 31, 2024, the platform had €36,000 in average monthly recurring revenue, 4,231 investors, and €15.1 million in active investments. In 2024, the company aims to grow its investor base, increase partnerships, and raise additional funds.</content>
    <link href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1RYdZr5RIGqn09XRRN2m46DRoZwnTtrwh/view?usp=sharing"/>
    <published>2024-09-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>P2P Empire launches portfolio evaluation reports - 2024-09-13T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>P2P Empire launches portfolio evaluation reports</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.609539+00:00</updated>
    <content>P2P Empire now offers portfolio evaluation reports with updated charts and statistics for all listed platforms. The data is refreshed monthly, giving you regular insights into loan portfolio quality, which impacts both liquidity and returns. You can view these evaluation reports in our individual platform reviews, helping you make informed investment decisions with up-to-date information.</content>
    <link href="https://p2pempire.com/en/newsfeed"/>
    <published>2024-09-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Income launches new long-term investment opportunities - 2024-09-13T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Income launches new long-term investment opportunities</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.609449+00:00</updated>
    <content>Income platform introduces long-term investments from Hoovi and Current Auto, offering stable cash flow, risk diversification, and protection against interest rate fluctuations. Hoovi provides SME loans up to 3 years with 14% p.a., while Current Auto offers 2-year car rental loans with 10% p.a. and early buyout options.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/income"/>
    <published>2024-09-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Bondora temporarily increased it's Go &amp; Grow rate to 6.75% - 2024-09-13T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Bondora temporarily increased it's Go &amp; Grow rate to 6.75%</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.609344+00:00</updated>
    <content>From 9 September until 2 January 2025, Go &amp; Grow offers up to 6.75% per annum. After this period, the rate may change with a 30-day notice.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/bondora"/>
    <published>2024-09-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>P2P Portfolio Update | August 2024 - 2024-09-07T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>P2P Portfolio Update | August 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.609254+00:00</updated>
    <content>Learn more about the recent changes in our P2P lending portfolio.</content>
    <link href="https://p2pempire.com/en/portfolio"/>
    <published>2024-09-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>September 2024 Performance Update Is Now Available! - 2024-09-16T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>September 2024 Performance Update Is Now Available!</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.609165+00:00</updated>
    <content>We've released a new video showcasing the top-performing P2P lending platforms for September 2024. This video includes the latest news and insights that could affect your investments on these platforms.</content>
    <link href="https://p2pempire.com/en/comparison"/>
    <published>2024-09-16T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Stikcredit H1 2024 results: Strong growth and new car loans - 2024-09-21T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Stikcredit H1 2024 results: Strong growth and new car loans</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.609076+00:00</updated>
    <content>Stikcredit has published its results for the first half of 2024, showing significant growth. Net profit increased by over 10% compared to H1 2023, with the loan portfolio growing by 24% since the start of the year. Company assets also rose from €21.8M to €24.4M.

Additionally, the newly introduced auto loans project, still in its pilot phase, is showing promising potential for future expansion.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/afranga"/>
    <published>2024-09-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>VIAINVEST's lenders are giving away €50,000 in cashback bonuses - 2024-09-21T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>VIAINVEST's lenders are giving away €50,000 in cashback bonuses</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.608987+00:00</updated>
    <content>Between September 23 and October 13, 2024, VIAINVEST offers individual investors a chance to receive cashback of up to €700 for new capital investments. Cashback will be credited on November 15, 2024, based on the amount invested during the promotional period.

Investments of €5,000 to €9,999 qualify for a €150 bonus, while those between €10,000 to €19,999 earn €350. Investments exceeding €20,000 will receive a €700 bonus. The total bonus pool is €50,000, distributed on a first-come, first-served basis.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/viainvest"/>
    <published>2024-09-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Hoovi reports a net profit of €180,136 for 2023 - 2024-09-23T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Hoovi reports a net profit of €180,136 for 2023</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.608898+00:00</updated>
    <content>Hoovi has released its H1-2024 financial results, showing strong growth. Total operating income rose by 65% to €1.1 million, while net profit increased by 156% to €180,000 compared to H1-2023.

Since joining the Income platform in 2022, Hoovi has attracted €8 million in investments, with investors earning €377,000 so far. Offering up to 14% annual returns on business loans, Hoovi remains a strong option for investors seeking higher interest rates.</content>
    <link href="https://getincome.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2024/09/Hoovi-financial-statements-H1-2024.pdf"/>
    <published>2024-09-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Lithuanian Development Institution invests in agricultural loans - 2024-09-24T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Lithuanian Development Institution invests in agricultural loans</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.608810+00:00</updated>
    <content>The Lithuanian national development institution ILTE has partnered with HeavyFinance to invest in agricultural loans, aiming to contribute €2 million by the end of 2024. Through the Avietė Crowdfunding Loans facility, ILTE will fund up to 40% of loans, or €30,000, for Lithuanian farmers, with the remainder covered by investors on HeavyFinance.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/heavy-finance"/>
    <published>2024-09-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>New annual fee for Core Loans - 2024-09-24T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>New annual fee for Core Loans</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.608722+00:00</updated>
    <content>Starting 7 October 2024, an annual fee of 0.39% will be applied to all new investments made through Core Loans portfolios. This fee will only apply to investments made after this date. Please note that any investments made before 7 October will remain exempt from the fee, as will investments made through Manual Investment and Custom Automation strategies.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/mintos"/>
    <published>2024-09-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Lonvest is hosting a live Q&amp;A with the CEO - 2024-09-25T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Lonvest is hosting a live Q&amp;A with the CEO</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.608633+00:00</updated>
    <content>Lonvest has announced a Q&amp;A session scheduled for September 26th at 17:00 CET, featuring Roman Katerynchyk, CEO and Founder of Lonvest, and Vadym Bortnyk, Country Manager at SpaceCrew Finance. This event provides investors with an excellent opportunity to learn more about the Mexican loan originator and SpaceCrew Finance's strategic expansion into the LATAM region.</content>
    <link href="https://www.youtube.com/live/uh-n4aLhE48"/>
    <published>2024-09-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Income expands offerings from Current Auto in Latvia and Lithuania - 2024-09-26T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Income expands offerings from Current Auto in Latvia and Lithuania</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.608513+00:00</updated>
    <content>Income now offers investors access to Current Auto’s car rental agreements from Latvia and Lithuania, with yields up to 10% p.a. Current Auto has expanded rapidly since its 2020 launch, originating €7.7 million in rental agreements in Lithuania.

Investors can explore rental agreements with buyback obligations and flexible terms on the Income platform.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/income"/>
    <published>2024-09-26T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>NovaLend from Poland joins PeerBerry - 2024-10-01T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>NovaLend from Poland joins PeerBerry</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.608415+00:00</updated>
    <content>NovaLend, a Polish business lending provider, is now available on PeerBerry, offering an 8% annual return on business loans secured by a buyback guarantee. Launched in March 2023, NovaLend is 40% owned by Aventus Group. CEO Sergii Demchuk, formerly with Debitum, shared that the company has funded €5 million in loans so far, with a default rate of 3%.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/peerberry"/>
    <published>2024-10-01T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Indemo review now available - Exclusive insights from the CEO - 2024-10-01T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Indemo review now available - Exclusive insights from the CEO</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.608299+00:00</updated>
    <content>Check out our detailed review of Indemo, covering one of the highest-yielding regulated investment platforms. Plus, watch our exclusive interview with the founder for insights on what's happening behind the scenes.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/indemo"/>
    <published>2024-10-01T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Capitalia reports €27,000 profit in H1 2024 - 2024-10-03T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Capitalia reports €27,000 profit in H1 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.608208+00:00</updated>
    <content>Capitalia reported a turnover of €764k and a profit of €27k in the first half of 2024, marking the first release of consolidated figures. While operating revenue saw slight growth, financing activity remained stable, with €10.6 million in funding issued, down from €13.03 million in the same period last year. The decrease is attributed to the discontinuation of larger factoring contracts and longer loan terms. Capitalia expects continued growth in consolidated revenue and its portfolio under management.</content>
    <link href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1RpsdMlDj7mOpbCDV-RO1A9sM3ufZML6N/view?usp=sharing"/>
    <published>2024-10-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Crowdpear reports 74% growth in Q3 loan funding, delivering strong returns - 2024-10-04T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Crowdpear reports 74% growth in Q3 loan funding, delivering strong returns</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.608120+00:00</updated>
    <content>In Q3 2024, Crowdpear funded €3.4 million in loans, a 74% increase compared to Q2. September alone saw investors fully fund 13 real estate-backed loans, totaling €1.17 million, while €91,812 was distributed as interest. Additionally, €655,508 in principal plus interest was repaid from 10 loans. Since its inception, Crowdpear investors have funded 189 loans worth €14.32 million and received over €0.64 million in interest, with 78 loans repaid totaling €4.46 million.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/crowdpear"/>
    <published>2024-10-04T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Indemo delivers 15% to 36% annual returns in latest debt repayment - 2024-10-04T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Indemo delivers 15% to 36% annual returns in latest debt repayment</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.608030+00:00</updated>
    <content>Indemo has announced another successful debt repayment, with 208,317 euros repaid across 41 Notes, impacting around 36% of their investor community. Investors saw annual returns ranging between 15% and 36%. The repaid debt, listed as A62 - Apartment in Tossa de Mar, underwent multiple stages on the platform before being sold on the secondary market.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/indemo"/>
    <published>2024-10-04T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Ibancar joins the Income Marketplace - 2024-10-08T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Ibancar joins the Income Marketplace</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.607940+00:00</updated>
    <content>Ibancar’s collateralized installment loans are now live on the Income Marketplace, offering investors up to 11.5% interest per year with loan terms of up to 37 months. Backed by cars with a loan-to-value (LTV) of up to 50%, these loans provide a secure investment option. With a track record of originating €40 million in car loans across Spain and Mexico and currently managing a portfolio of €18 million with a default rate below 8%, Ibancar is a proven lender. All loans include a buyback obligation and are safeguarded by an 11% risk-adjusted Junior Share, delivering enhanced investor protection.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/income"/>
    <published>2024-10-08T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Ricany property reaches 48% occupancy, more projects coming soon - 2024-10-10T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Ricany property reaches 48% occupancy, more projects coming soon</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.607853+00:00</updated>
    <content>Fintown's rental property in Ricany, which opened in August, has already reached a 48% occupancy rate. Overall, two-thirds of Fintown's funded projects are now operational, with 197 out of 228 rental units active. The next project, Honest Michle, featuring 31 units, is scheduled to open in early 2026.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/fintown"/>
    <published>2024-10-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Mintos releases updated information about its suspended lenders - 2024-10-11T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Mintos releases updated information about its suspended lenders</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.607765+00:00</updated>
    <content>Mintos has released updated information on its suspended lenders, detailing the expected recovery amounts and timelines for each.</content>
    <link href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1uTT_AbwiVPUkI01GD2bNB9kzbmeObMUy/edit?usp=sharing&amp;ouid=112733212443575190013&amp;rtpof=true&amp;sd=true"/>
    <published>2024-10-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Swaper publishes annual report for 2023 - 2024-10-14T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Swaper publishes annual report for 2023</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.607675+00:00</updated>
    <content>Swaper has published its 2023 annual report, revealing a loss of €100,739 for the year. Despite this, loan volumes grew by 64% compared to 2022, and the platform paid out €7.57 million in interest to investors. More details can be found in the attached report.</content>
    <link href="https://swaper.com/en/assets/reports/swaper_platform_ou_annual_report_2023.pdf"/>
    <published>2024-10-14T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Changes to the crypto feature on Esketit - 2024-10-18T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Changes to the crypto feature on Esketit</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.607587+00:00</updated>
    <content>Esketit has disabled the crypto feature for new investors and those who have not previously used it. However, the feature remains available for users who have utilized it in the past. Going forward, Esketit offers investment options exclusively in EUR and USD.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/esketit"/>
    <published>2024-10-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Update on Fintown’s rental revenue performance - 2024-10-19T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Update on Fintown’s rental revenue performance</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.607497+00:00</updated>
    <content>Fintown has shared an update on the revenue and occupancy rates of its operational rental units. Honest Smichov generated €49,745 in total revenue, with an average daily rate of €72 and an occupancy rate of 87%. Honest Karlin, which began operations in May 2024, generated €62,326, with an average daily rate of €79 and an occupancy rate of 86%. Honest Ricany, Fintown’s flagship project launched in August 2024, has earned €83,640 so far, with a daily rate of €41 and a current occupancy rate of 62% as of October 14.</content>
    <link href="https://s3.eu-central-1.amazonaws.com/fintown.eu/reports-investors/occupancy/vihorev-group---projects-performance---september-24.pdf"/>
    <published>2024-10-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Findom Kazakhstan joins PeerBerry with 9% buyback-guaranteed loans - 2024-10-22T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Findom Kazakhstan joins PeerBerry with 9% buyback-guaranteed loans</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.607405+00:00</updated>
    <content>Findom, a loan originator from Kazakhstan, has begun offering short-term loans on PeerBerry, backed by a buyback and group guarantee. These loans provide an annual yield of 9% and will be available on the platform every business day.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/peerberry"/>
    <published>2024-10-22T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>HeavyFinance secures €10.5 million EIF guarantee to boost sustainable farming investments - 2024-10-24T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>HeavyFinance secures €10.5 million EIF guarantee to boost sustainable farming investments</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.607299+00:00</updated>
    <content>HeavyFinance secured a €10.5 million portfolio guarantee from the European Investment Fund (EIF) to fund agricultural loans. The platform offers a weighted average interest rate of over 13%, with default rates declining for four consecutive months.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/heavy-finance"/>
    <published>2024-10-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>InRento surpasses EUR 30 million loan portfolio with zero late payments in Q3 2024 - 2024-10-24T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>InRento surpasses EUR 30 million loan portfolio with zero late payments in Q3 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.607210+00:00</updated>
    <content>In Q3 2024, InRento’s loan portfolio surpassed EUR 30 million with zero late payments, while over 25,000 registered investors collectively earned EUR 500,000 in interest and capital gains. The platform financed EUR 3.56 million across 23 new opportunities, with an average investment return of 13.27%.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/inrento"/>
    <published>2024-10-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Robocash is introducing "One-Click" portfolio - 2024-10-25T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Robocash is introducing "One-Click" portfolio</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.607121+00:00</updated>
    <content>To reduce cash drag, investors now have the option to set up a One-Click portfolio, which functions like Auto Invest with the broadest settings. This feature diversifies investments across all available loans, providing a streamlined approach to maintaining an active portfolio.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/robocash"/>
    <published>2024-10-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Income adds loans from Sanfield Capital - 2024-11-01T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Income adds loans from Sanfield Capital</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.607032+00:00</updated>
    <content>Income has partnered with UK-based Sandfield Capital, opening new investment options in civil litigation funding. Offering annual returns up to 13.5% with maturities of up to 15 months, Sandfield Capital brings a €14.2 million loan originations track record and €11.8 million in active loans. All loans are fully insured, adding extra security, while litigation funding provides strong, uncorrelated returns for diversified portfolio growth.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/income"/>
    <published>2024-11-01T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>November 2024 Performance Update Is Now Available! - 2024-11-16T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>November 2024 Performance Update Is Now Available!</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.606943+00:00</updated>
    <content>We've released a new video showcasing the top-performing P2P lending platforms for November 2024. This video includes the latest news and insights that could affect your investments on these platforms.</content>
    <link href="https://p2pempire.com/en/comparison"/>
    <published>2024-11-16T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>LANDE achieves record growth and debt recovery milestones in October 2024 - 2024-11-18T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>LANDE achieves record growth and debt recovery milestones in October 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.606853+00:00</updated>
    <content>LANDE's October 2024 Platform Performance Report highlights notable achievements in agricultural financing. Farmers secured €993,051 in loans across 39 projects, with an average project size of €25,462. The platform welcomed 166 new investors, marking a record high, while investors earned €112,024 in interest, pushing total interest earnings to €2.11 million. Significant progress was made in debt recovery, with full repayments from two defaulted clients in Latvia. Additionally, €593,099 in principal was repaid during the month, bringing the all-time total to €11.02 million.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/lande"/>
    <published>2024-11-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>InRento launches first Buy-to-Let Project in Ireland with 9.5%-10% annual returns - 2024-12-01T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>InRento launches first Buy-to-Let Project in Ireland with 9.5%-10% annual returns</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.606764+00:00</updated>
    <content>InRento’s Parkview 33 in Renmore, Galway, offers investors 9.5%-10% annual returns. The property, a four-bedroom house, will be converted into two rental units in a high-demand area with minimal supply and average rents of €2,500/month.

Investors receive 8%-8.5% fixed interest, paid monthly, plus 1.5% capital growth, with a maximum 18-month loan term. Strong market fundamentals, including Ireland’s 5.3M population and 3.6% GDP growth forecast for 2025, ensure favorable conditions.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/inrento"/>
    <published>2024-12-01T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Ibancar increases interest rates to 12.5% - 2024-12-06T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Ibancar increases interest rates to 12.5%</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.606676+00:00</updated>
    <content>The Spanish loan originator Ibancar has raised its interest rates to an attractive 12.5% starting this December. This platform specializes in car loan investments, offering loan terms ranging from 24 to 36 months, making it an appealing option for investors seeking stable, mid-term opportunities.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/income"/>
    <published>2024-12-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>P2P Portfolio Update | November 2024 - 2024-12-07T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>P2P Portfolio Update | November 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.606587+00:00</updated>
    <content>Learn more about the recent changes in our P2P lending portfolio.</content>
    <link href="https://p2pempire.com/en/portfolio"/>
    <published>2024-12-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>TWINO faces diversification challenges while expanding in Poland - 2024-12-11T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>TWINO faces diversification challenges while expanding in Poland</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.606498+00:00</updated>
    <content>TWINO's investment portfolio is heavily concentrated, with 80% of loans originating from Poland, raising concerns about limited diversification for investors. Additionally, the platform has not provided updates on its plans for portfolio recovery in Asia, leaving questions about its risk mitigation strategy in that region.

In a related development, TWINO subsidiary Fincard Sp. z.o.o. has obtained a national payment institution license from the Polish Financial Supervision Authority, effective November 22. This license allows Fincard to offer services comparable to banks in payment processing and e-commerce, with the potential for expansion beyond Poland.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/twino"/>
    <published>2024-12-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Income Marketplace ensures investors security with Sandfield Capital loans - 2024-12-11T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Income Marketplace ensures investors security with Sandfield Capital loans</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.606406+00:00</updated>
    <content>Income has introduced Sandfield Capital as a Loan Originator, emphasizing that its financial status does not impact loan security. These litigation-focused bullet loans are fully insured by Accelerant Insurance Europe SA (A- rated), ensuring investor compensation in case of default.

The loans are structured through a bankruptcy-remote SPV (SFC4), isolating risks and maintaining uninterrupted repayments to investors. With law firms carefully vetted and comprehensive insurance in place, Income provides a robust dual-layered protection system, underscoring its commitment to transparency and investor safety.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/income"/>
    <published>2024-12-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>PeerBerry completes repayment of EUR 51.4 Million in war-affected loans - 2024-12-16T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>PeerBerry completes repayment of EUR 51.4 Million in war-affected loans</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.606301+00:00</updated>
    <content>PeerBerry, a leading P2P investment platform, has successfully processed the final repayment of loans impacted by the war in Ukraine. Since February 24, 2022, PeerBerry's business partners, Aventus Group and Gofingo Group, have repaid investors a total of EUR 51.4 million, including accrued interest.

This milestone makes PeerBerry the first and only investment platform in the market to fully meet its war-affected obligations, setting a benchmark for investor protection and resilience in times of crisis.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/peerberry"/>
    <published>2024-12-16T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Clickcash repayment pause extended - 2024-12-18T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Clickcash repayment pause extended</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.606213+00:00</updated>
    <content>ClickCash expects to secure funding by February 2025 to strengthen operations and resume direct repayments.

The pause on bridging repayments, initially set for August–November 2024, is extended through December 2024 and January 2025.

Repayments are targeted to resume in February 2025, depending on ClickCash’s funding status, either through direct payments or bridging by Income.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/income"/>
    <published>2024-12-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Holiday season update: Limited support and transfer delays ahead - 2024-12-19T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Holiday season update: Limited support and transfer delays ahead</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.606123+00:00</updated>
    <content>As the holiday season approaches, many platforms will operate with limited support, and banking holidays might cause delays in transfers to and from your P2P lending platforms. The P2P Empire team wishes you a joyful holiday season and a prosperous New Year!</content>
    <link href="https://p2pempire.com/en/newsfeed"/>
    <published>2024-12-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>UnaFinancial exits Sri Lanka - 2024-12-19T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>UnaFinancial exits Sri Lanka</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.606035+00:00</updated>
    <content>UnaFinancial is exiting Sri Lanka due to market changes. Its entity, Rapidlend (PVT), has repaid all loans to RC RIGA. Investors will receive principal and interest by December 23, 2024. With Sri Lankan loans comprising just 0.15% of the portfolio, platform operations remain unaffected.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/robocash"/>
    <published>2024-12-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>New investment deals: Up to 15% APY - 2024-12-20T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>New investment deals: Up to 15% APY</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.605946+00:00</updated>
    <content>Fresh opportunities are live: Moldovan deals offer up to 15% APY, Romanian deals provide 13.5% APY with terms under two years, and Latvian deals feature terms under one year.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/nectaro"/>
    <published>2024-12-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>CreditPrime Moldova achieves 50% loan portfolio growth in 2024 - 2024-12-20T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>CreditPrime Moldova achieves 50% loan portfolio growth in 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.605857+00:00</updated>
    <content>CreditPrime Moldova, a brand of Ecofinance, grew its loan portfolio by 50% in 2024 to MDL 139.8 million (€7.7 million). The company, Moldova’s first fully online microfinance institution, also diversified its funding sources, with Nectaro as a major partner and local bank contributions increasing fourfold.

Notable advancements included the launch of Instant Payments, enabling 24/7 financing, and strengthened risk management systems aligned with “Responsible Lending” regulations. With 91% of its portfolio classified as “Good Book” loans, CreditPrime is setting new standards in Moldova’s financial sector.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/nectaro"/>
    <published>2024-12-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Crowdpear launches mobile app - 2025-01-02T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Crowdpear launches mobile app</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.605768+00:00</updated>
    <content>Crowdpear has launched its mobile app, now available on Google Play and the App Store. Version 1.0.0 includes features already available on the desktop version: investing in property-backed loans, tracking investments, registering and verifying accounts, and managing documents. No additional features have been introduced in the app.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/crowdpear"/>
    <published>2025-01-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Indemo pauses Fast-Track to introduce new investments - 2025-01-03T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Indemo pauses Fast-Track to introduce new investments</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.605679+00:00</updated>
    <content>Indemo has temporarily paused its Fast Track program as the company prepares to launch a new offering: mortgage-backed loans with monthly interest payouts. This exciting development is expected to be released in Q1, bringing enhanced investment opportunities to the platform.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/indemo"/>
    <published>2025-01-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Fintown launches "The Seed" project: 15% APY secured by a 1st rank mortgage - 2025-01-04T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Fintown launches "The Seed" project: 15% APY secured by a 1st rank mortgage</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.605589+00:00</updated>
    <content>Fintown's The Seed Project launches on January 7, designed to provide a 15% annual return over a 24-month term with a €2 million investment target. The project progresses through land acquisition, construction preparation, and phased construction. Investment security is ensured with a 1st rank mortgage on the acquired land, with principal and interest paid at term-end.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/fintown"/>
    <published>2025-01-04T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Bondora extends the 6.75% rate on Go &amp; Grow portfolios - 2025-01-04T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Bondora extends the 6.75% rate on Go &amp; Grow portfolios</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.605499+00:00</updated>
    <content>Bondora has announced the extension of its 6.75% annual rate for Go &amp; Grow portfolios. This favorable rate will now be available until March 31, 2025.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/bondora"/>
    <published>2025-01-04T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Income reflects on a year of growth and trust in 2024 - 2025-01-08T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Income reflects on a year of growth and trust in 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.605405+00:00</updated>
    <content>Income celebrated significant milestones in 2024, with €59.5M loans listed and €57.4M invested. Investor confidence soared, driving a 77% growth in active portfolios, outpacing 2023’s 53%. Loan repayments totaled €50.5M, underscoring strong loan performance.

Newcomers like Ibancar and Sandfield joined, while top loan originators like Danarupiah attracted €27.9M in investments. High-value portfolios surged, with those over €100K growing 166.67%, reflecting deepening trust in Income’s secure, high-yield opportunities.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/income"/>
    <published>2025-01-08T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>PeerBerry announces interest rate adjustment starting January 15, 2025 - 2025-01-08T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>PeerBerry announces interest rate adjustment starting January 15, 2025</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.605297+00:00</updated>
    <content>From January 15, new investments on PeerBerry will feature adjusted interest rates, ranging from 8% to 9%. These changes apply only to new investments and will not impact existing ones.</content>
    <link href="https://c.trackmytarget.com/?a=wc58g4&amp;i=6ckbe7&amp;r=https%3A%2F%2Fpeerberry.com%2Fin-2024-peerberry-investors-funded-eur-586-11m-of-loans%2F"/>
    <published>2025-01-08T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Attractive Buy-to-Let Project in Poland - 2025-01-09T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Attractive Buy-to-Let Project in Poland</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.605206+00:00</updated>
    <content>InRento has launched the Zlota 71 investment project in Kalisz, Poland. This buy-to-let opportunity offers investors a fixed annual return of 11.5–12% and up to 30% in capital gains.

The project includes a five-storey complex with 160 apartments, 6 commercial spaces, and extensive parking. With a competitive 70% loan-to-value (LTV) ratio and a projected sales value of EUR 11.83M, Zlota 71 aims to deliver solid returns in one of Poland’s oldest cities.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/inrento"/>
    <published>2025-01-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Swiss Funds joins Iuvo: Czech Republic's first originator - 2025-01-09T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Swiss Funds joins Iuvo: Czech Republic's first originator</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.605108+00:00</updated>
    <content>Swiss Funds debuts on iuvo, offering investors 10% annual interest on EUR loans with maturities of 15 and 30 days and one-time payments at the end of the term. The loans are rated Score class D and include a 60-day buyback guarantee on the principal. Backed by Orka Group Services, Swiss Funds brings over 11 years of lending expertise from the Czech Republic and Iceland.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/iuvo-group"/>
    <published>2025-01-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Update on Fintown's rental revenue performance for 2024 - 2025-01-09T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Update on Fintown's rental revenue performance for 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.605017+00:00</updated>
    <content>Fintown has shared an update on the revenue and occupancy rates of its operational rental units. Honest Smichov generated €209,012 in total revenue, with an average daily rate of €94 and an occupancy rate of 92%. Honest Karlin, which began operations in May 2024, generated €241,476, with an average daily rate of €97 and an occupancy rate of 86%. Honest Ricany, Fintown’s flagship project launched in August 2024, has earned €379,903 so far, with an occupancy rate of 72% as of December 31.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/fintown"/>
    <published>2025-01-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Crowdpear achieves triple growth in 2024 and expands for 2025 - 2025-01-10T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Crowdpear achieves triple growth in 2024 and expands for 2025</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.604925+00:00</updated>
    <content>Crowdpear marked its third year with EUR 13.19M in property-backed loans funded in 2024—a threefold increase. Investors earned EUR 853,503 in interest. Since its launch, Crowdpear has funded 222 loans worth EUR 17.47M, with EUR 8.6M already repaid. Looking ahead, the platform targets growth through a new mobile app and expansion into a new EU market.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/crowdpear"/>
    <published>2025-01-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>P2P Portfolio Update | December 2024 - 2025-01-11T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>P2P Portfolio Update | December 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.604834+00:00</updated>
    <content>Learn more about the recent changes in our P2P lending portfolio.</content>
    <link href="https://p2pempire.com/en/portfolio"/>
    <published>2025-01-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Profitus launches a mobile app - 2025-01-15T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Profitus launches a mobile app</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.604745+00:00</updated>
    <content>The Lithuanian real estate platform Profitus launched a mobile app, improving the user experience for investors who will benefit from real-time notifications about important updates and news. The app includes all tools which are also available on the Desktop version.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/profitus"/>
    <published>2025-01-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>LANDE hits new highs in December 2024 - 2025-01-16T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>LANDE hits new highs in December 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.604657+00:00</updated>
    <content>LANDE closed 2024 with record-breaking performance: €1.41M in loans issued, €1.16M in repaid principal, and €153K in investor interest payouts. Romania led with €634K issued across 16 projects. December also welcomed 149 new investors and saw steady loan repayment progress. Plans for 2025 include platform upgrades and prioritization of land/machinery-backed loans to enhance stability. Cashback campaigns and referral bonuses continue into the new year!</content>
    <link href="/en/review/lande"/>
    <published>2025-01-16T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>January 2025 Performance Update Is Now Available! - 2025-01-20T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>January 2025 Performance Update Is Now Available!</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.604569+00:00</updated>
    <content>We've released a new video showcasing the top-performing P2P lending platforms for January 2025. This video includes the latest news and insights that could affect your investments on these platforms.</content>
    <link href="https://p2pempire.com/en/comparison"/>
    <published>2025-01-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Hoovi introduces "Collection Claim" loans backed by real estate - 2025-01-24T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Hoovi introduces "Collection Claim" loans backed by real estate</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.604478+00:00</updated>
    <content>Estonian SME lender Hoovi is launching a new loan category—Collection Claim Loans—featuring loans in recovery with predictable cash flows. Backed primarily by real estate collateral, these loans offer 13.5% p.a. returns, a 60-month maturity, and a 60 DPD buyback guarantee. While Hoovi retains collateral rights, investors benefit from Hoovi’s recovery-driven strategy and junior share logic. Update your auto-invest settings to explore this balanced, higher-return option.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/income"/>
    <published>2025-01-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>InRento wins Europe FinTech Award, expands across Europe - 2025-02-01T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>InRento wins Europe FinTech Award, expands across Europe</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.604383+00:00</updated>
    <content>InRento achieved a major milestone in 2024, winning the Best Investment Technology Platform at the Europe FinTech Awards. The company expanded into Poland and Ireland, introduced innovations like the Secondary Market Grand Sale, and reinforced its position in premium real estate investments. In 2025, InRento will focus on large-scale hotel projects, leveraging the sector’s post-COVID growth and stability to offer high-yield opportunities in strategic markets.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/inrento"/>
    <published>2025-02-01T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Reinvest24 faces multiple legal battles in Moldova - 2025-02-01T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Reinvest24 faces multiple legal battles in Moldova</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.604275+00:00</updated>
    <content>Reinvest24 is involved in nine ongoing legal proceedings in Moldova, covering bankruptcy cases, restructuring disputes, mortgage rights, and insolvency claims. Key hearings are set throughout 2025. Additionally, the company has engaged with Moldovan authorities, leading to criminal investigations into corruption. As Moldova progresses toward EU integration, judicial reforms are underway, including the vetting of Judge Valeriu Pedurari, whose rulings have impacted Reinvest24's cases.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/reinvest24"/>
    <published>2025-02-01T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Fintown CEO shares key updates in an exclusive interview - 2025-02-02T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Fintown CEO shares key updates in an exclusive interview</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.604185+00:00</updated>
    <content>P2P Empire interviewed Fintown CEO Maxim Vihorev, covering crucial topics like regulation, audited financials, the secondary market, and mortgage-backed investments. These insights provide a clearer picture of Fintown’s future direction. Watch the summary in our exclusive Fintown review.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/fintown"/>
    <published>2025-02-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Explore new platforms as loan availability tightens on top-rated P2P platforms - 2025-02-03T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Explore new platforms as loan availability tightens on top-rated P2P platforms</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.604095+00:00</updated>
    <content>Due to a decreased availability of loans on top-rated platforms featured on P2P Empire, opportunities to invest may be limited. For those looking to allocate funds in the P2P loan market, we recommend considering alternative platforms such as Fintown, Income Marketplace, Nectaro, Lonvest, or Indemo, which continue to offer viable investment options.</content>
    <link href="https://p2pempire.com/en/newsfeed"/>
    <published>2025-02-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Abele Finance now categorizes loans by borrower’s country - 2025-02-19T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Abele Finance now categorizes loans by borrower’s country</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.604004+00:00</updated>
    <content>Abele Finance will now classify loans based on the borrower's location rather than the loan originator’s country. Currently, all loans on Nectaro will be labeled as Cyprus-based, reflecting the actual end borrowers.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/nectaro"/>
    <published>2025-02-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Mintos offers loans with up to 17% interest rate - 2025-02-20T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Mintos offers loans with up to 17% interest rate</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.603915+00:00</updated>
    <content>Mintos has listed new loans with interest rates reaching up to 17% per annum. Loan terms vary from 18 days to 35 months, with lending companies rated between 5.9 and 7.3 on the Mintos Risk Score. Notable lenders include Nera Capital (up to 17.0%), Iute Group (up to 13.7%), and Eleving Group (up to 13.6%), providing diverse investment opportunities.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/mintos"/>
    <published>2025-02-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Nectaro enters Philippines with a high-yielding 14% investment opportunity - 2025-02-21T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Nectaro enters Philippines with a high-yielding 14% investment opportunity</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.603825+00:00</updated>
    <content>Abele Finance has partnered with Honey Loan, a Philippine-based lender under EcoFinance, to support market expansion. Investors can now access the fast-growing Southeast Asian market with loans offering a 14% interest rate and a 12-month term. Honey Loan has rapidly built a portfolio exceeding EUR 1 million in just six months. Loan volumes are currently limited, providing exclusive early investment opportunities.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/nectaro"/>
    <published>2025-02-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>LANDE reports record-breaking January 2025 performance - 2025-02-21T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>LANDE reports record-breaking January 2025 performance</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.603733+00:00</updated>
    <content>LANDE achieved another record month, with investors earning €178,270 in interest. The platform also saw a historic high in repaid principal, totaling €1.77M. As part of its risk strategy, LANDE is shifting focus from livestock and harvest-backed loans to land and machinery-backed projects. Most 90+ day delayed loans are now in enforcement, with bailiffs recovering collateral value. The 3% cashback campaign for investments on the primary market continues!</content>
    <link href="/en/review/lande"/>
    <published>2025-02-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>InRento launches fifth stage of its Zlot 71 investment in Poland - 2025-02-21T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>InRento launches fifth stage of its Zlot 71 investment in Poland</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.603640+00:00</updated>
    <content>InRento introduces the fifth stage of its buy-to-let project, Zlota 71, in Kalisz, Poland. Investors can earn a fixed annual interest of 11.5%–12%, plus up to 30% in capital gains if the property sells above projections. The project is valued at EUR 11.83M, with an expected profit of EUR 1.69M.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/inrento"/>
    <published>2025-02-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>EstateGuru struggles with loan recoveries in January - 2025-02-22T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>EstateGuru struggles with loan recoveries in January</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.603551+00:00</updated>
    <content>EstateGuru reported that just €400,000 had been recovered from problematic loans in January 2025, highlighting ongoing challenges in reducing defaults. While loans issued in 2023 and 2024 perform reasonably well, the platform still faces over €133 million in recovery efforts.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/estateguru"/>
    <published>2025-02-22T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Hoovi to buy back €2M in loans amid bank funding deal - 2025-02-27T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Hoovi to buy back €2M in loans amid bank funding deal</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.603459+00:00</updated>
    <content>Loan originator Hoovi is set to buy back approximately €2 million of its loans from the Income marketplace this week. The move aligns with ongoing talks to secure bank funding, which will lower Hoovi’s capital costs and strengthen its growth. As part of the deal, the bank will invest in Hoovi’s loans, reinforcing confidence in its lending model. Hoovi will continue offering new investment opportunities on Income.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/income"/>
    <published>2025-02-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Growth in Mexican loan portfolio - 2025-03-01T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Growth in Mexican loan portfolio</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.603351+00:00</updated>
    <content>Lonvest shares performance data on its Mexican lending portfolio since July 2024. CliCredito’s CEO reveals the lender has disbursed $2.4 million in loans since launch, with consistent monthly growth. Currently, investors on Lonvest hold a €885,000 stake in these loans. The figures highlight expanding opportunities in Mexico’s credit market.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/lonvest"/>
    <published>2025-03-01T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Go &amp; Grow updates: Simplified returns at 6% p.a. - 2025-03-01T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Go &amp; Grow updates: Simplified returns at 6% p.a.</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.603263+00:00</updated>
    <content>Starting 1 April 2025, Go &amp; Grow investors will enjoy a streamlined experience with a single return rate of up to 6%* p.a. No more monthly limits or varying rates—just straightforward daily returns. This change follows positive investor feedback after the removal of monthly limits in September 2024.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/bondora"/>
    <published>2025-03-01T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Fintown introduces a new investment - Kolovraty  | Secured with a 1st rank mortgage - 2025-03-03T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Fintown introduces a new investment - Kolovraty  | Secured with a 1st rank mortgage</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.603176+00:00</updated>
    <content>Fintown has launched Development - Kolovraty - LOT 1, offering investors 11% p.a. returns with 1st rank mortgage security. This 24-month investment ensures priority repayment, real estate collateral, and legal protection for lower risk and stable returns. Interest is paid at the end of the term.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/fintown"/>
    <published>2025-03-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Wandoo Finance publishes its 2024 investor report - 2025-03-09T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Wandoo Finance publishes its 2024 investor report</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.603087+00:00</updated>
    <content>Iveta Bruvele returns as CEO, and the company expands into Peru. Q4 revenue hit €12.3M (+26% QoQ), with EBITDA surging to €4.5M (+83%). Full-year revenue reached €35.6M (+74% YoY), and net profit soared to €2M (+400%). Despite rapid growth, risk remains controlled with a 10.0% loss rate. An audited report will be available by July 2025.</content>
    <link href="https://swaper.com/en/assets/reports/swaper_investor_report_q4_2024.pdf"/>
    <published>2025-03-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Successful completion of second "Azalijų 1" auction - 2025-03-13T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Successful completion of second "Azalijų 1" auction</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.602998+00:00</updated>
    <content>The second auction for the "Azalijų 1" project (loan IDs 31, 36, 39, 47) has been successfully completed. The auction winner must transfer the payment within 30 days to the bankruptcy administrator, who will distribute the funds to creditors. Crowdpear investors have priority in loan recovery. All invested funds and accrued interest are expected to be paid to investors in April-May 2024.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/crowdpear"/>
    <published>2025-03-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Crowdpear reports first profitable year in 2024 - 2025-03-13T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Crowdpear reports first profitable year in 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.602907+00:00</updated>
    <content>Crowdfunding platform Crowdpear achieved a net profit of EUR 152,126 in 2024, marking a turnaround from its EUR 38,137 net loss in 2023. While financial reports of ECSP license holders must be audited and submitted to state authorities, publishing them online is not mandatory. Crowdpear plans to make its financial statements accessible on its website in the future. Official data will appear on public registries once updated.</content>
    <link href="https://rekvizitai.vz.lt/en/company/crowdpear/"/>
    <published>2025-03-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Debitum Investments disputes the information presented on P2P Empire, highlighting three key points - 2025-03-13T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Debitum Investments disputes the information presented on P2P Empire, highlighting three key points</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.602819+00:00</updated>
    <content>Misrepresentation of Website Data &amp; War-Affected Loans – The statistics referenced are outdated, despite prior clarifications. Debitum states that all website data is now updated and includes timestamps. The claim that war-affected loans are hidden is incorrect, as the restructuring of MotorFinance investments due to the war is clearly disclosed. These loans are not defaulted or late but legally restructured, with regular investor updates provided.

Incorrect Information on DN Funding Alpha &amp; Chain Finance Investments – The claim that Debitum stated Chain Finance loans were fully repaid is inaccurate. These loans were restructured under SIA DN Funding Alpha, and this was disclosed. Debitum acknowledges the need for an additional disclaimer directing investors to DN Funding Alpha.

Clarification on DEB Token – Debitum Investments confirms that it has no connection to the 2017 ICO or the DEB Token, as verified by the Bank of Latvia and auditor Grant Thornton. The company has never used ICO funds or held liabilities related to it.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/debitum-network"/>
    <published>2025-03-13T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Nectaro launches boost campaign with cashback rewards - 2025-03-14T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Nectaro launches boost campaign with cashback rewards</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.602730+00:00</updated>
    <content>Nectaro’s new Boost Campaign offers investors extra rewards! By investing in financial instruments marked with the “Boost” flag, you’ll receive a cashback bonus—up to €1,000 per month. Eligible investments are calculated monthly, with bonuses credited by the 15th of the following month. Even Auto Invest strategies qualify. Each investment gets a one-time bonus, so act fast!</content>
    <link href="/en/review/nectaro"/>
    <published>2025-03-14T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Income partners with Virtus Lending - 2025-03-14T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Income partners with Virtus Lending</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.602643+00:00</updated>
    <content>Income has teamed up with Virtus Lending, a Kosovo-based financial institution specializing in leasing and consumer loans. With a €8.2M loan portfolio and low NPL (non-performing loans) rates, Virtus offers secured loans with yields of up to 10-12% annually. Investors can access car and consumer loans with buyback obligations and Junior Shares of 24-27%, ensuring strong protection.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/income"/>
    <published>2025-03-14T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>New investment opportunity from the Czech Republic - 2025-03-19T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>New investment opportunity from the Czech Republic</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.602555+00:00</updated>
    <content>VIAINVEST is introducing securities backed by loans from Via SMS s.r.o. in the Czech Republic. These offer up to 13.2% annual interest with an 18-month maturity. Investors using predefined Auto-invest strategies don’t need to take action. Custom strategy users should check their maturity filters. Manual investors can find them in the investment offer list.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/viainvest"/>
    <published>2025-03-19T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Indemo offers €30 Bonus for first-time investors - 2025-03-21T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Indemo offers €30 Bonus for first-time investors</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.602465+00:00</updated>
    <content>Indemo is offering a €30 bonus for first-time investors. From March 20 to April 19, 2025, users making their first investment of at least €10 will receive an additional €30. The bonus is automatically credited to the investor account.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/indemo"/>
    <published>2025-03-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>EstateGuru erzielt im Februar nur 0,37 Mio. € – 59 % des Portfolios in Verzug - 2025-03-22T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>EstateGuru erzielt im Februar nur 0,37 Mio. € – 59 % des Portfolios in Verzug</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.602355+00:00</updated>
    <content>EstateGuru konnte im Februar 2025 lediglich 0,37 Millionen Euro zurückgewinnen – ein weiteres Zeichen für die anhaltenden Schwierigkeiten bei der Rückholung von ausgefallenen, besicherten Krediten. Derzeit sind 132,8 Millionen Euro Anlegerkapital in ausgefallenen Krediten gebunden, was 59 % des gesamten ausstehenden Kreditportfolios entspricht. Dieses schrumpft von Monat zu Monat weiter.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/estateguru"/>
    <published>2025-03-22T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>EstateGuru recovers just €0.37M in February as defaults hit 59% - 2025-03-22T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>EstateGuru recovers just €0.37M in February as defaults hit 59%</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.602266+00:00</updated>
    <content>EstateGuru recovered only €0.37 million in February 2025, highlighting its ongoing struggle to recover funds from defaulted mortgage-backed loans. Currently, €132.8 million of investors' capital is tied up in defaults — representing 59% of the platform’s outstanding portfolio, which continues to shrink month over month.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/estateguru"/>
    <published>2025-03-22T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Afranga secures EU crowdfunding license, launches regulated platform with 16% returns - 2025-03-25T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Afranga secures EU crowdfunding license, launches regulated platform with 16% returns</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.602142+00:00</updated>
    <content>Afranga is now licensed under the EU Crowdfunding Regulation via Bulgaria’s Financial Supervision Commission. Investors benefit from enhanced transparency, stronger fund protection, business loan offerings, and improved risk controls. All users must register a new account to continue investing. Early adopters gain access to StikCredit loans with up to 16% returns. Existing stikcredit.eu portfolios will be repaid before platform closure.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/afranga"/>
    <published>2025-03-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Fintown introduces the Early Exit 2.0 Program - 2025-03-25T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Fintown introduces the Early Exit 2.0 Program</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.602052+00:00</updated>
    <content>Fintown's Early Exit 2.0 offers investors a way to exit projects before maturity, subject to conditions. Exits are allowed after a 6-month lock-in, with a 10% fee if done before 12 months. Exiting over 50% of the principal incurs an added 10% fee. Requests are processed within 30 days and allowed every 90 days. Accrued interest is deducted upon exit.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/fintown"/>
    <published>2025-03-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>How to avoid losing money on secondary market purchases - 2025-03-29T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>How to avoid losing money on secondary market purchases</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.601964+00:00</updated>
    <content>Investors are struggling with cash drag due to limited loan supply. The auto invest features don't always work, so many turn to the secondary market, where most loans are listed at a premium. These added costs can hurt returns, especially on short-term loans. A new guide explains how these premiums affect IRR and offers tips on securing better deals.</content>
    <link href="https://p2pempire.com/en/esketit-secondary-market-premium"/>
    <published>2025-03-29T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Vihorev group begins Park Vista project with site demolition - 2025-04-02T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Vihorev group begins Park Vista project with site demolition</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.601870+00:00</updated>
    <content>Vihorev Group has taken the first visible step in developing its Park Vista residential community by demolishing the old on-site building. A short video captures the transformation, showing the original structure being cleared to make way for the future development.</content>
    <link href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=HoKO2r_PaUw"/>
    <published>2025-04-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Robocash investors earn €674K in March with €20M invested - 2025-04-02T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Robocash investors earn €674K in March with €20M invested</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.601782+00:00</updated>
    <content>In March 2025, Robocash attracted 293 new investors. Active investors earned a total of €674,000 in interest, while over €20 million was invested through the platform, continuing Robocash’s track record of stable returns.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/robocash"/>
    <published>2025-04-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>PeerBerry reaches record €117.45M portfolio in May - 2025-04-02T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>PeerBerry reaches record €117.45M portfolio in May</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.601685+00:00</updated>
    <content>In March 2025, PeerBerry investors funded €33.62M in loans—up nearly 10% from February—and earned €944,538 in interest. Total interest paid since launch reached €41.97M. The platform’s portfolio hit an all-time high of €117.45M. PeerBerry welcomed 1,522 new investors, bringing its verified user base to over 99,500. Since inception, nearly €2.99B in loans have been funded.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/peerberry"/>
    <published>2025-04-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Crowdpear hits €23M milestone and expands to Romania - 2025-04-02T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Crowdpear hits €23M milestone and expands to Romania</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.601595+00:00</updated>
    <content>In March 2025, Crowdpear investors funded 11 property-backed loans worth €1.15M, pushing the platform's total funded volume above €23M. Investors received €72,219 in interest, bringing total payouts to over €1.26M. Eight loans totaling €578K were repaid. Over half of all loans issued have now been repaid. Crowdpear also launched Romanian real estate investments to broaden diversification options.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/crowdpear"/>
    <published>2025-04-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Debitum updates status of Ukrainian portfolio to "restructured" - 2025-04-02T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Debitum updates status of Ukrainian portfolio to "restructured"</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.601506+00:00</updated>
    <content>Debitum has corrected the status of its suspended Ukrainian portfolio from Chain Finance, changing it from "repaid" to "restructured." A disclaimer has been added to explain the ongoing restructuring process. This update aims to improve transparency for investors assessing Debitum’s loan book.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/debitum-network"/>
    <published>2025-04-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>PrimeLoans launches on PeerBerry with 9% interest rates - 2025-04-09T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>PrimeLoans launches on PeerBerry with 9% interest rates</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.601413+00:00</updated>
    <content>South African lender PrimeLoans has joined the PeerBerry platform, offering short-term loans with a 9% annual return. Backed by a buyback guarantee and Aventus Group support, these loans are available daily. PrimeLoans, established in 2024, currently manages a €0.5M portfolio. Investors can include PrimeLoans in their Auto Invest settings if aligned with their strategy.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/peerberry"/>
    <published>2025-04-09T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>InRento's audited financials for 2024: Revenue up 52%, profit down on higher costs - 2025-04-11T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>InRento's audited financials for 2024: Revenue up 52%, profit down on higher costs</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.601308+00:00</updated>
    <content>Sales rose to €1.16M, but net profit slipped to €63K as admin costs more than doubled. Cash fell sharply, while receivables and fixed assets grew—signaling expansion. InRento remains profitable, with stronger equity and reduced retained losses. The full audited report is available for download in the Statistics section of our InRento review.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/inrento"/>
    <published>2025-04-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>PeerBerry hits 100,000 investors, manages €116M without losses - 2025-04-11T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>PeerBerry hits 100,000 investors, manages €116M without losses</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.601220+00:00</updated>
    <content>PeerBerry has reached a milestone of 100,000 investors. The platform now oversees more than €116 million in assets under management, with no reported losses of investor capital to date.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/peerberry"/>
    <published>2025-04-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>EstateGuru sees €1.45M rise in recovery funds, portfolio shrinks - 2025-04-11T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>EstateGuru sees €1.45M rise in recovery funds, portfolio shrinks</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.601132+00:00</updated>
    <content>In April, EstateGuru’s recovery funds in active markets grew by €1.45 million, reaching €133.27 million. Meanwhile, the platform's outstanding portfolio dropped by 1.34%, indicating a modest contraction in active lending activity.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/estateguru"/>
    <published>2025-04-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>InRento doubles investment volume to €43M, expands internationally with strong Q1 results - 2025-04-10T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>InRento doubles investment volume to €43M, expands internationally with strong Q1 results</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.601044+00:00</updated>
    <content>In just over a year, InRento grew its total funded volume from €20M to over €43M, signaling strong investor trust. Q1 2025 saw €5.56M financed, 16 new projects, and zero late loans. With expansion into Poland and Ireland and a new Warsaw office, over half of 2025’s deals are expected to be international.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/inrento"/>
    <published>2025-04-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>LANDE 2024 report: Growth, profitability, and strong returns - 2025-04-14T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>LANDE 2024 report: Growth, profitability, and strong returns</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.600956+00:00</updated>
    <content>LANDE reported a 22% revenue increase in 2024, reaching €1.96M, and returned to profitability with €166.9K net profit. Operating costs were reduced by €267K. €12.57M in loans were issued across Latvia, Romania, and Lithuania, with an average investor return of 11%. 93% of the portfolio is secured by land or machinery. Default rate remained low at 2.22%, underlining LANDE’s strong risk management.</content>
    <link href="https://7187705.fs1.hubspotusercontent-na1.net/hubfs/7187705/LANDE_Operational_Report_2024_EN.pdf"/>
    <published>2025-04-14T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Autoinvest ends on stikcredit.eu in 7 days - 2025-04-14T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Autoinvest ends on stikcredit.eu in 7 days</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.600866+00:00</updated>
    <content>Stikcredit.eu will disable its autoinvest feature in 7 days as the legacy platform is phased out. While no new loans are available, users can still access their accounts until all investments are repaid. Repaid and uninvested funds can be withdrawn and moved to Afranga over time.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/afranga"/>
    <published>2025-04-14T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Nectaro reports €5.56M in outstanding portfolio with zero loans in recovery - 2025-04-14T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Nectaro reports €5.56M in outstanding portfolio with zero loans in recovery</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.600777+00:00</updated>
    <content>Nectaro announces an outstanding current portfolio of €5,559,331. All loans are secured by a 60-day buyback guarantee, and none are currently in recovery. This performance places Nectaro among the top-performing platforms in the market.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/nectaro"/>
    <published>2025-04-14T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>€50 Bonus for New Investors + 1% Cashback on Nectaro Deals - 2025-04-16T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>€50 Bonus for New Investors + 1% Cashback on Nectaro Deals</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.600688+00:00</updated>
    <content>From April 15–30, 2025, new investors who sign up and invest €1,000+ within 30 days get a €50 bonus. This stacks with the 1% Cashback from the Newbies Campaign. Look out for “Boost” deals from Nectaro (Moldova) offering an extra 1% Cashback on eligible investments.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/nectaro"/>
    <published>2025-04-16T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>MojoCapital Launches €1M Loan Backed by Founders, Offers 10% Return - 2025-04-16T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>MojoCapital Launches €1M Loan Backed by Founders, Offers 10% Return</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.600599+00:00</updated>
    <content>MojoCapital, active on the platform since June 2024, has funded €2M in loans and paid over €100K in interest. Now, it’s issuing a €1M loan to a partner to meet reserve requirements. Initially funded by founders, the loan offers a 10% annual return and added security as funds remain internal. Linked to a high-ROI FinTech project, the loan goes live after April 21 and joins the Diversified strategy.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/esketit"/>
    <published>2025-04-16T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Bondora’s net profit drops 64% despite revenue growth in 2024 - 2025-04-16T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Bondora’s net profit drops 64% despite revenue growth in 2024</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.600511+00:00</updated>
    <content>Bondora Group reported €1.2M net profit for 2024, down 64% year-on-year, despite an annual revenue increase of 19% to €52.6M. Loan issuance rose 30% to €262M, and investment volume hit €567M. While borrower and investor numbers grew, return on equity fell to 6% from 17% in 2023. The group continued expanding across Europe and advanced its banking license preparations.</content>
    <link href="https://help.bondora.com/hc/en-us/article_attachments/25898471904914"/>
    <published>2025-04-16T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Estateguru Posts €5.5M in Loans for March, Default Rate Hits 60% - 2025-04-18T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Estateguru Posts €5.5M in Loans for March, Default Rate Hits 60%</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.600420+00:00</updated>
    <content>In March, Estateguru issued €5.5M in loans, led by Estonia (€2.63M) and Latvia (€1.42M). However, only €1M was recovered from defaulted loans. Total defaults now stand at €134.5M—representing a striking 60% of the portfolio. The defaulted portion continued to rise month-over-month.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/estateguru"/>
    <published>2025-04-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Easter Holiday Notice: Possible Delays in Transfers - 2025-04-18T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Easter Holiday Notice: Possible Delays in Transfers</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.600313+00:00</updated>
    <content>April 21 (Monday) is a public holiday in many European countries. While platforms remain accessible, expect potential delays in money transfers. Client Support will respond to inquiries received during the Easter break on the next business day.</content>
    <link href="https://p2pempire.com/en/newsfeed"/>
    <published>2025-04-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>P2P Lending Platforms Performance Update - April 2025 - 2025-04-20T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>P2P Lending Platforms Performance Update - April 2025</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.600224+00:00</updated>
    <content>In this month’s update, we cover the latest data on recoveries, defaults, and loan volumes across major players like Mintos, PeerBerry, EstateGuru, and more. Watch the full video to see where your money might be working—or at risk.</content>
    <link href="https://youtu.be/dpP75Y5uvog"/>
    <published>2025-04-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Exclusive Interview With The CEO &amp; Founder Svetlin Sabev - 2025-04-21T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Exclusive Interview With The CEO &amp; Founder Svetlin Sabev</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.600135+00:00</updated>
    <content>Afranga is now a regulated crowdfunding platform with direct loan agreements, asset-backed lending, and no buyback guarantee. Funds are held in segregated LemonWay wallets, and investor protections have improved. Auto Invest, a Secondary Market, and EU expansion are coming soon. Want the full picture? CEO Svetlin Sabev breaks it all down in our exclusive Afranga interview – watch it in our latest review.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/afranga"/>
    <published>2025-04-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Virtus Lending Q1 Net Profit Triples YoY, Eyes Expansion into Car Loans - 2025-04-23T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Virtus Lending Q1 Net Profit Triples YoY, Eyes Expansion into Car Loans</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.600046+00:00</updated>
    <content>Virtus Lending posted a strong Q1 2025, with operating income up 68% YoY to €481K and net profit tripling to €116K. Gross margin hit 68%. Assets totaled €10.6M, with a €9M loan portfolio. Since joining the Income platform, the firm has raised over €1M. Virtus now plans to launch collateralized car loans, offering shorter terms and low default rates.</content>
    <link href="https://getincome.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2025/04/Virtus_Lending_Q1_2025.pdf"/>
    <published>2025-04-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>LANDE March 2025: €935K Principal Returned, Debt Collection Intensifies - 2025-04-24T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>LANDE March 2025: €935K Principal Returned, Debt Collection Intensifies</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.599956+00:00</updated>
    <content>In March, LANDE investors received €935,024 in principal repayments, pushing the all-time total to €16.65M. Most overdue loans (90+ days) are now in enforcement, with bailiffs involved in asset recovery. The platform continues shifting from livestock and harvest-backed loans to those secured by land or machinery to improve loan performance and reduce default risk.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/lande"/>
    <published>2025-04-24T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>TWINO Appoints 4th CEO in 5 Years as Henšelis Steps Down - 2025-04-25T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>TWINO Appoints 4th CEO in 5 Years as Henšelis Steps Down</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.599865+00:00</updated>
    <content>TWINO CEO Helvijs Henšelis has resigned, marking the fourth leadership change in five years. Nauris Bloks, a former Supervisory Board member and ex-DelfinGroup executive, steps in as Interim CEO effective April 24. Bloks brings fintech and digital product expertise, aiming to guide a stable transition and strengthen the platform amid continued strategic shifts.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/twino"/>
    <published>2025-04-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>PeerBerry 2024: Profit Up 32%, Assets Up 41% - 2025-05-02T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>PeerBerry 2024: Profit Up 32%, Assets Up 41%</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.599777+00:00</updated>
    <content>PeerBerry reported a net profit of €579K in 2024, a 32% increase from the previous year. Revenue rose to €2.2M (+17%), while total assets jumped 41% to €15.4M.

The platform boosted short-term financial assets to €10.3M and made a €500K long-term investment, despite a slight drop in cash. Short-term liabilities rose to €13.45M, reflecting increased investor activity.

PeerBerry remains profitable, lean, and continues to scale efficiently.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/peerberry"/>
    <published>2025-05-02T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Income Marketplace Finances €6.2M in April 2025 - 2025-05-06T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Income Marketplace Finances €6.2M in April 2025</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.599689+00:00</updated>
    <content>Income Marketplace funded €6.19M in loans in April 2025, bringing total all-time funding to €162.7M. The average interest rate for April loans was 12.23%, while the platform’s historical average return stands at 13.65%. 91 new investors joined last month, raising the total to 9,496 active users.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/income"/>
    <published>2025-05-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Capitalia Posts €28K Profit in Q1 2025 Amid €5.3M in New Loans - 2025-05-06T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Capitalia Posts €28K Profit in Q1 2025 Amid €5.3M in New Loans</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.599599+00:00</updated>
    <content>Capitalia Investment Holding reported €28K profit and €474K revenue in Q1 2025, driven by €5.3M in business funding. Return on equity rose to 17.5%, with strong liquidity and bond covenant coverage at 38% of assets.</content>
    <link href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1CBVq3-Z05_p5H1vNsE1EMmvRF_cDvTwj/view?usp=sharing"/>
    <published>2025-05-06T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Mintos to Charge 0.29% Annual Fee on New Custom Loans Portfolios from 16 May 2025 - 2025-05-07T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Mintos to Charge 0.29% Annual Fee on New Custom Loans Portfolios from 16 May 2025</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.599510+00:00</updated>
    <content>Starting 16 May 2025, Mintos will charge a 0.29% yearly fee on new investments via Custom Loans portfolios. The fee is calculated daily and deducted monthly from available balances. Existing portfolios and manual investments are unaffected. Mintos says the change will fund platform upgrades, recovery management, and new products—aiming to boost long-term investor value and service quality.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/mintos"/>
    <published>2025-05-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Income Company OÜ Reports 77% Growth in Investments Amid Operational Reorganization - 2025-05-07T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Income Company OÜ Reports 77% Growth in Investments Amid Operational Reorganization</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.599418+00:00</updated>
    <content>In 2024, Income Company OÜ saw outstanding investments surge to €19.1M (+77% YoY) and active investors rise to 4,613. The platform onboarded its first institutional investor, despite a net loss of €613K due to higher customer acquisition and depreciation costs. Revenue grew 17.5% to €507K. The company plans a new funding round in 2025 to reach profitability and expand investable loan volumes.</content>
    <link href="https://getincome.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/2024-Aruanne_16014116_ENG.pdf"/>
    <published>2025-05-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>ITF Group AD Reports 60% Revenue Growth in 2024 Audited Results - 2025-05-07T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>ITF Group AD Reports 60% Revenue Growth in 2024 Audited Results</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.599311+00:00</updated>
    <content>ITF Group AD posted EUR 13.5M in revenue for 2024, up 60% YoY. Net profit rose 74% to EUR 1.8M, with a 14% net margin. Assets hit EUR 20M, equity EUR 6.9M. The net loan portfolio expanded to EUR 15.6M. Since joining the Income platform, investors have funded over EUR 38.8M in ITF loans, earning EUR 1M+.</content>
    <link href="https://getincome.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2025/05/ITF-Group-audited-consolidated-FS_2024.pdf"/>
    <published>2025-05-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>P2P Portfolio Update | April 2025 - 2025-05-10T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>P2P Portfolio Update | April 2025</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.599221+00:00</updated>
    <content>Learn more about the recent changes in our P2P lending portfolio.</content>
    <link href="https://p2pempire.com/en/portfolio"/>
    <published>2025-05-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Triple Dragon Commits to Repayment by May 20 Amid Missed Payments - 2025-05-10T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Triple Dragon Commits to Repayment by May 20 Amid Missed Payments</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.599130+00:00</updated>
    <content>Triple Dragon has pledged to repay €125,469.22 — covering overdue principal, interest, and late fees — by May 20. The company missed repayments starting April 21, prompting oversight from Debitum’s credit committee. Remedial steps have been agreed upon, with a follow-up meeting set for May 14. Debitum will assess Triple Dragon’s Trust Score and future platform eligibility in the coming weeks.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/debitum-network"/>
    <published>2025-05-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Bondora's Loan Portfolio Heavily Backed by Retail Investors - 2025-05-14T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Bondora's Loan Portfolio Heavily Backed by Retail Investors</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.599041+00:00</updated>
    <content>As of December 31, 2024, Bondora reported €600M in active loan principals and €567M in total investor balances. This means retail investors are funding 94.5% of the loan portfolio, highlighting Bondora’s reliance on them to sustain its lending operations—a factor that may raise risk concerns for investors.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/bondora"/>
    <published>2025-05-14T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>InSoil Finance Sees Strong April Activity Amid Ongoing Loan Repayments - 2025-05-14T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>InSoil Finance Sees Strong April Activity Amid Ongoing Loan Repayments</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.598953+00:00</updated>
    <content>In April 2025, InSoil Finance facilitated €2.92M in new investments and financed €2.98M across 62 farmer loans. Total lending reached €79.2M. Investors received €1.03M in repayments, with 79.4% of loans on schedule. However, €10.13M of loans are over 90 days late. May repayments are forecasted at €620K, while 83.4% of delayed payments were resolved last month.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/insoil-finance"/>
    <published>2025-05-14T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>InRento Launches First Buy-to-Let in Italy with 12% Yield Target - 2025-05-15T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>InRento Launches First Buy-to-Let in Italy with 12% Yield Target</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.598863+00:00</updated>
    <content>InRento debuts in Italy with a buy-to-let project in Catania, Sicily. The 1,460 m² building will be converted into a 4-star hotel with 35 rooms. Investors receive 9.25–10.5% annual interest plus 1.5% capital gain, totaling up to 12% return. Backed by permits, a EUR 1.7M valuation, and strong local tourism, the project runs for up to 24 months.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/inrento"/>
    <published>2025-05-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Vihorev Group Defies Seasonal Slowdown With Strong Q1 Performance - 2025-05-15T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Vihorev Group Defies Seasonal Slowdown With Strong Q1 Performance</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.598774+00:00</updated>
    <content>Despite Q1’s low-season challenges, Vihorev Group maintained high occupancy across all sites, with Ricany reaching a stabilized 80%. Revenue remained solid, with only a minor March dip due to Easter timing. Guest satisfaction stayed high with a 9.0 average rating. Tenant-driven upgrades—including new beds in Smíchov and full AC in Karlín—boosted comfort, positioning all properties for continued growth in 2025.</content>
    <link href="https://s3.eu-central-1.amazonaws.com/fintown.eu/reports-investors/projects_performance/vihorev-group---rental-projects-performance---q1-2025.pdf"/>
    <published>2025-05-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Income Resumes Bridging with €5,000 Repayment for ClickCash - 2025-05-18T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Income Resumes Bridging with €5,000 Repayment for ClickCash</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.598684+00:00</updated>
    <content>Income has resumed bridging repayments for ClickCash, initiating a €5,000 payment—the first since July 2024. This move follows ongoing delays in ClickCash’s funding efforts. While the company continues its relaunch, Income will reassess further bridging monthly. The goal remains full investor recovery, with transparency and investor protection at the core of each decision.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/income"/>
    <published>2025-05-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Income Launches Crowdfunding on SeedBlink, Targets Expansion and Investor Liquidity - 2025-05-23T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Income Launches Crowdfunding on SeedBlink, Targets Expansion and Investor Liquidity</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.598595+00:00</updated>
    <content>Private debt platform Income has opened a €250K crowdfunding round on SeedBlink, inviting retail investors to co-own its next phase. Backed by €540K from a key shareholder, the funds will support expansion into Mexico and the Philippines, tech upgrades, and a new secondary market for early exits. Income has over €160M in loan investments and aims for €60M AUM by 2026.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/income"/>
    <published>2025-05-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>TWINO CEO Promises Transparency Amid Rental Issues and Market Challenges - 2025-05-23T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>TWINO CEO Promises Transparency Amid Rental Issues and Market Challenges</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.598505+00:00</updated>
    <content>TWINO’s new CEO, Nauris Bloks, pledges clearer investor communication through monthly updates. The platform is addressing delays in Rental updates, promising a full report next week. TWINO also expands into shorter-term asset-backed securities. On Russia, Vietnam, and the Philippines, the CEO acknowledges slow repayments and partial losses but commits to recovery efforts and honoring guarantees where applicable.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/twino"/>
    <published>2025-05-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Esketit Closes &lt;1% of Accounts After Risk Policy Review, Full Repayment Within 10 Days - 2025-05-23T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Esketit Closes &lt;1% of Accounts After Risk Policy Review, Full Repayment Within 10 Days</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.598412+00:00</updated>
    <content>Esketit is terminating less than 1% of investor accounts following a 5-year review of its internal and AML risk policies. Affected users will receive full repayment within 10 days of notification, or sooner if requested. The platform cites multiple risk-related factors behind the decisions, which cannot be publicly detailed. Esketit acknowledges user concerns but confirms the decisions are final and carefully considered.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/esketit"/>
    <published>2025-05-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Afranga Adds Lendivo as New Loan Originator - 2025-05-28T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Afranga Adds Lendivo as New Loan Originator</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.598303+00:00</updated>
    <content>Afranga has partnered with Bulgarian lender Lendivo, co-developed by the team behind Stikcredit. Investors can now access more loans, enhance portfolio diversification, and earn up to 16% p.a. in returns. Lendivo loans meet Afranga’s due diligence standards and are available exclusively on the platform.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/afranga"/>
    <published>2025-05-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Philippines SEC Revokes Digido License; Company Appeals Decision - 2025-05-28T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Philippines SEC Revokes Digido License; Company Appeals Decision</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.598213+00:00</updated>
    <content>The Philippine SEC revoked Digido Finance Corp.'s license over 2021 marketing booths deemed as permanent offices. Digido disputes the claim and filed a motion for reconsideration. Operations continue during the appeal. Existing loans remain active, with investor payouts and interest unaffected. Robocash reassures investors of its Buyback guarantee and ongoing obligations fulfillment.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/robocash"/>
    <published>2025-05-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Insoil Finance Introduces Inactivity Fee for Unclaimed Payments - 2025-06-03T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Insoil Finance Introduces Inactivity Fee for Unclaimed Payments</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.598123+00:00</updated>
    <content>Insoil Finance has added an Inactivity Fee (Clause 4.3) for investors who fail to provide valid account details. If payments can’t be distributed due to missing account info, the fee will apply from the date funds are received and continue until proper details are shared. This may reduce the total amount investors are entitled to receive.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/insoil-finance"/>
    <published>2025-06-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Nectaro Boosts Auto-Invest Returns by 0.29% Starting June 2 - 2025-06-03T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Nectaro Boosts Auto-Invest Returns by 0.29% Starting June 2</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.598031+00:00</updated>
    <content>From June 2, 2025, Nectaro users will earn an extra 0.29% annually on new Auto-Invest investments. The bonus interest is calculated daily and paid with standard payouts. The boost applies to all strategies launched while the offer is active and lasts until the investments mature or are repaid.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/nectaro"/>
    <published>2025-06-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>LANDE Reports €196K Profit in 2024 Amid Expansion and Regulatory Milestone - 2025-06-04T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>LANDE Reports €196K Profit in 2024 Amid Expansion and Regulatory Milestone</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.597943+00:00</updated>
    <content>LANDE Platform SIA closed 2024 with a €196,086 profit, reversing the previous year's loss. Revenue rose to nearly €2M, reflecting growing investor trust. Shareholder equity increased to €626K. The platform secured an ECSP license from the Bank of Latvia and plans to enter the Polish market. Over €30M in total funding has been issued since launch, with over 8,000 investors onboard—mainly from Germany and Central Europe.</content>
    <link href="https://lande.finance/docs/annual-report-2024.pdf"/>
    <published>2025-06-04T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>PeerBerry Investment Grows 12% in May as Long-Term Loan Supply Increases - 2025-06-04T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>PeerBerry Investment Grows 12% in May as Long-Term Loan Supply Increases</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.597854+00:00</updated>
    <content>PeerBerry investors funded €31.43M in May, up 12% from April. €890,468 in interest was paid, bringing total interest to €43.76M. The €115.45M portfolio dipped slightly due to major long-term loan repayments. Long-term loans now dominate the platform, increasing availability—investors are advised to adjust AutoInvest settings. PeerBerry gained 1,846 new users, reaching 103,100. Since inception, nearly €3.05B in loans have been funded.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/peerberry"/>
    <published>2025-06-04T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Income Marketplace Reports €6.1M in New Funding for May 2025 - 2025-06-05T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Income Marketplace Reports €6.1M in New Funding for May 2025</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.597764+00:00</updated>
    <content>Income Marketplace saw €6.1M funded in May 2025, bringing total all-time funding to €168.8M. The average return since inception stands at 13.1%, with May’s new loans averaging 12.09% interest. 158 new investors joined, raising the total to 9,654. The outstanding portfolio reached €22.5M, with an average investor portfolio of €4,600. Total investor earnings to date: €4.74M.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/income"/>
    <published>2025-06-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Nectaro Adds Two-Factor Authentication for Extra Account Security - 2025-06-05T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Nectaro Adds Two-Factor Authentication for Extra Account Security</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.597674+00:00</updated>
    <content>Nectaro now supports Two-Factor Authentication (2FA), adding an extra layer of login protection. Users must enter both a password and a time-sensitive code from an authenticator app. This helps block unauthorized access, phishing, and fraud. Activate 2FA via your profile’s Security settings by scanning a QR code with Google Authenticator or similar apps.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/nectaro"/>
    <published>2025-06-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Nectaro Reports €987K Loss in 2024, Expands EU Reach and ESG Framework - 2025-06-05T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Nectaro Reports €987K Loss in 2024, Expands EU Reach and ESG Framework</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.597585+00:00</updated>
    <content>Nectaro closed 2024 with a €987K loss amid platform launch investments. Revenue reached €72.5K, up from €168 in 2023. Operating expenses totaled €1.06M. Assets rose to €422K, with share capital increased to €1.61M. The platform now spans 5 EU countries, manages a €3.7M loan portfolio, and is integrating ESG risk oversight. Parent Dyninno Fintech confirms continued capital support.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/nectaro"/>
    <published>2025-06-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>AvaFin Exits Esketit; Spanda Capital Launches €7M Loan Offering - 2025-06-05T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>AvaFin Exits Esketit; Spanda Capital Launches €7M Loan Offering</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.597492+00:00</updated>
    <content>AvaFin is exiting P2P funding, including Esketit, following its integration with Capitec Bank. Czech and Spanish loans will be repurchased, with no user impact. Meanwhile, Spanda Capital—backed by Esketit founders—will list €7M in new loans, their largest offering yet, after acquiring promising portfolios. The move strengthens Spanda’s role in NPL management with growing institutional interest.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/esketit"/>
    <published>2025-06-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Capitalia Reports Slower May Activity, Introduces Withdrawal Fee from July - 2025-06-07T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Capitalia Reports Slower May Activity, Introduces Withdrawal Fee from July</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.597381+00:00</updated>
    <content>In May, Capitalia saw a slight slowdown, with 96 borrower applications (€11.5M) vs. April’s 107 (€20.8M). The platform funded 15 projects worth €1.27M, down from 19 (€1.85M). Capitalia is expanding into Finland and strengthening its Baltic sales team. From July 1, a €3 fee applies for each withdrawal beyond two monthly free ones, addressing rising transaction and admin costs.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/capitalia"/>
    <published>2025-06-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>EstateGuru Opens EG Grow Waitlist With 7% Net Return, Monthly Payouts - 2025-06-07T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>EstateGuru Opens EG Grow Waitlist With 7% Net Return, Monthly Payouts</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.597269+00:00</updated>
    <content>EstateGuru has launched the waiting list for EG Grow, a hands-off investment product offering a fixed 7% net annual return, paid monthly. Backed by real estate, it features a contingency fund to support interest payouts, but not principal. The service requires a €100 minimum and a 14-day initial allocation period. Investments are locked in with no early exit.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/estateguru"/>
    <published>2025-06-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>TWINO Recovery Update: Russia Steady, Vietnam Uncertain, Philippines Pending - 2025-06-28T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>TWINO Recovery Update: Russia Steady, Vietnam Uncertain, Philippines Pending</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.597177+00:00</updated>
    <content>TWINO reports steady €100K monthly recoveries from Russia, totaling €3.8M (54% of affected portfolio). Vietnam recoveries remain unlikely amid halted operations. In the Philippines, no further repayments are expected, but a potential asset deal may ensure full recovery.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/twino"/>
    <published>2025-06-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Utopia Loans Repaid Early: Esketit Investors Recover Full Returns Despite Liquidation - 2025-07-03T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Utopia Loans Repaid Early: Esketit Investors Recover Full Returns Despite Liquidation</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.597085+00:00</updated>
    <content>All loans tied to Utopia Music AG (now Proper Group AG), funded via Esketit, have been fully repaid—over two years early. Despite Utopia’s liquidation in Nov 2024, repayments continued uninterrupted thanks to a robust SPV setup by Esketit and i2. Investors received full principal and interest with no losses, showcasing strong risk controls.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/esketit"/>
    <published>2025-07-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>PeerBerry Sees EUR 31.89M Loan Funding in June 2025 - 2025-07-05T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>PeerBerry Sees EUR 31.89M Loan Funding in June 2025</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.596991+00:00</updated>
    <content>In June, PeerBerry investors funded EUR 31.89 million in loans, slightly up from May. Interest paid to investors reached EUR 868,668 last month, with total interest since launch at EUR 44.63 million. The platform's portfolio grew to EUR 115.63 million. Over 1,500 new investors joined, bringing the user base to 104,700+. Since inception, investors funded over EUR 3.08 billion in loans.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/peerberry"/>
    <published>2025-07-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>InRento surpasses €50M funded with nearly 12% average annual returns, expands across Europe - 2025-07-08T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>InRento surpasses €50M funded with nearly 12% average annual returns, expands across Europe</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.596897+00:00</updated>
    <content>InRento has funded over €50 million since 2020, with a 12% average annual return. In the past year alone, investors financed €23 million, highlighting strong growth and trust. The platform now hosts 31,000+ investors across Europe and has backed 186 projects in five countries. Expansion in Poland and Italy supports greater diversification and long-term stability for investors.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/inrento"/>
    <published>2025-07-08T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>New 1-Year Business Loans Now Available from Jordan’s Money For Specialised Finance - 2025-07-08T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>New 1-Year Business Loans Now Available from Jordan’s Money For Specialised Finance</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.596802+00:00</updated>
    <content>Starting July 14, you can invest in 1-year business loans from Jordan’s Money For Specialised Finance at a 10% interest rate with monthly payments. This expands the existing short-term loans (1 month) available since 2021, offering longer investment options. These loans will also be included in Jordan and Diversified Automated strategies for broader portfolio allocation.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/esketit"/>
    <published>2025-07-08T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>RC RIGA Loan Agreements Transferred to RC BUCHAREST in 30 Days - 2025-07-12T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>RC RIGA Loan Agreements Transferred to RC BUCHAREST in 30 Days</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.596706+00:00</updated>
    <content>RC RIGA will transfer all rights and duties under existing loan and assignment agreements to affiliated entity RC BUCHAREST. The novation takes effect 30 days from notice. Investor agreements remain valid, with no changes to interest, repayment terms, or returns. No action is needed from investors; all transitions will occur automatically and without payment interruptions. This step supports UnaFinancial’s operational enhancement.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/robocash"/>
    <published>2025-07-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Aventus Group Reports €87.19M Profit in 2024, Up 62% YoY - 2025-07-12T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Aventus Group Reports €87.19M Profit in 2024, Up 62% YoY</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.596606+00:00</updated>
    <content>Aventus Group posted €87.19 million in net profits for 2024—a 62% increase from 2023. Loan issuance surged to €3.08 billion, with 12.07 million units issued. The loan portfolio reached €273.08 million (+30%), while equity doubled to €153.33 million. Interest income rose 57% to €349 million. Active in 16 countries, the group credits its growth to strong risk and resource management.</content>
    <link href="/en/review/peerberry"/>
    <published>2025-07-12T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>P2P Portfolio Update | May 2025 - 2025-07-14T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>P2P Portfolio Update | May 2025</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.596495+00:00</updated>
    <content>Learn more about the recent changes in our P2P lending portfolio.</content>
    <link href="https://p2pempire.com/en/portfolio"/>
    <published>2025-07-14T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>Una Financial's Audited Financial Report 2024 Flags Severe Risk for P2P Investors - 2025-07-16T00:00:00Z</id>
    <title>Una Financial's Audited Financial Report 2024 Flags Severe Risk for P2P Investors</title>
    <updated>2025-07-29T18:30:13.596278+00:00</updated>
    <content>Una Financial’s 2024 audited report reveals a 58% equity drop to $4.25M and a 7x increase in losses to $6.33M. Debt-to-equity surged to 25.1x, highlighting dangerous leverage. Asset shrinkage suggests reduced originations or sell-offs. Despite a modest profit, structural losses persist. Investors face high risk unless protections like loan segregation are in place. Sustainability hinges on urgent restructuring or new capital.</content>
    <link href="https://k8s-sng-aws-asia-unafinance-strapi-media-library.s3.ap-southeast-1.amazonaws.com/Una_Financial_Group_Summary_Special_Purpose_Consolidated_DEC_2024_AUP_Report_4e01ba61cc.pdf"/>
    <published>2025-07-16T00:00:00+00:00</published>
  </entry>
</feed>
